<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>encouragement on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/encouragement/</link>
        <description>Recent content in encouragement on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/encouragement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Already perfected</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/already-perfected/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/already-perfected/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/already-perfected/tanja-tepavac-cWMhxNmQVq0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Already perfected" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you not encouraged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No? Then what would encourage you? Do you even know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you would be encouraged then encourage another. So my question becomes, do you know how to encourage another?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is most important that you understand this if you are to be of any use in the Kingdom. For there are some who think they can encourage another by dropping platitudes from the stratosphere while they cruise by living their own comfortable and privileged lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course that is no help at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even before you begin to think about how, consider who⸺who to encourage. For it is not only the down-trodden who need encouragement. Listen to Moses telling of what the Lord spoke to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Even with me the LORD was angry on your account and said, ‘You also shall not go in there. Joshua the son of Nun, who stands before you, he shall enter. Encourage him, for he shall cause Israel to inherit it.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 1:37-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses was to encourage Joshua, who as we know was already a man of courage and conviction, albeit one who needed to be encouraged. For who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the who is easy. It is each and every one. Do not hold back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the how can be harder⸺how to encourage? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ, who died for us so that whether we are awake or asleep we might live with him. Therefore encourage one another and build one another up, just as you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encouragement is about building up another, affirming and validating. It is most certainly not about platitudes. Indeed the dictionary definition is &lt;em&gt;to give support, confidence, or hope to someone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s find some of that right here to use as encouragement for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Christ had offered for all time a single sacrifice for sins, he sat down at the right hand of God, waiting from that time until his enemies should be made a footstool for his feet. For by a single offering he has perfected for all time those who are being sanctified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider just that last verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For by a single offering he has perfected for all time those who are being sanctified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To perfect here means to complete, accomplish, consecrate, make perfect, to add what is yet wanting in order to render a thing full. And this has already been done for all time for those who are being sanctified, because Christ offered himself as the sacrifice for sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have to ask, are we among these being sanctified? For these are the ones who have been perfected, precisely the ones who are being sanctified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you being sanctified?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But be careful that you understand the question. It is not about whether you are without fault. For it is only Christ who perfects, and that has already happened. But being sanctified is the ongoing process of being made holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you being made holy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the very next verses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Holy Spirit also bears witness to us; for after saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is the covenant that I will make with them after those days, declares the Lord: I will put my laws on their hearts, and write them on their minds,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then he adds,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I will remember their sins and their lawless deeds no more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where there is forgiveness of these, there is no longer any offering for sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would be sanctified then God&amp;rsquo;s holy law must be on your heart. And you must understand what this means. It is not about being without fault, for we know that is utterly beyond us. No. It is about what you set your heart upon, what you desire above all. And that begins with intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we know that the law is spiritual, but I am of the flesh, sold under sin. For I do not understand my own actions. For I do not do what I want, but I do the very thing I hate. Now if I do what I do not want, I agree with the law, that it is good. So now it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me. For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out. For I do not do the good I want, but the evil I do not want is what I keep on doing. Now if I do what I do not want, it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:14-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, intent. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/love-and-holiness/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;We already considered&lt;/a&gt; that in this regard there can be no pretending.  I wrote previously that &lt;em&gt;if my deepest desire is to honour my Heavenly Father, he knows this, and my stumbles are easily forgiven as simply that.&lt;/em&gt; O my soul, is this your deepest desire? There can be no pretending!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For if you live according to the flesh you will die, but if by the Spirit you put to death the deeds of the body, you will live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make this your deepest desire then, and by the Spirit you will indeed put to death the deeds of the body and live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so because of this ongoing but as yet incomplete process of sanctification by the power of the Holy Spirit you have already been perfected. And be further encouraged, because the Day is drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, encourage one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What to think about</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/redd-f-LP3PabHuyiE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What to think about" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you thinking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking again about those insolent ones? And if so, why? Why would you continue to think about them? Thinking about them is not blessing you. Be assured that they are not thinking about you! Or are you dwelling on other things which drag you down? Why would you continue to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Like a dog that returns to his vomit is a fool who repeats his folly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 26:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what are you doing? Would you be building that dam on the river of life? Stop! Stop thinking about those things which drag you down. Stop dwelling on them. Stop living in them. Think instead about something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then? What must you think about? Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honourable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about these things and be lifted up and encouraged. So what are they, these things that we must think about? Rejoice that they are many and varied, and fill your mind with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw heaven opened, and behold, a white horse! The one sitting on it is called Faithful and True, and in righteousness he judges and makes war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Here is Jesus in all of his resurrection power and splendour, whose very name is Faithful and True. In righteousness he judges and makes war on all that is unholy. And he is victorious. Think about him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now, O Lord GOD, you are God, and your words are true, and you have promised this good thing to your servant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Samuel 7:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words of the Lord are true. What he has promised is true. His name is Faithful and True. Think about this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is just.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours in full. If we confess our sins and cry out to God for mercy it is his justice that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment precisely because he is just. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I the LORD love justice; I hate robbery and wrong; I will faithfully give them their recompense, and I will make an everlasting covenant with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1,8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that the Lord loves justice. In power and compassion Jesus came to do justice for the poor and the oppressed. Think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn to do good; seek justice, correct oppression; bring justice to the fatherless, plead the widow&amp;rsquo;s cause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about how to do justice⸺the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own justice which binds up the brokenhearted and proclaims liberty to the captives and the opening of the prison to those who are bound. Think about how to do this in his Spirit and by his power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about what is worthy of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I looked, and I heard around the throne and the living creatures and the elders the voice of many angels, numbering myriads of myriads and thousands of thousands, saying with a loud voice, “Worthy is the Lamb who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and might and honour and glory and blessing!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the sound of a hundred million angels singing praise to the risen Lord Jesus in his resurrection power and splendour. And hear his own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I turned to see the voice that was speaking to me, and on turning I saw seven golden lampstands, and in the midst of the lampstands one like a son of man, clothed with a long robe and with a golden sash around his chest. The hairs of his head were white, like white wool, like snow. His eyes were like a flame of fire, his feet were like burnished bronze, refined in a furnace, and his voice was like the roar of many waters. In his right hand he held seven stars, from his mouth came a sharp two-edged sword, and his face was like the sun shining in full strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw him, I fell at his feet as though dead. But he laid his right hand on me, saying, “Fear not, I am the first and the last, and the living one. I died, and behold I am alive forevermore, and I have the keys of Death and Hades.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:12-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear not, O my soul, and think about this. He is the first and the last and the living one, who died and rose again to life, and he is alive forevermore. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, why finally? Why does Paul say finally? We need to look at what came before. And what came before is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about those insolent ones or about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about these true, just, praiseworthy things, O my soul, and pray with thanksgiving, and know that the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your heart and your mind in Christ Jesus! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
