<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>integrity on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/integrity/</link>
        <description>Recent content in integrity on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/integrity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Love marks the spot</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/love-marks-the-spot/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/love-marks-the-spot/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/love-marks-the-spot/suhash-villuri-DYWHwLZyJ64-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Love marks the spot" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you find the way to that treasure in heaven yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ought to have done so because it&amp;rsquo;s not well hidden and you have a map. But if perhaps you are thinking that X marks the spot you would be wrong. For it is in fact love which marks the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And behold, a man came up to [Jesus], saying, “Teacher, what good deed must I do to have eternal life?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn a lesson from this likeable young man, for many make similar mistakes and he made several, and there&amp;rsquo;s one right here in the first thing he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“What good deed must I do to have eternal life?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One good deed? In the singular? Just one? Will that be enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [Jesus] said to him, “Why do you ask me about what is good? There is only one who is good. If you would enter life, keep the commandments.” He said to him, “Which ones?” And Jesus said, “You shall not murder, You shall not commit adultery, You shall not steal, You shall not bear false witness, Honour your father and mother, and, You shall love your neighbour as yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:17-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this interesting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus has quoted only six of the Ten Commandments. He skipped the first four. Why would he do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall the context in which the Lord introduced the Ten Commandments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God spoke all these words, saying, “I am the LORD your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of slavery.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 20:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commandments were given to the Israelites by their rescuer and redeemer who had every right to command obedience⸺the one who is also our own rescuer and redeemer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are the four commandments which Jesus skipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You shall have no other gods before me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not make for yourself a carved image, or any likeness of anything that is in heaven above, or that is in the earth beneath, or that is in the water under the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not take the name of the LORD your God in vain,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Remember the Sabbath day, to keep it holy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 20:3-4,7a,8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll come to Jesus&amp;rsquo; skipping⸺or as we&amp;rsquo;ll see, not skipping⸺over these headline commandments. But before we do that, let&amp;rsquo;s notice his rephrasing of the tenth commandment. Listen to the continuation as originally given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Honour your father and your mother, that your days may be long in the land that the LORD your God is giving you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not commit adultery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not bear false witness against your neighbour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not covet your neighbour&amp;rsquo;s house; you shall not covet your neighbour&amp;rsquo;s wife, or his male servant, or his female servant, or his ox, or his donkey, or anything that is your neighbour&amp;rsquo;s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 20:12-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Jesus said, “You shall not murder, You shall not commit adultery, You shall not steal, You shall not bear false witness, Honour your father and mother, and, You shall love your neighbour as yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:18b-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus restated the commandment not to covet as, “You shall love your neighbour as yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How interesting! Why would he do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was unwrapping the commandment to reveal the full extent of its reach, which is far more than its original hearers had understood, and far more than any of us have understood. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that his main point in the Sermon on the Mount?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice too the young man&amp;rsquo;s eagerness to claim obedience to these and how Jesus gently exposed his shortfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The young man said to him, “All these I have kept. What do I still lack?” Jesus said to him, “If you would be perfect, go, sell what you possess and give to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven; and come, follow me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The young man hadn&amp;rsquo;t remotely kept these commandments and as such was so much like us. So Jesus simply showed him the full extent of “love your neighbour as yourself” until the young man understood his shortfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the young man heard this he went away sorrowful, for he had great possessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only was his failure to love revealed but suddenly too were his idols exposed. For what was it that defined him? What was he living for? What had he built his life upon? Jesus showed him and he went away sorrowful. What a tragic figure he was, and how very much like us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For are we ourselves not overflowing in material wealth in our western affluence? Are we not rich like that tragic young man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Jesus said to his disciples, “Truly, I say to you, only with difficulty will a rich person enter the kingdom of heaven. Again I tell you, it is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich person to enter the kingdom of God.” When the disciples heard this, they were greatly astonished, saying, “Who then can be saved?” But Jesus looked at them and said, “With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:23-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clearly impossible for a camel to pass through the eye of a needle, notwithstanding the weasel words of reinterpretation imposed upon this verse by commentators throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hear Jesus&amp;rsquo; words, and cry out in gratitude and adoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:26b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what about Jesus&amp;rsquo; skipping over the first four commandments? Are these not in fact the more important, for it is these which concern our relationship with our Heavenly Father, which must surely come ahead of our relationships with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And one of the scribes came up and heard them disputing with one another, and seeing that he answered them well, asked him, “Which commandment is the most important of all?” Jesus answered, “The most important is, ‘Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. And you shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength.’ The second is this: ‘You shall love your neighbour as yourself.’ There is no other commandment greater than these.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 12:28-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So notice how Jesus returns to exactly this in our passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Peter said in reply, “See, we have left everything and followed you. What then will we have?” Jesus said to them, “Truly, I say to you, in the new world, when the Son of Man will sit on his glorious throne, you who have followed me will also sit on twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel. And everyone who has left houses or brothers or sisters or father or mother or children or lands, for my name&amp;rsquo;s sake, will receive a hundredfold and will inherit eternal life. But many who are first will be last, and the last first.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:27-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this not in fact precisely the commandment? Have no other gods before the Lord, and worship no idols. Put the Lord ahead of houses and brothers and sisters and father and mother and children and lands. And is Jesus not doing for us precisely what he did for that young man when he showed him how completely and comprehensively he had failed to understand “love your neighbour as yourself”, but now in the context of “love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these verses are addressed also to us. Have we actually understood “You shall have no other gods before me”? How the idols creep in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what is it that you have you placed ahead of the Lord? Gently and firmly and unequivocally Jesus says repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what a return on that investment you can expect! A hundredfold! So do not hold back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, love the Lord with all of your being, and your neighbour as yourself, and you shall have treasure in heaven, a hundredfold of what you surrender for the Kingdom! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to be rich</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/how-to-be-rich/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/how-to-be-rich/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/how-to-be-rich/dan-dennis-pZ56pVKd_6c-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to be rich" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like to be rich? Really rich? It is desperately important to be so, because otherwise you will have nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [Jesus] said to them, “Take care, and be on your guard against all covetousness, for one&amp;rsquo;s life does not consist in the abundance of his possessions.” And he told them a parable, saying, “The land of a rich man produced plentifully, and he thought to himself, ‘What shall I do, for I have nowhere to store my crops?’ And he said, ‘I will do this: I will tear down my barns and build larger ones, and there I will store all my grain and my goods. And I will say to my soul, “Soul, you have ample goods laid up for many years; relax, eat, drink, be merry.’” But God said to him, ‘Fool! This night your soul is required of you, and the things you have prepared, whose will they be?’ So is the one who lays up treasure for himself and is not rich toward God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 12:15-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this is about being rich towards God. What did you think I was asking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encountered this parable last week in the context of being looked after by our Heavenly Father but we didn&amp;rsquo;t adequately consider being rich towards God, so let&amp;rsquo;s do that now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let&amp;rsquo;s begin with Jesus&amp;rsquo; own commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said to them, “Take care, and be on your guard against all covetousness.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 12:15a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To covet means to long to possess, and not only what belongs to others. Coveting one&amp;rsquo;s own possessions is a perennial snare to the one who would be rich towards God, for such coveting creates treasures on earth in blatant disregard of Jesus&amp;rsquo; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Do not lay up for yourselves treasures on earth, where moth and rust destroy and where thieves break in and steal, but lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven, where neither moth nor rust destroys and where thieves do not break in and steal. For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:19-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How tragic to convert a potential asset for the Kingdom into the casualty of moth and rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what else did Jesus say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Sell your possessions, and give to the needy. Provide yourselves with moneybags that do not grow old, with a treasure in the heavens that does not fail, where no thief approaches and no moth destroys. For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 12:33-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is again. Your possessions are assets for the Kingdom, and they wholly belong to the King. So use them for Kingdom work and you will be rich with treasure in heaven which is immune to both moth and rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us who live in modern Western affluence must be particularly vigilant. For ours is a culture of rugged individualism and indifference towards those in need. O my soul, beware lest you make your benchmark that of the world around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Jesus&amp;rsquo; warning continues into the parable of the master returning from the wedding feast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Stay dressed for action and keep your lamps burning, and be like men who are waiting for their master to come home from the wedding feast, so that they may open the door to him at once when he comes and knocks.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 12:35-36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is surely about living lives consistent with what we have received, and at all times. We won&amp;rsquo;t get into this now, except to notice a portent for any who would excuse their own lack of concern for others by using the benchmark of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And that servant who knew his master&amp;rsquo;s will but did not get ready or act according to his will, will receive a severe beating. But the one who did not know, and did what deserved a beating, will receive a light beating. Everyone to whom much was given, of him much will be required, and from him to whom they entrusted much, they will demand the more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 12:47-48&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus expects far more of those within the church than those without. Of course he does! We who have so richly received and who know his will, how then could we hold back in blessing others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What good is it, my brothers, if someone says he has faith but does not have works? Can that faith save him? If a brother or sister is poorly clothed and lacking in daily food, and one of you says to them, “Go in peace, be warmed and filled,” without giving them the things needed for the body, what good is that? So also faith by itself, if it does not have works, is dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 2:14-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dead, no less!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And know that loving one another has a high cost. Will you bear it? It helps to remember the cost which was borne for you at Calvary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By this we know love, that he laid down his life for us, and we ought to lay down our lives for the brothers. But if anyone has the world&amp;rsquo;s goods and sees his brother in need, yet closes his heart against him, how does God&amp;rsquo;s love abide in him? Little children, let us not love in word or talk but in deed and in truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this we shall know that we are of the truth and reassure our heart before him; for whenever our heart condemns us, God is greater than our heart, and he knows everything. Beloved, if our heart does not condemn us, we have confidence before God; and whatever we ask we receive from him, because we keep his commandments and do what pleases him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 3:16-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do what pleases God in loving one another and in every other way and you will be rich beyond imagining! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The perils of worldliness</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-perils-of-worldliness/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-perils-of-worldliness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-perils-of-worldliness/engin-akyurt-pFv815lYZwc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The perils of worldliness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you accepted worldliness into your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the answer is yes. For now though let&amp;rsquo;s leave to one side how or what to do and let&amp;rsquo;s simply consider the great cost that you have suffered and will continue to suffer because of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider King Asa of Judah about whom we read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abijah slept with his fathers, and they buried him in the city of David. And Asa his son reigned in his place. In his days the land had rest for ten years. And Asa did what was good and right in the eyes of the LORD his God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart of Asa was wholly true all his days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 14:1-2, 15:17b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t we be inclined to rank Asa among the upright and true kings, one of so very few men of integrity along with Hezekiah and Josiah and David himself? Of course we would and he is even commended for it. So why is he my example of worldliness? Exactly for this reason in fact, that he was otherwise upright and true. And may his life serve as a solemn warning to any who might consider themselves also to be upright and true, living a life of integrity and honouring the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what do we find in his later years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the thirty-sixth year of the reign of Asa, Baasha king of Israel went up against Judah and built Ramah, that he might permit no one to go out or come in to Asa king of Judah.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baasha king of Israel was undeniably evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the third year of Asa king of Judah, Baasha the son of Ahijah began to reign over all Israel at Tirzah, and he reigned twenty-four years. He did what was evil in the sight of the LORD and walked in the way of Jeroboam and in his sin which he made Israel to sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 15:33-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only was Baasha evil but he had a reputation for destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And as soon as he was king, he killed all the house of Jeroboam. He left to the house of Jeroboam not one that breathed, until he had destroyed it, according to the word of the LORD that he spoke by his servant Ahijah the Shilonite. It was for the sins of Jeroboam that he sinned and that he made Israel to sin, and because of the anger to which he provoked the LORD, the God of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 15:29-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what was good king Asa to do? Was he to suffer the same fate as the house of Jeroboam? Not if he could help it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Asa took silver and gold from the treasures of the house of the LORD and the king&amp;rsquo;s house and sent them to Ben-hadad king of Syria, who lived in Damascus, saying, “There is a covenant between me and you, as there was between my father and your father. Behold, I am sending to you silver and gold. Go, break your covenant with Baasha king of Israel, that he may withdraw from me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the same king who had faced an Ethiopian army twice the size of his own, who had cried out to God and been miraculously delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Zerah the Ethiopian came out against them with an army of a million men and 300 chariots, and came as far as Mareshah. And Asa went out to meet him, and they drew up their lines of battle in the Valley of Zephathah at Mareshah. And Asa cried to the LORD his God, “O LORD, there is none like you to help, between the mighty and the weak. Help us, O LORD our God, for we rely on you, and in your name we have come against this multitude. O LORD, you are our God; let not man prevail against you.” So the LORD defeated the Ethiopians before Asa and before Judah, and the Ethiopians fled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 14:9-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asa had cried out to the Lord who had defeated the Ethiopians before him. And yet now we find him raiding the treasures of the temple of the Lord to use as a bribe for Ben-hadad king of Syria, to deliver him from the hand of Baasha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could this be? How could this good and upright king whose heart was wholly true all his days behave in such a faithless and godless way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that I scoured three chapters of the Chronicles for evidence of an explanation, and found only this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And [Asa] gathered all Judah and Benjamin, and those from Ephraim, Manasseh, and Simeon who were residing with them, for great numbers had deserted to him from Israel when they saw that the LORD his God was with him. They were gathered at Jerusalem in the third month of the fifteenth year of the reign of Asa. They sacrificed to the LORD on that day from the spoil that they had brought 700 oxen and 7,000 sheep. And they entered into a covenant to seek the LORD, the God of their fathers, with all their heart and with all their soul, but that whoever would not seek the LORD, the God of Israel, should be put to death, whether young or old, man or woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the high places were not taken out of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 15:9-13, 17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must understand the significance of these high places which were not taken out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Judah did what was evil in the sight of the LORD, and they provoked him to jealousy with their sins that they committed, more than all that their fathers had done. For they also built for themselves high places and pillars and Asherim on every high hill and under every green tree, and there were also male cult prostitutes in the land. They did according to all the abominations of the nations that the LORD drove out before the people of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 14:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These high places were an abomination from the time before the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people were given the land of Canaan. They were the epitome of worldliness, and yet they were tolerated, remaining in the land, tainting and corrupting the Children of the Promise, and if I am right, becoming the downfall of Asa, that otherwise good, right, and true king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what a tragic end he consequently suffered, this king whose heart was nevertheless wholly true all his days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At that time Hanani the seer came to Asa king of Judah and said to him, “Because you relied on the king of Syria, and did not rely on the LORD your God, the army of the king of Syria has escaped you. Were not the Ethiopians and the Libyans a huge army with very many chariots and horsemen? Yet because you relied on the LORD, he gave them into your hand. For the eyes of the LORD run to and fro throughout the whole earth, to give strong support to those whose heart is whole toward him. You have done foolishly in this, for from now on you will have wars.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:7-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore Asa did not respond well to this rebuke from the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Asa was angry with the seer and put him in the stocks in prison, for he was in a rage with him because of this. And Asa inflicted cruelties upon some of the people at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acts of Asa, from first to last, are written in the Book of the Kings of Judah and Israel. In the thirty-ninth year of his reign Asa was diseased in his feet, and his disease became severe. Yet even in his disease he did not seek the LORD, but sought help from physicians. And Asa slept with his fathers, dying in the forty-first year of his reign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:10-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a tragic end to an otherwise right and true life. And what a solemn and sober warning to those who might be following Asa into worldliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asa had been warned so clearly, but perhaps in his complacency he had failed to take the warning seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Spirit of God came upon Azariah the son of Oded, and he went out to meet Asa and said to him, “Hear me, Asa, and all Judah and Benjamin: The LORD is with you while you are with him. If you seek him, he will be found by you, but if you forsake him, he will forsake you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 15:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord looks throughout the whole earth for those whose hearts are wholly for him, and he gives them strong support. Rejoice that he does so and be that wholehearted one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be vigilant and purge the worldliness from your own life, for the Lord knows whose hearts are wholly for him, and he gives them strong support! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The open door</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/chris-meads-VDHn0YmjIw4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The open door" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does an open door constitute a reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia write: ‘The words of the holy one, the true one, who has the key of David, who opens and no one will shut, who shuts and no one opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works. Behold, I have set before you an open door, which no one is able to shut.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:7-8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the seven churches only Smyrna was able to join with Philadelphia in being commended by Jesus without reservation. Jesus knew their works. What a joy it must have been for him to commend their faithfulness and to richly reward them. So let&amp;rsquo;s consider the reward of that open door. And let&amp;rsquo;s start by asking, how does that even constitute a reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t an open door simply an opportunity presenting itself? Indeed Paul uses exactly this metaphor on several occasions. Here are two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I will stay in Ephesus until Pentecost, for a wide door for effective work has opened to me, and there are many adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 16:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving. At the same time, pray also for us, that God may open to us a door for the word, to declare the mystery of Christ, on account of which I am in prison⸺that I may make it clear, which is how I ought to speak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 4:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly the opportunity here was not presenting itself but rather was being presented as a sovereign work of the Lord. Paul was most concerned about the open door for declaring the mystery of Christ, that he may make it clear⸺of course he was. But I am not persuaded that this was the nature of the reward for the Philadelphians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Jesus&amp;rsquo; next letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is not knocking on the Philadelphian door because it is already open and he is right there among them. This is the door to heaven itself, just as John&amp;rsquo;s vision continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After this I looked, and behold, a door standing open in heaven! And the first voice, which I had heard speaking to me like a trumpet, said, “Come up here, and I will show you what must take place after this.” At once I was in the Spirit, and behold, a throne stood in heaven, with one seated on the throne. And he who sat there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian, and around the throne was a rainbow that had the appearance of an emerald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a door this is! And it is wide open and cannot be shut. What a reward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In passing we must enjoy to notice John&amp;rsquo;s ludicrous attempt to describe the indescribable, the one seated on the throne. He who was seated there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian. Really? Is that the best he could have done? It tells us nothing. Except of course of the ineffability of the Creator God of the Universe, reigning and ruling in majesty and splendour. Praise his holy name! And praise his indescribable being!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we continue to think about that door, let&amp;rsquo;s consider what was being rewarded, for it seems to be so very little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that you have but little power, and yet you have kept my word and have not denied my name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you have kept my word about patient endurance &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:8b, 10a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s the entirety of it! But make no mistake, this is not so very little at all. We need to understand what this means, to keep Jesus&amp;rsquo; word and not to deny his name. It is in fact about absolute trust and complete surrender and living an uncompromised life which is fully consistent and perfectly aligned with Jesus being Lord of all. And it is about that personal holiness which is an ongoing act of worship to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; name is his character. It is who he is. So what would deny his name? Would it not be anxiety or doubt or inconsistency or pretence or pride or holding anything back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you understand the magnitude of what was being commended? Marvel at it, and now go and do likewise! And if you think you simply lack the strength to live like this, observe that the Philadelphians also had but little power. The power to live like this is all the Lord&amp;rsquo;s and it is his gift of grace. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But back to this open door. Jesus tells us a bit more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So Jesus again said to them, “Truly, truly, I say to you, I am the door of the sheep. All who came before me are thieves and robbers, but the sheep did not listen to them. I am the door. If anyone enters by me, he will be saved and will go in and out and find pasture. The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the door, and he is the door to life itself. Jesus came that we may have life and have it abundantly. O my soul, are you starting to understand the magnitude of the Philadelphian reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is something else which must not be overlooked. What does Jesus say of those who have not lived this pure and holy and surrendered life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and they will learn that I have loved you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:9b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, have you learnt this? Have you learnt that the King of the Universe has loved you with an everlasting love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, do not overlook that the abundant life is this life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 3:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, live like those Philadelphians, and receive from Jesus the reward of that open door! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Small victories?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/robert-collins-tvc5imO5pXk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Small victories?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that the smallest things are in fact the most important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s notice something in Jesus&amp;rsquo; letter to the church in Pergamum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“And to the angel of the church in Pergamum write: ‘The words of him who has the sharp two-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘I know where you dwell, where Satan&amp;rsquo;s throne is. Yet you hold fast my name, and you did not deny my faith even in the days of Antipas my faithful witness, who was killed among you, where Satan dwells.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Pergamum was dominated by worship of pagan deities and so the church there was right in the thick of the spiritual battle. But doesn&amp;rsquo;t Jesus&amp;rsquo; commendation seem to be of such a small thing? Simply holding fast his name? Is that all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not underestimate what such apparently small things are ultimately all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of forgiving a brother in Christ who has caused much pain, Paul writes this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this is why I wrote, that I might test you and know whether you are obedient in everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 2:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you obedient in everything? Even in apparently small things? Let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one such. Recall something Jesus said in the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You have heard that it was said, ‘You shall not commit adultery.’ But I say to you that everyone who looks at a woman with lustful intent has already committed adultery with her in his heart.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:27-28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this not an area which requires honest self-evaluation and ruthless self-discipline? And isn&amp;rsquo;t this precisely one of these apparently small things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider. As you drive through the student quarter on a balmy summer afternoon, are you noticing the oh-so-attractive and rather scantily clad students parading themselves? And what do your eyes do then? And where do your thoughts take you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what your eyes are doing, because no-one sees? And where your thoughts are taking you, because no-one knows? It matters! Our Heavenly Father sees and our Heavenly Father knows. The choice between looking to the left or looking to the right is in fact the choice between disobedience and disrespect, or personal holiness and an act of worship. An act of worship to the one who loves you. The one who rescued you. The one who grieves over the vestigial sin in your life. O my soul, choose to honour him in this! Make every small victory over sin an act of worship, and keep your eyes to the right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the contexts of giving and praying and fasting, Jesus follows up with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:4, 6, 18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David knew this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you, Solomon my son, know the God of your father and serve him with a whole heart and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches all hearts and understands every plan and thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every plan. Every thought. And the intent behind each and every thought. Every motive which wanted to remain hidden is in fact fully exposed to the Lord who searches all hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that if you present yourselves to anyone as obedient slaves, you are slaves of the one whom you obey, either of sin, which leads to death, or of obedience, which leads to righteousness?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding fast Jesus&amp;rsquo; name is in truth all about consistency and integrity in the secret heart. Do you realise your character is the product of a thousand seemingly insignificant choices? You simply cannot do one thing and become another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God. Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth. For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God. When Christ who is your life appears, then you also will appear with him in glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whatever you do, in word or deed, do everything in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:1-4, 17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must also take heed of Jesus&amp;rsquo; sharp two-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart. And no creature is hidden from his sight, but all are naked and exposed to the eyes of him to whom we must give account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 4:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, notice that Antipas chose martyrdom rather than deny Jesus. And his reward? To bear the same description as of Jesus himself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Grace to you and peace from him who is and who was and who is to come, and from the seven spirits who are before his throne, and from Jesus Christ the faithful witness, the firstborn of the dead, and the ruler of kings on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the faithful witness and he bestowed upon Antipas the very same title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be ruthlessly consistent in how you approach all these apparently small things, and be Jesus&amp;rsquo; faithful witness in everything! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
