<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>patience on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/patience/</link>
        <description>Recent content in patience on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/patience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A wondrous reason</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/a-wondrous-reason/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/a-wondrous-reason/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/a-wondrous-reason/federico-burgalassi-K7M-TG05LTo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A wondrous reason" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you think by now things would have changed? That the God of all power and knowledge of every last detail about you and your situation, and being deeply invested in both, would have acted? And has he still not? Even after all this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We considered this quite recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the silence and in the inaction you must continue to trust in him. You must! And even as you wait on him, believing and not doubting, know that he is doing a mighty work of transformation in you, building love and holiness and faith⸺so much faith!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, the longing does not go away, does it?⸺longing for deliverance, for mercy, and for judgment on that which dishonours the Lord. Because there is plenty that dishonours his Holy Name, and it is close at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s now discover another reason for the waiting, for the delay, for the apparent inaction. And may our discovery be faith-building, as we marvel once again at the goodness and mercy of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you long for God to act with mighty power to deal with all that you face and all that is faced by this broken world, do be careful what you wish for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think that the Lord doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel similarly about today&amp;rsquo;s world and today&amp;rsquo;s evil?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what he had done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then God said, “Let us make man in our image, after our likeness. And let them have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the heavens and over the livestock and over all the earth and over every creeping thing that creeps on the earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So God created man in his own image, in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humankind had been created in God&amp;rsquo;s own image with such capacity for love, for goodness, for kindness, and for holiness. But in his infinite wisdom and out of love God had not created automata, programmed simply to follow the Maker&amp;rsquo;s desired path. For love is defined by the ability to choose to love, goodness and kindness by the ability to choose them, and holiness too. And with that ability to choose comes the ability to choose not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a risk God had taken in creating such beings. And now he regretted that he had made humankind on the earth and it grieved him to his heart. Tremble at his intent to deal with the wickedness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet at the same time be grateful that there was one who stayed his hand, that there was a but.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Noah found favour in the eyes of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the generations of Noah. Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation. Noah walked with God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One righteous man was the reason that God did not blot out humankind from the face of the earth. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it almost unfathomable that a single human life lived with holiness and in honour of the Lord could have had such a profound impact upon the whole human race? O my soul, do not underestimate the value of living a God-honouring life of personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why are we even here considering Noah in the context of our opening question? Simply because of what the Apostle Peter wrote, and what he wrote is profound. He wrote first and foremost about facing trials and suffering and evil in the world, and he was clearly familiar with waiting and hoping and longing for deliverance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, all of you, have unity of mind, sympathy, brotherly love, a tender heart, and a humble mind. Do not repay evil for evil or reviling for reviling, but on the contrary, bless, for to this you were called, that you may obtain a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 3:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He continues by quoting Psalm 34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whoever desires to love life and see good days, let him keep his tongue from evil and his lips from speaking deceit; let him turn away from evil and do good; let him seek peace and pursue it. For the eyes of the Lord are on the righteous, and his ears are open to their prayer. But the face of the Lord is against those who do evil.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 3:10-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your place of hoping and longing and waiting, immerse yourself in Psalm 34, and know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s ears are open to your prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will bless the LORD at all times; his praise shall continually be in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I sought the LORD, and he answered me and delivered me from all my fears.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant, and their faces shall never be ashamed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is near to the brokenhearted and saves the crushed in spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD redeems the life of his servants; none of those who take refuge in him will be condemned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we must move on to Peter&amp;rsquo;s point about Noah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Christ also suffered once for sins, the righteous for the unrighteous, that he might bring us to God, being put to death in the flesh but made alive in the spirit, in which he went and proclaimed to the spirits in prison, because they formerly did not obey, when God&amp;rsquo;s patience waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was being prepared, in which a few, that is, eight persons, were brought safely through water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 3:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? God&amp;rsquo;s patience waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was being prepared. It is not inaction at all that we see from the Lord, but rather patience. And why is he patient?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Peter 3:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there we have it. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s strong desire is that none should perish but that all should reach repentance. And so he holds back, as he himself is waiting, is longing, is hoping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be patient yourself, trust the Lord, and keep waiting and longing and hoping! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The trust test</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/guzman-barquin-Qd688l1yDOI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The trust test" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is it to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I say trust, I mean completely depend upon him, fully committed, with no way out and no room for doubt. No wavering. No second guessing. None at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said &amp;hellip; “Do not fear, only believe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 5:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such trust is life and health and strength. Why would anyone not live like this? And yet many do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall with me the sorry saga of the Israelites failing to trust the Lord, their ongoing enslavement to fear and uncertainty and doubt. And recall too the Lord&amp;rsquo;s uncompromising response, his righteous anger burning against them, his chosen people, his beloved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What reason did the Israelites have to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the sight of their fathers he performed wonders in the land of Egypt, in the fields of Zoan. He divided the sea and let them pass through it, and made the waters stand like a heap. In the daytime he led them with a cloud, and all the night with a fiery light. He split rocks in the wilderness and gave them drink abundantly as from the deep. He made streams come out of the rock and caused waters to flow down like rivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:12-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the God who miraculously delivered his people from slavery in Egypt, parting the waters of the Red Sea so they could pass safely. And led them through the desert, miraculously guiding them and remaining with them. And slaked their thirst in the desert, again, miraculously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he fed them with manna from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Moses, “Behold, I am about to rain bread from heaven for you, and the people shall go out and gather a day&amp;rsquo;s portion every day, that I may test them, whether they will walk in my law or not.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 16:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was the test. This is the trust test. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that the Israelites faced time and again. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that we ourselves face time and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how did they do, those Israelites, those chosen people, those beloved ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They forgot his works and the wonders that he had shown them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They forgot all the reasons they had to trust him! Their earlier fear of the Lord and belief in him was so feeble it had simply evaporated like the morning mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet they sinned still more against him, rebelling against the Most High in the desert. They tested God in their heart by demanding the food they craved. They spoke against God, saying, “Can God spread a table in the wilderness? He struck the rock so that water gushed out and streams overflowed. Can he also give bread or provide meat for his people?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:17-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the sneering doubt here, the sheer contempt for their provider, the complete absence of trust? O my soul, be appalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, when the LORD heard, he was full of wrath; a fire was kindled against Jacob; his anger rose against Israel, because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not want you to be unaware, brothers, that our fathers were all under the cloud, and all passed through the sea, and all were baptized into Moses in the cloud and in the sea, and all ate the same spiritual food, and all drank the same spiritual drink. For they drank from the spiritual Rock that followed them, and the Rock was Christ. Nevertheless, with most of them God was not pleased, for they were overthrown in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They drank from the Rock which was Christ no less and yet they failed the trust test. Overthrown means struck down. In judgment for their lack of trust most of them were struck down by the Lord, their hitherto protector and provider, the Faithful One. Most of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The anger of God rose against them, and he killed the strongest of them and laid low the young men of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how important it is to trust, to believe, to depend upon the Lord without wavering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of our own trust test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even when things are very dark indeed you must trust the Lord and depend upon him relentlessly. He is faithful and true. Never doubt that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who among you fears the LORD and obeys the voice of his servant? Let him who walks in darkness and has no light trust in the name of the LORD and rely on his God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 50:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is tested when our lives are at stake, when our hearts are breaking, when things are entirely beyond us and all we can do is depend upon the Lord, upon his faithfulness to all that he has promised and to all that he is, when the way ahead is unseeable. But without the unseeable there can be no faith! O my soul, will you trust him then? Will you trust him now? Will you continue to trust him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now hope that is seen is not hope. For who hopes for what he sees? But if we hope for what we do not see, we wait for it with patience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in this waiting time of unseeing are you tempted to doubt? Are you tempted to despair? Are you tempted to run ahead of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will in your own strength? Resist! You must resist! Hold on to what is true. Hold on to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No temptation has overtaken you that is not common to man. God is faithful, and he will not let you be tempted beyond your ability, but with the temptation he will also provide the way of escape, that you may be able to endure it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can endure this, O my soul. Repudiate doubt and all that drags you down, and trust him. Trust him! You must endure with steadfast faith, believing and not doubting. Trust Jesus, whose name is Faithful and True!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The penalty for failing the truth test is severe, as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen. For standing firm, however, there are two stupendous prizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in him, O my soul, and he will act!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD’s delight is in those who fear him, those who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing this, by walking this path of trust and dependence and unwavering hope in him, waiting with patience, you can delight our Heavenly Father. You can delight him! What more motivation could you have to choose to trust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 15:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, put all your hope in his unfailing love and trust in the faithfulness of your Heavenly Father, and so delight him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
