<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>wisdom on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/wisdom/</link>
        <description>Recent content in wisdom on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/wisdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What to think about</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/redd-f-LP3PabHuyiE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What to think about" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you thinking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking again about those insolent ones? And if so, why? Why would you continue to think about them? Thinking about them is not blessing you. Be assured that they are not thinking about you! Or are you dwelling on other things which drag you down? Why would you continue to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Like a dog that returns to his vomit is a fool who repeats his folly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 26:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what are you doing? Would you be building that dam on the river of life? Stop! Stop thinking about those things which drag you down. Stop dwelling on them. Stop living in them. Think instead about something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then? What must you think about? Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honourable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about these things and be lifted up and encouraged. So what are they, these things that we must think about? Rejoice that they are many and varied, and fill your mind with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw heaven opened, and behold, a white horse! The one sitting on it is called Faithful and True, and in righteousness he judges and makes war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Here is Jesus in all of his resurrection power and splendour, whose very name is Faithful and True. In righteousness he judges and makes war on all that is unholy. And he is victorious. Think about him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now, O Lord GOD, you are God, and your words are true, and you have promised this good thing to your servant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Samuel 7:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words of the Lord are true. What he has promised is true. His name is Faithful and True. Think about this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is just.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours in full. If we confess our sins and cry out to God for mercy it is his justice that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment precisely because he is just. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I the LORD love justice; I hate robbery and wrong; I will faithfully give them their recompense, and I will make an everlasting covenant with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1,8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that the Lord loves justice. In power and compassion Jesus came to do justice for the poor and the oppressed. Think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn to do good; seek justice, correct oppression; bring justice to the fatherless, plead the widow&amp;rsquo;s cause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about how to do justice⸺the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own justice which binds up the brokenhearted and proclaims liberty to the captives and the opening of the prison to those who are bound. Think about how to do this in his Spirit and by his power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about what is worthy of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I looked, and I heard around the throne and the living creatures and the elders the voice of many angels, numbering myriads of myriads and thousands of thousands, saying with a loud voice, “Worthy is the Lamb who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and might and honour and glory and blessing!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the sound of a hundred million angels singing praise to the risen Lord Jesus in his resurrection power and splendour. And hear his own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I turned to see the voice that was speaking to me, and on turning I saw seven golden lampstands, and in the midst of the lampstands one like a son of man, clothed with a long robe and with a golden sash around his chest. The hairs of his head were white, like white wool, like snow. His eyes were like a flame of fire, his feet were like burnished bronze, refined in a furnace, and his voice was like the roar of many waters. In his right hand he held seven stars, from his mouth came a sharp two-edged sword, and his face was like the sun shining in full strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw him, I fell at his feet as though dead. But he laid his right hand on me, saying, “Fear not, I am the first and the last, and the living one. I died, and behold I am alive forevermore, and I have the keys of Death and Hades.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:12-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear not, O my soul, and think about this. He is the first and the last and the living one, who died and rose again to life, and he is alive forevermore. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, why finally? Why does Paul say finally? We need to look at what came before. And what came before is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about those insolent ones or about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about these true, just, praiseworthy things, O my soul, and pray with thanksgiving, and know that the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your heart and your mind in Christ Jesus! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
