<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>sanctification on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/sanctification/</link>
        <description>Recent content in sanctification on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/sanctification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Already perfected</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/already-perfected/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/already-perfected/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/already-perfected/tanja-tepavac-cWMhxNmQVq0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Already perfected" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you not encouraged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No? Then what would encourage you? Do you even know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you would be encouraged then encourage another. So my question becomes, do you know how to encourage another?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is most important that you understand this if you are to be of any use in the Kingdom. For there are some who think they can encourage another by dropping platitudes from the stratosphere while they cruise by living their own comfortable and privileged lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course that is no help at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even before you begin to think about how, consider who⸺who to encourage. For it is not only the down-trodden who need encouragement. Listen to Moses telling of what the Lord spoke to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Even with me the LORD was angry on your account and said, ‘You also shall not go in there. Joshua the son of Nun, who stands before you, he shall enter. Encourage him, for he shall cause Israel to inherit it.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 1:37-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses was to encourage Joshua, who as we know was already a man of courage and conviction, albeit one who needed to be encouraged. For who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the who is easy. It is each and every one. Do not hold back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the how can be harder⸺how to encourage? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ, who died for us so that whether we are awake or asleep we might live with him. Therefore encourage one another and build one another up, just as you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encouragement is about building up another, affirming and validating. It is most certainly not about platitudes. Indeed the dictionary definition is &lt;em&gt;to give support, confidence, or hope to someone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s find some of that right here to use as encouragement for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Christ had offered for all time a single sacrifice for sins, he sat down at the right hand of God, waiting from that time until his enemies should be made a footstool for his feet. For by a single offering he has perfected for all time those who are being sanctified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider just that last verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For by a single offering he has perfected for all time those who are being sanctified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To perfect here means to complete, accomplish, consecrate, make perfect, to add what is yet wanting in order to render a thing full. And this has already been done for all time for those who are being sanctified, because Christ offered himself as the sacrifice for sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have to ask, are we among these being sanctified? For these are the ones who have been perfected, precisely the ones who are being sanctified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you being sanctified?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But be careful that you understand the question. It is not about whether you are without fault. For it is only Christ who perfects, and that has already happened. But being sanctified is the ongoing process of being made holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you being made holy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the very next verses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Holy Spirit also bears witness to us; for after saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is the covenant that I will make with them after those days, declares the Lord: I will put my laws on their hearts, and write them on their minds,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then he adds,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I will remember their sins and their lawless deeds no more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where there is forgiveness of these, there is no longer any offering for sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would be sanctified then God&amp;rsquo;s holy law must be on your heart. And you must understand what this means. It is not about being without fault, for we know that is utterly beyond us. No. It is about what you set your heart upon, what you desire above all. And that begins with intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we know that the law is spiritual, but I am of the flesh, sold under sin. For I do not understand my own actions. For I do not do what I want, but I do the very thing I hate. Now if I do what I do not want, I agree with the law, that it is good. So now it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me. For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out. For I do not do the good I want, but the evil I do not want is what I keep on doing. Now if I do what I do not want, it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:14-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, intent. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/love-and-holiness/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;We already considered&lt;/a&gt; that in this regard there can be no pretending.  I wrote previously that &lt;em&gt;if my deepest desire is to honour my Heavenly Father, he knows this, and my stumbles are easily forgiven as simply that.&lt;/em&gt; O my soul, is this your deepest desire? There can be no pretending!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For if you live according to the flesh you will die, but if by the Spirit you put to death the deeds of the body, you will live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make this your deepest desire then, and by the Spirit you will indeed put to death the deeds of the body and live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so because of this ongoing but as yet incomplete process of sanctification by the power of the Holy Spirit you have already been perfected. And be further encouraged, because the Day is drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, encourage one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Humbled by stumbling</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/humbled-by-stumbling/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/humbled-by-stumbling/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/humbled-by-stumbling/k-mitch-hodge-IqSaG9zv2e0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Humbled by stumbling" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are you going with your &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/approaching-holiness/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;holiness&lt;/a&gt; and repudiation of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/the-perils-of-worldliness/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;worldliness&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you embarrassed, ashamed even, of how feeble is your ability to live a right life which honours the Lord? Are you occasionally skewered by thoughts which take you to places you know you should not go, and in fact later you bitterly regret visiting? Do you find yourself stumbling? Again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not understand my own actions. For I do not do what I want, but I do the very thing I hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was written by the Apostle Paul, the very same man who had encountered Jesus personally and dramatically on the Damascus Road. The same man who had been taken up into the third heaven, into paradise, to hear things which man may not utter, however we grapple to understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I know a man in Christ who fourteen years ago was caught up to the third heaven⸺whether in the body or out of the body I do not know, God knows. And I know that this man was caught up into paradise⸺whether in the body or out of the body I do not know, God knows⸺and he heard things that cannot be told, which man may not utter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 12:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul knows this man in Christ for it is himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet after these amazing encounters and being filled with the Holy Spirit now we find Paul writing this, and in the present tense no less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not understand my own actions. For I do not do what I want, but I do the very thing I hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is Paul struggling with the very same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we must do is acknowledge that the spiritual battle is real and that it must be fought every day. Every single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then we must be wise to what we are up against. Again, listen to Paul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out. For I do not do the good I want, but the evil I do not want is what I keep on doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you somehow think that you have the ability to do that which was beyond the apostle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So I find it to be a law that when I want to do right, evil lies close at hand. For I delight in the law of God, in my inner being, but I see in my members another law waging war against the law of my mind and making me captive to the law of sin that dwells in my members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians through the ages have struggled to understand what Paul is saying here, for does it not seem to be both defeatist and without hope? It is neither of these things. It is gritty reality, the astute observation of one for whom there is no pretending, and the humble acknowledgement of the extent to which the hooks of sin remain in one&amp;rsquo;s life even after eternal salvation has been secured by Christ&amp;rsquo;s death and resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a war being waged then it must be fought. But it must be fought with the right weapons and in the grace of God. Let us first recognise that which is our own responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For those who live according to the flesh set their minds on the things of the flesh, but those who live according to the Spirit set their minds on the things of the Spirit. For to set the mind on the flesh is death, but to set the mind on the Spirit is life and peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what is your mind set upon? The Lord knows! And it is this which is the key to victory in the spiritual battle for our own holiness⸺earnest desire to honour the Lord in every last detail of our lives, and a longing for that which is good, right, and true to have the victory over sin in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what? Well then we must fully engage with Paul&amp;rsquo;s argument, for it is hope and strength and life and peace to each one burdened by ongoing and besetting sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now if I do what I do not want, I agree with the law, that it is good. So now it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if I do what I do not want, it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:16-17, 20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is precisely that earnest desire to live a right life in humble gratitude to my saviour that is evidence of this: I am not my sin! It no longer defines me. And so along with Paul and with a grateful heart I can declare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wretched man that I am! Who will deliver me from this body of death? Thanks be to God through Jesus Christ our Lord! So then, I myself serve the law of God with my mind, but with my flesh I serve the law of sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only through Jesus&amp;rsquo; death and resurrection can I be delivered from this wretched state. Praise my Saviour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. Much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is therefore now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus. For the law of the Spirit of life has set you free in Christ Jesus from the law of sin and death. For God has done what the law, weakened by the flesh, could not do. By sending his own Son in the likeness of sinful flesh and for sin, he condemned sin in the flesh, in order that the righteous requirement of the law might be fulfilled in us, who walk not according to the flesh but according to the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the victory. It is in Christ and it is Christ. And for those who are in Christ there is no condemnation. Instead there is freedom⸺freedom in Christ. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tension between the flesh and the Spirit remains but notice that the Lord has condemned sin in the flesh. He did this in order that the righteous requirement of the law might be fulfilled in each one of us, that is, in order that each one of us may become holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And furthermore notice this phenomenal promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But if Christ is in you, although the body is dead because of sin, the Spirit is life because of righteousness. If the Spirit of him who raised Jesus from the dead dwells in you, he who raised Christ Jesus from the dead will also give life to your mortal bodies through his Spirit who dwells in you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is nothing if not a promise of sanctification through the indwelling Spirit of Christ Jesus. These very mortal bodies which are dead because of sin will be given life. Victory over sin is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s gift of grace, the sanctifying work of the Spirit. Yes, it is utterly beyond us, but it is not beyond him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are we to do when we stumble? Simply cry out to the Lord in anguish over our ongoing sin, confess that sin, repent, and receive forgiveness and restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even when you stumble, especially when you stumble, repent, set your mind on the things of the Spirit, be lifted up once more, and by doing so choose life and peace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
