<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>pain on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/pain/</link>
        <description>Recent content in pain on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Curse the accuser?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/curse-the-accuser/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/curse-the-accuser/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/curse-the-accuser/miguel-alcantara-19IDRDmMLgU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Curse the accuser?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What outcome do you desire for your accusers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To suffer a character assassination from the shadows is utterly reprehensible. Who are these who whisper lies against you? Of course you do not know because the accusations have not been brought into the light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And this is the judgment: the light has come into the world, and people loved the darkness rather than the light because their works were evil. For everyone who does wicked things hates the light and does not come to the light, lest his works should be exposed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These accusations are indeed thoroughly wicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wicked and deceitful mouths are opened against me, speaking against me with lying tongues. They encircle me with words of hate, and attack me without cause. In return for my love they accuse me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:2b-4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ironic that in your attempt to bring a message of love you are repelled by wicked and deceitful mouths and lying tongues and words of hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, I do know the harm that they have done to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am poor and needy, and my heart is stricken within me. I am gone like a shadow at evening; I am shaken off like a locust. My knees are weak through fasting; my body has become gaunt, with no fat. I am an object of scorn to my accusers; when they see me, they wag their heads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your accusers have crushed you. So again I have to ask, what outcome do you desire for them? What outcome do you pray for? For I know that you pray, oh how you pray! And I know that you continue to praise, even in the despising and the rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be not silent, O God of my praise! For wicked and deceitful mouths are opened against me, speaking against me with lying tongues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In return for my love they accuse me, but I give myself to prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:1-2, 4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a psalm of David, that man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart. And here is something to notice right away. The Hebrew for “but I give myself to prayer” is literally “but I am prayer”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am prayer. O my soul, make it so. Clothe yourself in your prayer and wrap it tightly around you. Become that prayer. I am prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Help me, O LORD my God! Save me according to your steadfast love!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what? Know that David was beset by wicked and deceitful mouths speaking against him with lying tongues. So what was his response? What was his heart-cry? What what his prayer for his accuser? Listen and be appalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May his days be few; may another take his office! May his children be fatherless and his wife a widow!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His prayer was for divine judgment of death upon his accuser. And not only that but financial disaster upon the remnant of his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May his children wander about and beg, seeking food far from the ruins they inhabit! May the creditor seize all that he has; may strangers plunder the fruits of his toil!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And not only that but also for them childlessness and destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May his posterity be cut off; may his name be blotted out in the second generation!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This diatribe of a prayer continues for fifteen verses. Fifteen verses! What an outpouring of anger and bewilderment and pain and grief and dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several such imprecatory psalms in the Bible and some harsher even than this. What are we to make of them? And what are we to take from this? Is this to be a model for our own praying in such times?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must understand how to take these prayers of David, how to use them, how to learn from them. For his curses upon his accusers are simply repugnant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are they here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He loved to curse; let curses come upon him! He did not delight in blessing; may it be far from him! He clothed himself with cursing as his coat; may it soak into his body like water, like oil into his bones! May it be like a garment that he wraps around him, like a belt that he puts on every day! May this be the reward of my accusers from the LORD, of those who speak evil against my life!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:17-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David is hurting. The whispered accusations have crushed him. He has been destroyed by wicked and deceitful mouths speaking against him with lying tongues, and it really hurts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, it hurts, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? And it is so unjust. It is absolutely and thoroughly wicked, and it contradicts all that Jesus taught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David&amp;rsquo;s fifteen verses of diatribe show us how much he is hurting as he lashes out in prayer. With some relief we can finally observe him get it all out and move on to something more reasonable, to a curse more proportionate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May my accusers be clothed with dishonour; may they be wrapped in their own shame as in a cloak!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that he got all that out of his system is this where we should stand together with David? Again no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You have heard that it was said, ‘You shall love your neighbour and hate your enemy.’ But I say to you, Love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you, so that you may be sons of your Father who is in heaven. For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:43-45&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, having been the victim of deceitful mouths and lying tongues, of accusations whispered from the shadows from those who do not come into the light, your response must be love and prayer, and to be exceedingly clear, prayer for repentance and rescue and transformation and not for harm. For what is the best possible outcome?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So that you may be sons of your Father who is in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:45a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one day you can stand alongside your accusers as sons of your Father, then you will be brothers with them⸺brothers and sisters in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, you cannot love your faceless accusers without knowing who they are. But you can forgive them. You can choose not to resent them. You can pray for them. And you can desire reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, observe the harm and the hurt done to David by his accusers, know that you are not alone in your own hurt, and now put that aside and respond with gentleness and forgiveness! 😭🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The sacrifice of thanksgiving</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-thanksgiving/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-thanksgiving/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-thanksgiving/velizar-ivanov-V_Giq2h5jak-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The sacrifice of thanksgiving" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you grateful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, really, joyously grateful to the one who has rescued you, redeemed you, blessed you, and given you hope and a future. Are you grateful to him with all your heart? It matters that you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the way to Jerusalem he was passing along between Samaria and Galilee. And as he entered a village, he was met by ten lepers, who stood at a distance and lifted up their voices, saying, “Jesus, Master, have mercy on us.” When he saw them he said to them, “Go and show yourselves to the priests.” And as they went they were cleansed. Then one of them, when he saw that he was healed, turned back, praising God with a loud voice; and he fell on his face at Jesus&amp;rsquo; feet, giving him thanks. Now he was a Samaritan. Then Jesus answered, “Were not ten cleansed? Where are the nine? Was no one found to return and give praise to God except this foreigner?” And he said to him, “Rise and go your way; your faith has made you well.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:11-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten lepers were healed but only one was sufficiently grateful to return to Jesus, to thank him and to praise God. What did Jesus say to this one alone? “Your faith has made you well.” Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this leave us wondering, what of the others? Did they remain healed? We don&amp;rsquo;t know and we can&amp;rsquo;t know. I suspect the generosity of the Lord towards ungrateful sinners is that they did in fact remain healed. But really, shame on them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will give thanks to the LORD with my whole heart; I will recount all of your wonderful deeds. I will be glad and exult in you; I will sing praise to your name, O Most High.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 9:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So is this what gratitude must be? Ensuring to thank the Lord with your whole heart as and when you receive blessing and healing and deliverance, with the expectation of further blessing to come? By no means! O my soul, you must not settle for such an impoverished understanding of thankfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul gives us a clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all circumstances you must give thanks, even acknowledging that some of these circumstances are hard to bear. For this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider David, fleeing for his life from Saul. Listen to his words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be merciful to me, O God, be merciful to me,
for in you my soul takes refuge; in the shadow of your wings I will take refuge, till the storms of destruction pass by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul is in the midst of lions; I lie down amid fiery beasts⸺the children of man, whose teeth are spears and arrows, whose tongues are sharp swords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:1, 4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this sound remotely like one who is receiving blessing and healing and deliverance? And yet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be exalted, O God, above the heavens! Let your glory be over all the earth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even in the midst of peril how does he end his psalm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will give thanks to you, O Lord, among the peoples; I will sing praises to you among the nations. For your steadfast love is great to the heavens, your faithfulness to the clouds. Be exalted, O God, above the heavens! Let your glory be over all the earth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something profound here which must be understood, and it is the nature of &lt;em&gt;sacrifice&lt;/em&gt; in thanksgiving. Another psalmist articulates it like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I love the LORD, because he has heard my voice and my pleas for mercy. Because he inclined his ear to me, therefore I will call on him as long as I live. The snares of death encompassed me; the pangs of Sheol laid hold on me; I suffered distress and anguish. Then I called on the name of the LORD: “O LORD, I pray, deliver my soul!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 116:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in times such as these that it is costly to give thanks, and yet it is precisely because of this that the thanksgiving becomes a sacrifice. The psalmist continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Precious in the sight of the LORD is the death of his saints. O LORD, I am your servant; I am your servant, the son of your maidservant. You have loosed my bonds. I will offer to you the sacrifice of thanksgiving and call on the name of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 116:15-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has he been saved or will his death imminently become precious in the sight of the Lord? It seems somewhat ambiguous to me. Is this why his thanksgiving is a sacrifice? Perhaps he will not even survive the time of crisis and yet still he gives thanks to God. This is the sacrifice of thanksgiving, and it is costly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, I know your heartbreak and your longing. In these you must give thanks. And yes, that is so very painful, but you simply must. Be encouraged by the words of the Apostle Paul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There remain two observations still to be made and it is vital that they be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is that giving thanks &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; a situation of pain and grief and heartbreak is not giving thanks &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; these things, in some kind of passive-aggressive “thank you for hurting me” way. But it is never too difficult to find something truly worthy of thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this surely remains a sacrifice of thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second may seem to be quite close to “thank-you for hurting me”, but in fact it is not. It is the place where joy and sorrow meet and are inextricably intertwined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It is for discipline that you have to endure. God is treating you as sons. For what son is there whom his father does not discipline?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O sons and daughters dearly loved, know that your Heavenly Father is so deeply invested in you there is nothing he won&amp;rsquo;t do for your eternal good. And some of these things are painful indeed to endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the moment all discipline seems painful rather than pleasant, but later it yields the peaceful fruit of righteousness to those who have been trained by it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of the most painful experience, offer up to God your sacrifice of thanksgiving for such commitment and investment that he has made in you, that he will see through to completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asaph speaks the word of the Lord to those who may have forgotten this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who offers thanksgiving as his sacrifice glorifies me; to one who orders his way rightly I will show the salvation of God!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 50:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, offer up to the Lord your sacrifice of thanksgiving however much you are hurting! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The dam on the river</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/vlad-d-5j6tOZ4LdN4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The dam on the river" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you build a dam across the river of living water? Would you reduce to a trickle that which has been flowing so abundantly? Would you be a busy little beaver, hoarding and assembling your pain and disappointment and cementing it all in place with  unforgiveness and resentment? Would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that I do understand why you would want to build your dam. I acknowledge that you have been treated heinously and that you have been brushed aside and disregarded. And I know that you&amp;rsquo;re hurting, really hurting, and from time to time you want to assert that nobody cares. You want to shout it out across the rooftops at the top of your voice: nobody cares. It&amp;rsquo;s a lie, by the way, that nobody cares. For sure, there are some who don&amp;rsquo;t, perhaps several, and others who are only pretending. But there remain those who are loving and kind and faithful and true. Be grateful for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those insolent ones whose behaviour has been so heinous⸺those who should care and yet do not? Beware, my soul, of how you regard them in return. This is perilous ground indeed upon which you stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul. This means that you must forgive and you must let go of all resentment. You must do these things! And you must not build that dam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me remind you just what is at stake here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, ‘Out of his heart will flow rivers of living water.’” Now this he said about the Spirit, whom those who believed in him were to receive, for as yet the Spirit had not been given, because Jesus was not yet glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 7:37-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you thirst? Do you thirst for love and wholeness and relational authenticity? Come to Jesus and drink. Believe in him and listen to him. Listen to him in your sorrow and pain and dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But I say to you, Do not resist the one who is evil. But if anyone slaps you on the right cheek, turn to him the other also.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Judge not, and you will not be judged; condemn not, and you will not be condemned; forgive, and you will be forgiven; give, and it will be given to you. Good measure, pressed down, shaken together, running over, will be put into your lap. For with the measure you use it will be measured back to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive and you will be forgiven. Extend love and kindness to those who do not, and it will be measured back to you, O my soul, how it will! And rivers of living water will flow out of your heart and you will be a blessing to many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t the way these insolent ones carry on simply egregious? Yes of course it is, and appallingly so. What&amp;rsquo;s to be done then about their heinous behaviour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin; ponder in your own hearts on your beds, and be silent. Offer right sacrifices, and put your trust in the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry, O my soul. Be angry and do not sin. Notice it is “and” not “but”. Interesting! The dam on the river is not made of anger. Was Jesus angry when he cleared the temple? Yes of course he was and rightly so. There is a righteous anger and it is of the Lord. Be angry and do not sin. The behaviour is egregious and it cannot be excused. It can only be forgiven, and this you must do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And listen to the heart-cry of the Psalmist to the Lord. Make it your own as you put your trust in the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal bountifully with your servant, that I may live and keep your word. Open my eyes, that I may behold
wondrous things out of your law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You rebuke the insolent, accursed ones, who wander from your commandments. Take away from me scorn and contempt, for I have kept your testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:17-18, 21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the one who rebukes these insolent ones. And there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word of the LORD came to me: “Son of man, prophesy against the shepherds of Israel; prophesy, and say to them, even to the shepherds, Thus says the Lord GOD: Ah, shepherds of Israel who have been feeding yourselves! Should not shepherds feed the sheep? You eat the fat, you clothe yourselves with the wool, you slaughter the fat ones, but you do not feed the sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says the Lord GOD, Behold, I am against the shepherds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:1-3,10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is good news indeed for these poor sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I myself will be the shepherd of my sheep, and I myself will make them lie down, declares the Lord GOD. I will seek the lost, and I will bring back the strayed, and I will bind up the injured, and I will strengthen the weak, and the fat and the strong I will destroy. I will feed them in justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beware, O my soul, there is a warning also to these very same sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it not enough for you to feed on the good pasture, that you must tread down with your feet the rest of your pasture; and to drink of clear water, that you must muddy the rest of the water with your feet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will rescue my flock; they shall no longer be a prey. And I will judge between sheep and sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:18,22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then are we to do? Two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Forgive, and you will be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you pour yourself out for the hungry and satisfy the desire of the afflicted, then shall your light rise in the darkness and your gloom be as the noonday. And the LORD will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must do what those insolent ones will not, and then you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water. You must forgive, and love and care for the hungry and the afflicted, and pursue humility and hope and joy in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
