<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>rescue on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/rescue/</link>
        <description>Recent content in rescue on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/rescue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The things that are revealed</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/vladimir-soares-3fer5_PzDkM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The things that are revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When is a mystery not a mystery? Why, when it has been revealed of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider just what has been revealed and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically on this Good Friday I want to consider the revelation of the mystery of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will, according to his purpose, from my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;desert island&lt;/a&gt; chapter of the Bible. And of course it is all and entirely about Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of our trespasses, according to the riches of his grace, which he lavished upon us, in all wisdom and insight making known to us the mystery of his will, according to his purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time, to unite all things in him, things in heaven and things on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack this slowly and carefully, for the words are so familiar we are at risk of progressing past them without really noticing what they&amp;rsquo;re even saying, when in fact we should again be completely overwhelmed by the goodness and kindness and sovereignty and justice of the Father, and by the riches of his grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jesus we have redemption. Thayer defines redemption as a releasing effected by payment of a ransom. So we must remind ourselves from what we have been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you were dead in the trespasses and sins in which you once walked, following the course of this world, following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience⸺among whom we all once lived in the passions of our flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind, and were by nature children of wrath, like the rest of mankind.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was dead in my trespasses and sins, and this was the norm as I merely followed the course of this world along with several billion others. How ironic that those who live in the passions of their flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind thinking they are free to do so are in fact slaves to sin, in bondage, children of wrath by their very nature, like the whole of mankind. We cannot understand the magnitude of this redemption⸺this release⸺without first understanding the sheer wretchedness and utter hopelessness of the previous state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was more wretched and more hopeless even than that. I was obliviously following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience. Satan has such a hold on those sometimes seen merely as worldly, and so many remain in ignorance of this. It is entirely a spiritual battle, and without Christ the battle is hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are not without Christ! And realising this and the magnitude of the rescue, how can humble gratitude not come flooding into our hearts, and love for our wonderful Saviour? And worship and adoration of our Heavenly Father whose purpose this is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was the ransom that was paid to release us from that previous state? It was the blood of the Lamb, the very Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they brought [Jesus] to the place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they crucified him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the sixth hour had come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour. And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, “Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?” which means, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:22,24a,33-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold the only Son of God crying out in anguish, forsaken by the Father who turned his face away from his only and most beloved Son. And you and I both know the reason why, the answer to Jesus&amp;rsquo; most desperate question. We know it only because in all wisdom and insight our Heavenly Father has made known to us the mystery of his will. This is no secret⸺it has been revealed to us according the riches of his grace. Jesus was forsaken on that cross so that we may not be. The debt that he paid was entirely ours. Our redemption is through the blood of the Lamb, poured out at Calvary for the forgiveness of sins, such a costly sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father turned his face away from his beloved Son precisely so that he could turn it towards us, previously miserable, hopeless and helpless sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was all according to God&amp;rsquo;s purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time. So it&amp;rsquo;s worth asking when he did this. When exactly did he set forth this plan? Behold! It was right at the beginning!  Only moments after sin first came into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD God said to the serpent, “Because you have done this, cursed are you above all livestock and above all beasts of the field; on your belly you shall go, and dust you shall eat all the days of your life. I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rescue was planned so far ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have obtained an inheritance, having been predestined according to the purpose of him who works all things according to the counsel of his will, so that we who were the first to hope in Christ might be to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of the fullness of time? Yet more revelation, this time through John the Apostle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw an angel coming down from heaven, holding in his hand the key to the bottomless pit and a great chain. And he seized the dragon, that ancient serpent, who is the devil and Satan, and bound him for a thousand years, and threw him into the pit, and shut it and sealed it over him, so that he might not deceive the nations any longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 20:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But finally, we must remember why it is that these things are revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apostle Paul expands upon this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father chose us in him before the foundation of the world that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this we must do, out of gratitude and adoration for our wonderful Saviour, as an act of worship, and in the power and grace of our risen Lord Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still the real mystery remains. Why would he do this? Why would the Creator God of the Universe set his love upon what is unlovely, those dead in trespasses and sins, at such great cost? We cannot fathom this. We can only thank and praise and worship and adore the one who made it so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, this mystery is revealed and yet remains. Worship and adore its divine author! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Three trees</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/three-trees/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/three-trees/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/three-trees/simon-wilkes-S297j2CsdlM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Three trees" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you notice the tree of life flourishing on the river of life, yielding its fruit each month?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the angel showed me the river of the water of life, bright as crystal, flowing from the throne of God and of the Lamb through the middle of the street of the city; also, on either side of the river, the tree of life with its twelve kinds of fruit, yielding its fruit each month. The leaves of the tree were for the healing of the nations. No longer will there be anything accursed, but the throne of God and of the Lamb will be in it, and his servants will worship him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 22:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve seen this tree before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the LORD God planted a garden in Eden, in the east, and there he put the man whom he had formed. And out of the ground the LORD God made to spring up every tree that is pleasant to the sight and good for food. The tree of life was in the midst of the garden, and the tree of the knowledge of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 2:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly and quite unlike the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, there were no prohibitions concerning the tree of life, at least initially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD God took the man and put him in the garden of Eden to work it and keep it. And the LORD God commanded the man, saying, “You may surely eat of every tree of the garden, but of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil you shall not eat, for in the day that you eat of it you shall surely die.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 2:15-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve were free to eat of the tree of life but we soon learn that they did not avail themselves of that opportunity. O my soul, weep over the inclination of the human heart to pursue that which is forbidden, that which is evil, that which leads only to death and destruction. It is perverse in the extreme. It is called sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the serpent was more crafty than any other beast of the field that the LORD God had made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said to the woman, “Did God actually say, ‘You shall not eat of any tree in the garden?’” And the woman said to the serpent, “We may eat of the fruit of the trees in the garden, but God said, ‘You shall not eat of the fruit of the tree that is in the midst of the garden, neither shall you touch it, lest you die.’” But the serpent said to the woman, “You will not surely die. For God knows that when you eat of it your eyes will be opened, and you will be like God, knowing good and evil.” So when the woman saw that the tree was good for food, and that it was a delight to the eyes, and that the tree was to be desired to make one wise, she took of its fruit and ate, and she also gave some to her husband who was with her, and he ate. Then the eyes of both were opened, and they knew that they were naked. And they sewed fig leaves together and made themselves loincloths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:1-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, and so in this simple act of disobedience, this first act of rebellion against their creator, innocence died and evil came into the human heart and into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, grieve over how different the world would have been today if they had eaten instead from the tree of life which was allowed, and not from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil which was forbidden. The consequences were severe indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD God said, “Behold, the man has become like one of us in knowing good and evil. Now, lest he reach out his hand and take also of the tree of life and eat, and live forever⸺” therefore the LORD God sent him out from the garden of Eden to work the ground from which he was taken. He drove out the man, and at the east of the garden of Eden he placed the cherubim and a flaming sword that turned every way to guard the way to the tree of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two trees and the tragedy of a wrong choice. All seemed lost and the tree of life was now out of reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was a third tree. O my soul, rejoice that there was a third tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For to this you have been called, because Christ also suffered for you, leaving you an example, so that you might follow in his steps. He committed no sin, neither was deceit found in his mouth. When he was reviled, he did not revile in return; when he suffered, he did not threaten, but continued entrusting himself to him who judges justly. He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we might die to sin and live to righteousness. By his wounds you have been healed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 2:21-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third tree stood at Calvary, and on that darkest of days our Saviour gave up his own life for the sake of all humankind. For us, the rebels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what the Lord had said to Adam when evicting him from that perfect garden, and marvel in gratitude at the magnitude of what was being undone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And to Adam he said, “Because you have listened to the voice of your wife and have eaten of the tree of which I commanded you, ‘You shall not eat of it,’ cursed is the ground because of you; in pain you shall eat of it all the days of your life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the beginning. Here is the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; on either side of the river, the tree of life with its twelve kinds of fruit, yielding its fruit each month. The leaves of the tree were for the healing of the nations. No longer will there be anything accursed, but the throne of God and of the Lamb will be in it, and his servants will worship him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 22:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ redeemed us from the curse of the law by becoming a curse for us⸺for it is written, “Cursed is everyone who is hanged on a tree”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 3:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only are we redeemed from the curse of the law but so too is the whole world⸺this broken and hurting world. The tree of life bears twelve kinds of fruit, and twelve means complete. And its leaves are for the healing of the nations⸺the healing of this nation, and each one like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now recall what Jesus said to the church at Ephesus, where some had lost their way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the angel of the church in Ephesus write: ‘The words of him who holds the seven stars in his right hand, who walks among the seven golden lampstands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. To the one who conquers I will grant to eat of the tree of life, which is in the paradise of God.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:1, 7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is only one way to conquer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said &amp;hellip;, “I am the way, and the truth, and the life. No one comes to the Father except through me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then one of the elders addressed me, saying, “Who are these, clothed in white robes, and from where have they come?” I said to him, “Sir, you know.” And he said to me, “These are the ones coming out of the great tribulation. They have washed their robes and made them white in the blood of the Lamb.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 7:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are those who wash their robes, so that they may have the right to the tree of life and that they may enter the city by the gates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 22:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, wash your robes in the blood of the Lamb with a grateful heart, gain access to that tree of life, and praise him! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What child is this?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/what-child-is-this/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/what-child-is-this/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/what-child-is-this/taksh-Ss3bXajj-po-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What child is this?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this broken world need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Ukraine need? And Palestine? And Syria? And South Sudan? And the U.S.? And New Zealand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do the downtrodden and the brokenhearted need? And O my soul, what do you need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is God&amp;rsquo;s rescue plan for this broken world and for each broken heart. But the answer has already come and it came in weakness and frailty and obscurity the form of a little baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Joseph also went up from Galilee, from the town of Nazareth, to Judea, to the city of David, which is called Bethlehem, because he was of the house and lineage of David, to be registered with Mary, his betrothed, who was with child. And while they were there, the time came for her to give birth. And she gave birth to her firstborn son and wrapped him in swaddling cloths and laid him in a manger, because there was no place for them in the inn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 2:4-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an inauspicious start to an incredible, lavish, and costly rescue⸺a couple of nobodies away from home in a busy city with no place to stay, laying this newborn baby down in an animal&amp;rsquo;s food trough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perspective is everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And in the same region there were shepherds out in the field, keeping watch over their flock by night. And an angel of the Lord appeared to them, and the glory of the Lord shone around them, and they were filled with great fear. And the angel said to them, “Fear not, for behold, I bring you good news of great joy that will be for all the people. For unto you is born this day in the city of David a Saviour, who is Christ the Lord. And this will be a sign for you: you will find a baby wrapped in swaddling cloths and lying in a manger.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 2:8-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you marvel at the sheer audacity of sending a helpless baby to be the Saviour of the World, ensure to do so as Mary and not as Zechariah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the angel said to her, “Do not be afraid, Mary, for you have found favour with God. And behold, you will conceive in your womb and bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus. He will be great and will be called the Son of the Most High. And the Lord God will give to him the throne of his father David, and he will reign over the house of Jacob forever, and of his kingdom there will be no end.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Mary said to the angel, “How will this be, since I am a virgin?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the angel answered her &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Mary said, “Behold, I am the servant of the Lord; let it be to me according to your word.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:30-35, 38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is at the same time so similar to and yet so very different from Zechariah&amp;rsquo;s response to a parallel revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the angel said to him, “Do not be afraid, Zechariah, for your prayer has been heard, and your wife Elizabeth will bear you a son, and you shall call his name John. And you will have joy and gladness, and many will rejoice at his birth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Zechariah said to the angel, “How shall I know this? For I am an old man, and my wife is advanced in years.” And the angel answered him, “I am Gabriel. I stand in the presence of God, and I was sent to speak to you and to bring you this good news. And behold, you will be silent and unable to speak until the day that these things take place, because you did not believe my words, which will be fulfilled in their time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:13-14, 18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that Mary&amp;rsquo;s question asked from her surrendered heart sounded to all intents and purposes just like Zechariah&amp;rsquo;s from his doubting heart, but it was in fact so very different. “How will this be?” was asked in faith and obedience, whereas “How shall I know this?” was asked in unbelief and scepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must be Mary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Behold, I am the servant of the Lord; let it be to me according to your word.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in hope and faith and with a surrendered heart, let us ask why and how. Why would the Creator God of the Universe and Lord of All choose such an apparently risky and fragile plan? And how could this helpless baby change everything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitally Jesus was both fully man and fully God, but there is another factor here, and it is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the angel answered her &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For nothing will be impossible with God.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:35, 37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this not God demonstrating exactly this, revealing his great power made perfect in weakness? He is absolutely the God of the impossible. O my soul, he is the God of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;your own impossible&lt;/a&gt;. Consider even this one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have a helpless newborn baby and a tyrant king out to kill him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Herod summoned the wise men secretly and ascertained from them what time the star had appeared. And he sent them to Bethlehem, saying, “Go and search diligently for the child, and when you have found him, bring me word, that I too may come and worship him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Herod, when he saw that he had been tricked by the wise men, became furious, and he sent and killed all the male children in Bethlehem and in all that region who were two years old or under, according to the time that he had ascertained from the wise men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 2:7-9, 16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet Mary and Joseph escaped with the baby Jesus to Egypt where they lived for a while as refugees in a foreign land. How was &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; even possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the why is the God of the impossible demonstrating his great power, rescuing and redeeming his creation and the whole of humankind through this little baby. And how? Isaiah tells it and Handel composed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For to us a child is born, to us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder, and his name shall be called Wonderful Counsellor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, Prince of Peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 9:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This little baby would not remain weak and helpless. He was and is the great I Am, Mighty God, one with the Father, everlasting, reigning and ruling in majesty and splendour. The Prince of Peace indeed. Praise him! Praise his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And never was the birth of a baby so anticipated, so eagerly awaited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The people who walked in darkness have seen a great light; those who dwelt in a land of deep darkness, on them has light shone. You have multiplied the nation; you have increased its joy; they rejoice before you as with joy at the harvest, as they are glad when they divide the spoil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 9:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spoil is divided, &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what child is this? John tells it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through him, and without him was not any thing made that was made. In him was life, and the life was the light of men. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 1:1-5, 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God the Son, the Creator of the Universe and the one who sustains all things by his powerful word, became flesh, became a little baby, and dwelt among us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that all things were made through him and for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He is the image of the invisible God, the firstborn of all creation. For by him all things were created, in heaven and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities⸺all things were created through him and for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 11:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, marvel at the power and wisdom and goodness and mercy of the God of the impossible, and the rescue and redemption and healing of Jesus Christ who was that little baby and is the Lord of All, and praise him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Do not be angry</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/cas-holmes-_zyt1WWWdv4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Do not be angry" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that righteous anger we examined last week the right response to all the sin in the world, that sin which corrupts and stains everything, that sin which we see all around us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus came to the temple on another occasion, and this visit was so very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Early in the morning he came again to the temple. All the people came to him, and he sat down and taught them. The scribes and the Pharisees brought a woman who had been caught in adultery, and placing her in the midst they said to him, “Teacher, this woman has been caught in the act of adultery. Now in the Law, Moses commanded us to stone such women. So what do you say?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:2-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this woman epitomise all that&amp;rsquo;s wrong with society? Everyone choosing to do what they want with no regard for God&amp;rsquo;s holy law, and no regard for the cost in human suffering and shame? Surely that righteous anger is the fitting response to such a thing, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pharisees were clearly angry, but let&amp;rsquo;s pause for a moment and look into the reason for their anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This they said to test him, that they might have some charge to bring against him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth they didn&amp;rsquo;t really care about honouring the Lord, and they certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t care about the woman herself⸺she evidently meant nothing to them. They were out to test Jesus, to bring a charge against him, to bring him down. Perhaps they saw him as soft on sin, or at least soft on sinners. Their aim was to trap him into contradicting the law so that they could discredit him. Is this not precisely the behaviour of vain and dishonest men of rank? Theirs was so clearly not a righteous anger then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of Jesus&amp;rsquo; righteous anger that we saw previously?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus bent down and wrote with his finger on the ground. And as they continued to ask him, he stood up and said to them, “Let him who is without sin among you be the first to throw a stone at her.” And once more he bent down and wrote on the ground. But when they heard it, they went away one by one, beginning with the older ones, and Jesus was left alone with the woman standing before him. Jesus stood up and said to her, “Woman, where are they? Has no one condemned you?” She said, “No one, Lord.” And Jesus said, “Neither do I condemn you; go, and from now on sin no more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:6b-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon being confronted with their own sinfulness, and beginning with the older ones, they went away one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning with the older ones. Perhaps only eventually do each of us understand how far we fall short. Is there not sometimes a harshness to be seen among the younger generation in their zealous pursuit of what is right and true? Perhaps only with the passage of time and the humble recognition of ongoing failure and shame in our own lives is each of us able to say with Paul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 1:15b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s put aside then that righteous anger that Jesus would have been feeling towards those vain and dishonest men of rank, and ask, what was he feeling towards the adulterous woman?⸺for the answer to that addresses our opening question on how we should respond to all that sin and brokenness we see in the world, that sin which corrupts all. Notice what he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus stood up and said to her, “Woman, where are they? Has no one condemned you?” She said, “No one, Lord.” And Jesus said, “Neither do I condemn you; go, and from now on sin no more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus did not condemn and he does not condemn, but it matters that each one sin no more. O my soul, from now on sin no more. Your Saviour demands it! And listen to Jesus explain why he came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so the answer is compassion, not anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Father&amp;rsquo;s compassion for our broken and dysfunctional world and our own brokenness was the reason for sending his only Son to rescue and redeem, to die at Calvary where that great love was poured out for all, and to rise again in resurrection victory and power over sin and death and all that corrupts and spoils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do need to pause however and ask whether the Pharisees had a point. In all his compassion, is Jesus in fact soft on sin? And if his sacrifice at Calvary was sufficient to pay the debt of eight billion sinners, why would we any longer be concerned about the sin that remains. Cannot all be forgiven?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not so quickly forget Jesus&amp;rsquo; final words to the adulterous woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go, and from now on sin no more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:11b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else did Jesus have to say about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whoever causes one of these little ones who believe in me to sin, it would be better for him if a great millstone were hung around his neck and he were thrown into the sea. And if your hand causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life crippled than with two hands to go to hell to the unquenchable fire. And if your foot causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life lame than with two feet to be thrown into hell. And if your eye causes you to sin, tear it out. It is better for you to enter the kingdom of God with one eye than with two eyes to be thrown into hell, ‘where their worm does not die and the fire is not quenched.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 9:42-48&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are these the words of one who is soft on sin? O my soul, you must purge the sin from your own life, and you must be ruthless in this. Do not tolerate it any longer. Do not be deceived⸺look ahead to what will happen at the end of this present age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a great white throne and him who was seated on it. From his presence earth and sky fled away, and no place was found for them. And I saw the dead, great and small, standing before the throne, and books were opened. Then another book was opened, which is the book of life. And the dead were judged by what was written in the books, according to what they had done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 20:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tremble at these things, and be grateful for the book of life, written at such great cost by the author of life. Such is compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So thank and praise the Lord for his compassion which rescues and redeems. Put aside your righteous anger before it becomes self-righteousness, soften your heart, and reach out with compassion and kindness and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great rescue for this broken world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, learn to live with humility as one who was once lost and is now saved, put aside that anger, and put on a grateful and compassionate heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The answer</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/neil-mark-thomas-hgIJfyEaQQQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The answer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this answer that the psalmist received when he told the Lord of his ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And why is this followed by an immediate and urgent plea to be taught his statutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what even was the question that demanded an answer? Do you see a question here from the psalmist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s answer is not so much an answer to a question but something far deeper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find something similar in the previous psalm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Out of my distress I called on the LORD; the LORD answered me and set me free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling on the Lord is no sort of question. This is a cry for help. So what is the answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joel tells of an answer of a similar kind. In the context of the day of the Lord, that fearful day of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s righteous judgment of his own wayward people, that day of destruction, that day of reckoning, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD became jealous for his land and had pity on his people. The LORD answered and said to his people, “Behold, I am sending to you grain, wine, and oil, and you will be satisfied; and I will no more make you a reproach among the nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one question in sight here, and it is found in the prayer of the ministers of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spare your people, O LORD, and make not your heritage a reproach, a byword among the nations. Why should they say among the peoples, “Where is their God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where indeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s first understand what it means for the Lord to become jealous for his land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the LORD said to Abram, “Go from your country and your kindred and your father&amp;rsquo;s house to the land that I will show you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To your offspring I will give this land.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 12:1, 7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land was hugely symbolic of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s covenant promise to his chosen people. The Lord is faithful even when his people are not. He never once forgot that covenant promise. He never once forgot that covenant love poured out at Calvary and he never will. He is faithful in covenant love to his people even when they are not. O my soul, praise the God of your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was his answer for his chosen people in the midst of that divine and righteous judgment of the day of the Lord? It was presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LORD answered and said to his people,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be glad, O children of Zion, and rejoice in the LORD your God, for he has given the early rain for your vindication; he has poured down for you abundant rain, the early and the latter rain, as before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall eat in plenty and be satisfied, and praise the name of the LORD your God, who has dealt wondrously with you. And my people shall never again be put to shame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And it shall come to pass that everyone who calls on the name of the LORD shall be saved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:19, 23, 26, 32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compassion and kindness rain down from heaven on undeserving sinners. Praise the Lord, who has dealt wondrously with us all! And everyone who calls on the name of the Lord shall be saved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is where we started. Let&amp;rsquo;s examine the context of our opening verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to the dust; give me life according to your word! When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes! Make me understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your wondrous works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:25-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context is one in need of rescue, clinging to the dust, despairing of life itself. When I told of my ways⸺when I gave an account to the Lord of my own ruined life, when I acknowledged before him my own complete and utter inadequacy⸺he answered me, and his answer is presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice in this answer! Rejoice in the God of your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these statutes? Why does my heart cry out to the Lord, teach me your statutes? Because the only possible response from the one who understands the magnitude of the rescue is this: to live a right life, a noble life, a life that honours the Lord in every way and in every thought and in every deed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the desire we see in the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Teach me your statutes! &amp;hellip;  Make me understand the way of your precepts &amp;hellip; Put false ways far from me
and graciously teach me your law! &amp;hellip; I set your rules before me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:26, 27, 29, 30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been rescued by the God of my salvation, the Creator of the Universe, and my life now belongs to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, praise the God of your salvation for this answer in Christ, and live for him alone! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Plan B</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/senjuti-kundu-JfolIjRnveY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Plan B" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life as God had intended?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was hated by his brothers to the extent that they wanted to murder him. Narrowly escaping death at their hands he was sold into slavery at the age of seventeen and then thrown into prison in Egypt for a crime he didn&amp;rsquo;t commit, where he was incarcerated for more than ten years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this what God had intended for him? Why had this all happened? Is this what the Lord&amp;rsquo;s perfect plans and purposes look like for those he loves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means! We simply must account for human folly and foolishness. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s own life and his whole family were dominated by these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Israel loved Joseph more than any other of his sons, because he was the son of his old age. And he made him a robe of many colours. But when his brothers saw that their father loved him more than all his brothers, they hated him and could not speak peacefully to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacob, now called Israel, fathered Joseph in his old age and doted upon him, unwisely favouring him above his brothers whose subsequent envy grew to become hatred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Joseph demonstrated that he was his father&amp;rsquo;s son through his own lack of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Joseph, being seventeen years old, was pasturing the flock with his brothers. He was a boy with the sons of Bilhah and Zilpah, his father&amp;rsquo;s wives. And Joseph brought a bad report of them to their father.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At seventeen shouldn&amp;rsquo;t he have known better how to get on with his brothers than telling tales about them to their own father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Joseph had a dream, and when he told it to his brothers they hated him even more. He said to them, “Hear this dream that I have dreamed: Behold, we were binding sheaves in the field, and behold, my sheaf arose and stood upright. And behold, your sheaves gathered around it and bowed down to my sheaf.” His brothers said to him, “Are you indeed to reign over us? Or are you indeed to rule over us?” So they hated him even more for his dreams and for his words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph&amp;rsquo;s dream was from the Lord and revealed a glorious future. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that. But this revelation caused his brothers to hate him even more. They hated him even more because he was unwise enough to tell them of that prophecy which did indeed come to pass, eventually. Nevertheless, sharing it with his brothers as he did was both foolish and inflammatory. He was his father&amp;rsquo;s son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was a mistake he repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he dreamed another dream and told it to his brothers and said, “Behold, I have dreamed another dream. Behold, the sun, the moon, and eleven stars were bowing down to me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps such things are better kept to one&amp;rsquo;s self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later when he arrived in Egypt as a slave he was equally naive. Let&amp;rsquo;s first notice how this foreign slave without credentials or experience became the trusted overseer of the household of Potiphar, the captain of the guard of the Pharaoh of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD was with Joseph, and he became a successful man, and he was in the house of his Egyptian master. His master saw that the LORD was with him and that the LORD caused all that he did to succeed in his hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t this blessing from the Lord all entirely undeserved? Grace and favour were raining down from heaven on this naive young man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then he was accused by Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife of attempted rape. But notice again the pattern here. Just as Joseph had been unwise to share that dream with his brothers, so also he was unwise to be in the house alone with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now Joseph was handsome in form and appearance. And after a time his master&amp;rsquo;s wife cast her eyes on Joseph and said, “Lie with me.” But he refused &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as she spoke to Joseph day after day, he would not listen to her, to lie beside her or to be with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:6-8, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it continued day after day. His woeful encounter with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife was not an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As soon as his master heard the words that his wife spoke to him, “This is the way your servant treated me,” his anger was kindled. And Joseph&amp;rsquo;s master took him and put him into the prison, the place where the king&amp;rsquo;s prisoners were confined, and he was there in prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph again got what he deserved for his own foolishness, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? But what do we find, again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But the LORD was with Joseph and showed him steadfast love and gave him favour in the sight of the keeper of the prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The undeserved steadfast love of the Lord continued to rain down upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And whatever he did, the LORD made it succeed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually⸺and never was a word so appropriate as here in Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life⸺eventually, Joseph came before Pharaoh himself, in a way which was indeed by the hand of the Lord, interpreted his dream, and was freed to a great and glorious future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Pharaoh said to Joseph, “Since God has shown you all this, there is none so discerning and wise as you are. You shall be over my house, and all my people shall order themselves as you command. Only as regards the throne will I be greater than you.” And Pharaoh said to Joseph, “See, I have set you over all the land of Egypt.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 41:39-41&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ironic. Through those long years of incarceration God had transformed that foolish youth into a man so discerning and wise. What a miracle of grace. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you know the rest. Famine in Canaan caused Jacob to send his sons to Egypt to buy food. After some scheming by Joseph which we could see as teaching his brothers a lesson (and who could blame him for that?) there was an emotional reconciliation. And then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus Israel settled in the land of Egypt, in the land of Goshen. And they gained possessions in it, and were fruitful and multiplied greatly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 47:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this story all about then? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s incredible rescue of Joseph&amp;rsquo;s family from famine in their own land? Yes, certainly it is that. A family reconciliation after separation caused by hatred and betrayal? Yes, that too. Rescue and restoration of a naive young man from the consequences of his own foolishness? Indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ultimately isn&amp;rsquo;t this in fact all about the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for undeserving sinners? A Plan B so good and full of grace it seems to improve upon that hypothetical Plan A which never transpired. This Plan B which was wrought out of folly and foolishness and disappointment and shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much had gone wrong, but none of this pain and heartbreak and suffering was intended by the Lord nor attributable to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with us. He is the great rescuer, fully able to pick up the pieces of ruined lives and work all things together for good. His plans and purposes are not thwarted by our mistakes nor by our foolishness. Praise the Lord! And throughout Joseph&amp;rsquo;s story never once did God&amp;rsquo;s grace and steadfast love and faithfulness reach its limit. His grace is sufficient. Yes, the rescue took its time, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t it so well worth the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for your own ruined life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
