<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>transformation on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/transformation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in transformation on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/transformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>After midnight</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/after-midnight/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/after-midnight/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/after-midnight/graddes-fcavMQtHIXg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post After midnight" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why has the Lord not acted? Why are you still waiting? You were prepared to be taken to the eleventh hour, waiting and hoping and trusting, but now it&amp;rsquo;s after midnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After midnight for Cinderella: the coach has turned back into a pumpkin, the horses into mice and the footmen lizards. And here too are we, so long past midnight in our own waiting on the Lord. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it now all far too late?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who promised is indeed faithful. Rejoice in this wonderful verse, and hold fast without wavering. Hold fast without wavering for his name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so holding fast, we must now carefully read this verse in context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, brothers, since we have confidence to enter the holy places by the blood of Jesus, by the new and living way that he opened for us through the curtain, that is, through his flesh, and since we have a great priest over the house of God, let us draw near with a true heart in full assurance of faith, with our hearts sprinkled clean from an evil conscience and our bodies washed with pure water. Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful. And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:19-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin by reminding ourselves about this curtain, which was originally specified in meticulous detail by the Lord in the context of the tabernacle, that tent the Israelites were instructed to construct even while they were in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now even the first covenant had regulations for worship and an earthly place of holiness. For a tent was prepared, the first section, in which were the lampstand and the table and the bread of the Presence. It is called the Holy Place. Behind the second curtain was a second section called the Most Holy Place, having the golden altar of incense and the ark of the covenant covered on all sides with gold, in which was a golden urn holding the manna, and Aaron&amp;rsquo;s staff that budded, and the tablets of the covenant. Above it were the cherubim of glory overshadowing the mercy seat. Of these things we cannot now speak in detail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 9:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No indeed, we have not time to speak of these things in detail, or we would be reading the original six chapters in Exodus rather than these few verses in Hebrews. But those chapters are worth reading in their entirety to gain some insight into the holiness of God, and the astonishing level of consecration the priests were required to undergo before they could enter the holy place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do you remember that holy anointing oil made of myrrh and cassia and cinnamon and olive oil? Hear again the Lord&amp;rsquo;s instructions to Moses, and marvel anew at the ineffable holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“With it you shall anoint the tent of meeting and the ark of the testimony, and the table and all its utensils, and the lampstand and its utensils, and the altar of incense, and the altar of burnt offering with all its utensils and the basin and its stand. You shall consecrate them, that they may be most holy. Whatever touches them will become holy. You shall anoint Aaron and his sons, and consecrate them, that they may serve me as priests. And you shall say to the people of Israel, ‘This shall be my holy anointing oil throughout your generations. It shall not be poured on the body of an ordinary person, and you shall make no other like it in composition. It is holy, and it shall be holy to you. Whoever compounds any like it or whoever puts any of it on an outsider shall be cut off from his people.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 30:26-33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realise I am trying to do the impossible here, to convey something of the awe-inspiring holiness of God in just a couple of minutes, for this simply cannot be done. So go and read those chapters in their entirety with a view to being overwhelmed by the splendour and majesty and profound holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For we cannot understand our Cinderella story without having some grasp of the holiness of God, and the stupendous power poured out at the cross, and what this curtain is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now from the sixth hour there was darkness over all the land until the ninth hour. And about the ninth hour Jesus cried out with a loud voice, saying, “Eli, Eli, lema sabachthani?” that is, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?” And some of the bystanders, hearing it, said, “This man is calling Elijah.” And one of them at once ran and took a sponge, filled it with sour wine, and put it on a reed and gave it to him to drink. But the others said, “Wait, let us see whether Elijah will come to save him.” And Jesus cried out again with a loud voice and yielded up his spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And behold, the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. And the earth shook, and the rocks were split. The tombs also were opened. And many bodies of the saints who had fallen asleep were raised, and coming out of the tombs after his resurrection they went into the holy city and appeared to many. When the centurion and those who were with him, keeping watch over Jesus, saw the earthquake and what took place, they were filled with awe and said, “Truly this was the Son of God!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 27:45-54&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story is so familiar that we are in danger of reading straight past what is happening. So I will slow down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And behold, the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. And the earth shook, and the rocks were split. The tombs also were opened. And many bodies of the saints who had fallen asleep were raised, and coming out of the tombs after his resurrection they went into the holy city and appeared to many.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 27:51-53&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curtain separating off the Most Holy Place was torn in two, from top to bottom. The earth shook. Rocks were split. Tombs were opened and the dead were raised to life. And there were many witnesses of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular one doesn&amp;rsquo;t become a centurion in Caesar&amp;rsquo;s legions without surviving the horrors of war and the savagery unleashed on the battlefield. So pay attention to the comment from this battle-hardened veteran who was so very familiar with the awful and the terrible, and yet here was filled with awe. “Truly this was the Son of God!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this so relevant for the one waiting on the Lord?⸺the one waiting and longing and hoping? Because it shows the enormity of the power that was released when Jesus gave up his life and the curtain of the temple was torn in two from top to bottom. From top to bottom, mind you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because of the holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a new heaven and a new earth, for the first heaven and the first earth had passed away, and the sea was no more. And I saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband. And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man. He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. He will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain anymore, for the former things have passed away.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that glorious day the dwelling of God will be with his people. But make no mistake. His holiness will not be compromised. He will not lower his standards to let grubby sinners in to his perfect heaven. By no means! He will welcome in all who are holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore lift your drooping hands and strengthen your weak knees, and make straight paths for your feet, so that what is lame may not be put out of joint but rather be healed. Strive for peace with everyone, and for the holiness without which no one will see the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that holiness without which no-one will see the Lord we must be transformed, even as we are now being transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since we have these promises, beloved, let us cleanse ourselves from every defilement of body and spirit, bringing holiness to completion in the fear of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is what happens after midnight. It is after midnight in the crucible of life when it seems that all has failed that the Lord does his most profound work of transforming grace in our lives, but only as we surrender to his will, trusting without reservation and without holding back from the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, how he will! So trust him, even and especially after midnight, because that is when the things of this world are losing their grip on you. Make the most of your remaining time to repent of all that is unholy, to banish each and every shameful thought and deed, knowing that the power to do this is found only in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We know that our old self was crucified with him in order that the body of sin might be brought to nothing, so that we would no longer be enslaved to sin. For one who has died has been set free from sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For it is well after midnight and the new day is fast approaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, trust the Lord and prepare yourself for the new day which even now is drawing near! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Everything beautiful in its time</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/everything-beautiful-in-its-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/everything-beautiful-in-its-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/everything-beautiful-in-its-time/dietmar-becker-8Zt0xOOK4nI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Everything beautiful in its time" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did Solomon in fact discover anything of value on his tragic quest, on his journey of self-destruction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He most certainly did. He was after all the wisest man who ever lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have seen the business that God has given to the children of man to be busy with. He has made everything beautiful in its time. Also, he has put eternity into man&amp;rsquo;s heart, yet so that he cannot find out what God has done from the beginning to the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 3:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider this carefully, for there is enormous blessing in Solomon&amp;rsquo;s insight here, such that we should be grateful to him for the sacrifice he made of himself to uncover it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has made everything beautiful in its time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 3:11a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s focus in then on just one of these beautiful things. O my soul, let&amp;rsquo;s focus on your own failure and shame and loss and searing pain, and your despising and rejection. Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on these, for he has made everything beautiful in its time, even this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how could this possibly be true? How could something so wrong, so shameful, and so humiliating, be made beautiful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we may have to receive this in the prophetic past tense. He has made everything beautiful in its time. It is a certainty, but it may not yet have been fulfilled. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s timing is such a mystery but his faithfulness is not. His name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s dig in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is near to the brokenhearted and saves the crushed in spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can heartbreak and loss be made beautiful? Because they are a gateway. The Lord is near to the brokenhearted.  This is both consolation and exceeding joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must know, however, that you have a choice here. In your pain and loss and suffering and heartbreak, you can harden your heart and set your face and resent your situation and turn away from the Lord, or you can soften your heart and run to the Lord and cast yourself upon him and pour out your sorrow there, and surrender to his goodness and sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which will you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For in heartbreak and loss you have a unique advantage. The things of this world have lost their grip on you. If all you have is the Lord, it is so much more straightforward to put him at the centre of your life, to love him and live for him alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD, and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This of course is nothing less than an astonishing and lavish promise from the Lord that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;he will give himself to the one who delights in him alone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The things of this world are such a distraction, such a barrier to wholehearted love and devotion to the Lord. We saw that with Solomon. The Apostle Paul expands upon this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But whatever gain I had, I counted as loss for the sake of Christ. Indeed, I count everything as loss because of the surpassing worth of knowing Christ Jesus my Lord. For his sake I have suffered the loss of all things and count them as rubbish, in order that I may gain Christ and be found in him, not having a righteousness of my own that comes from the law, but that which comes through faith in Christ, the righteousness from God that depends on faith⸺that I may know him and the power of his resurrection, and may share his sufferings, becoming like him in his death, that by any means possible I may attain the resurrection from the dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 3:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not shy away from sharing in Christ&amp;rsquo;s sufferings. Marvel at the intimacy with the Saviour which is to be found there. What a privilege and what a joy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And suffering also can be a gateway to holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since therefore Christ suffered in the flesh, arm yourselves with the same way of thinking, for whoever has suffered in the flesh has ceased from sin, so as to live for the rest of the time in the flesh no longer for human passions but for the will of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 4:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not overlook your choice which will determine whether the suffering becomes a process of sanctification or of hardening. O my soul, soften your heart and surrender to the work of the Saviour upon you. It is more painful by far but the rewards are great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also do not overlook in the pain and the shame and the humiliation the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power to use precisely these to excise all pride from your life and replace it with humble gratitude. Hallelujah! What a Saviour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beware. As you start upon this path and become more aware of the enormous blessing you are receiving and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s mighty work of transformation in your life, be most careful to avoid this mistaken belief: that it is the Lord who caused your failure and shame and pain, and for this reason. For might it not be natural to suppose that he would consider the sacrifice to be worth it? But this is not how he works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord works these painful and shameful things together for good, but he did not cause them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is mystery here, and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s ways are difficult to fathom indeed, but in the heartbreak and in the pain have you noticed that your longing for the Lord is beginning to be satisfied?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have seen the business that God has given to the children of man to be busy with. He has made everything beautiful in its time. Also, he has put eternity into man&amp;rsquo;s heart, yet so that he cannot find out what God has done from the beginning to the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 3:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that the Lord is making beauty from the ashes of your life, and he is not done yet! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The things that are revealed</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/vladimir-soares-3fer5_PzDkM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The things that are revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When is a mystery not a mystery? Why, when it has been revealed of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider just what has been revealed and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically on this Good Friday I want to consider the revelation of the mystery of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will, according to his purpose, from my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;desert island&lt;/a&gt; chapter of the Bible. And of course it is all and entirely about Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of our trespasses, according to the riches of his grace, which he lavished upon us, in all wisdom and insight making known to us the mystery of his will, according to his purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time, to unite all things in him, things in heaven and things on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack this slowly and carefully, for the words are so familiar we are at risk of progressing past them without really noticing what they&amp;rsquo;re even saying, when in fact we should again be completely overwhelmed by the goodness and kindness and sovereignty and justice of the Father, and by the riches of his grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jesus we have redemption. Thayer defines redemption as a releasing effected by payment of a ransom. So we must remind ourselves from what we have been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you were dead in the trespasses and sins in which you once walked, following the course of this world, following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience⸺among whom we all once lived in the passions of our flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind, and were by nature children of wrath, like the rest of mankind.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was dead in my trespasses and sins, and this was the norm as I merely followed the course of this world along with several billion others. How ironic that those who live in the passions of their flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind thinking they are free to do so are in fact slaves to sin, in bondage, children of wrath by their very nature, like the whole of mankind. We cannot understand the magnitude of this redemption⸺this release⸺without first understanding the sheer wretchedness and utter hopelessness of the previous state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was more wretched and more hopeless even than that. I was obliviously following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience. Satan has such a hold on those sometimes seen merely as worldly, and so many remain in ignorance of this. It is entirely a spiritual battle, and without Christ the battle is hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are not without Christ! And realising this and the magnitude of the rescue, how can humble gratitude not come flooding into our hearts, and love for our wonderful Saviour? And worship and adoration of our Heavenly Father whose purpose this is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was the ransom that was paid to release us from that previous state? It was the blood of the Lamb, the very Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they brought [Jesus] to the place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they crucified him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the sixth hour had come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour. And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, “Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?” which means, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:22,24a,33-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold the only Son of God crying out in anguish, forsaken by the Father who turned his face away from his only and most beloved Son. And you and I both know the reason why, the answer to Jesus&amp;rsquo; most desperate question. We know it only because in all wisdom and insight our Heavenly Father has made known to us the mystery of his will. This is no secret⸺it has been revealed to us according the riches of his grace. Jesus was forsaken on that cross so that we may not be. The debt that he paid was entirely ours. Our redemption is through the blood of the Lamb, poured out at Calvary for the forgiveness of sins, such a costly sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father turned his face away from his beloved Son precisely so that he could turn it towards us, previously miserable, hopeless and helpless sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was all according to God&amp;rsquo;s purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time. So it&amp;rsquo;s worth asking when he did this. When exactly did he set forth this plan? Behold! It was right at the beginning!  Only moments after sin first came into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD God said to the serpent, “Because you have done this, cursed are you above all livestock and above all beasts of the field; on your belly you shall go, and dust you shall eat all the days of your life. I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rescue was planned so far ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have obtained an inheritance, having been predestined according to the purpose of him who works all things according to the counsel of his will, so that we who were the first to hope in Christ might be to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of the fullness of time? Yet more revelation, this time through John the Apostle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw an angel coming down from heaven, holding in his hand the key to the bottomless pit and a great chain. And he seized the dragon, that ancient serpent, who is the devil and Satan, and bound him for a thousand years, and threw him into the pit, and shut it and sealed it over him, so that he might not deceive the nations any longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 20:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But finally, we must remember why it is that these things are revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apostle Paul expands upon this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father chose us in him before the foundation of the world that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this we must do, out of gratitude and adoration for our wonderful Saviour, as an act of worship, and in the power and grace of our risen Lord Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still the real mystery remains. Why would he do this? Why would the Creator God of the Universe set his love upon what is unlovely, those dead in trespasses and sins, at such great cost? We cannot fathom this. We can only thank and praise and worship and adore the one who made it so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, this mystery is revealed and yet remains. Worship and adore its divine author! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Walk before me and be blameless</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/anton-darius-zjGa2RQphRA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Walk before me and be blameless" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How on earth will you walk before the Lord and be blameless?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless, that I may make my covenant between me and you, and may multiply you greatly.” Then Abram fell on his face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall why Abraham fell on his face. Despite holding that impossible promise from the Lord for all those years, his life had been defined by cowardice and lies and failure and shame. He was at this time living with the consequence of having tried to fulfil that promise in his own strength, by fathering a child with the slave-girl Hagar. And I&amp;rsquo;m quite sure he enjoyed that at the time, having sex with the youthful Egyptian slave-girl rather than his ancient wife. But not now. Not when confronted with his sin and his shame and his failure by the Holy God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thirteen long years of living with the mess of that shameful failure all together in close proximity in that dysfunctional household,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham was overwhelmed by his own sin and shame and wretchedness, and when confronted by the holiness of God and his command, “Walk before me, and be blameless,” he fell on his face. There is nothing else he could have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whatever your situation, whatever shameful failure lies in your own past, and whatever the stumbling in more recent times, this is also addressed to you. It is exactly that to which each one of us is called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been chosen for you, but how on earth will you walk before this Holy God yourself and be holy and blameless? You must do this if you would enjoy his strong support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the eyes of the LORD run to and fro throughout the whole earth, to give strong support to those whose heart is blameless toward him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:9a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t this all too much to ask of an unholy people? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Creator God of the Universe chose each one of us in Christ, even before the foundation of the world, to be holy and blameless before him. He chose you for this and he chose me. You and I both must surrender to the choice of the one who is wise and strong and who knows how to achieve his plans and purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Job&amp;rsquo;s profession of faith after he had been confronted by the overwhelming greatness and majesty of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Job answered the LORD and said: “I know that you can do all things, and that no purpose of yours can be thwarted.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same overwhelmingly great and majestic God has a purpose for you and for me both, that we should be holy and blameless before him. So cry out to him along with the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfils his purpose for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not think you can resist the irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many are the plans in the mind of a man, but it is the purpose of the LORD that will stand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 19:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must surrender your life to the Holy Spirit as he does his sanctifying work in you. Resistance is futile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can unholy creatures be made holy? The answer is found only in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you, who once were alienated and hostile in mind, doing evil deeds, he has now reconciled in his body of flesh by his death, in order to present you holy and blameless and above reproach before him, if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has reconciled each one to himself in Christ&amp;rsquo;s body and by his death in order to present each one holy and blameless and above reproach before him. So do not shift from the hope of the gospel that you have heard, but which may not just now be in the forefront of your mind. Make it so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can we become holy, even according to his purposes? His strong and sure work of grace in our lives? If you desire this end, you must set your heart upon it. But isn&amp;rsquo;t it all just too hard? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I am up against. So how then can I co-operate with the Spirit of Christ in being transformed and made holy? Simply by noticing this: the strong connection between blamelessness and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now may our God and Father himself, and our Lord Jesus, direct our way to you, and may the Lord make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all, as we do for you, so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father, at the coming of our Lord Jesus with all his saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 3:11-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the Lord himself make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all precisely so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father. Oh my!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love that abounds more and more is the way to become pure and blameless for the day of Christ, and also quite remarkably how to fulfil the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Love does no wrong to a neighbour; therefore love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the power of love that will transform each one, and this fruit of righteousness comes only through Jesus. So set your course with determination to love the Lord with all your heart, soul, mind, and strength, and to love your neighbour as yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even as you wait on the Lord, even as you cry out to him through these long years of waiting, walk before him and be blameless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will sing of steadfast love and justice; to you, O LORD, I will make music. I will ponder the way that is blameless. Oh when will you come to me? I will walk with integrity of heart within my house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 101:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the waiting and the longing here? Oh when will you come to me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But above all, know that you will only be able to do any of this because of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to keep you from stumbling and to present you blameless before the presence of his glory with great joy, to the only God, our Saviour, through Jesus Christ our Lord, be glory, majesty, dominion, and authority, before all time and now and forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/jude&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude 1:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even in the waiting time, even in the heartbreak and the desperate longing, ensure to increase and abound in love, and so walk before him and be blameless! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What do you want me to do for you?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/what-do-you-want-me-to-do-for-you/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/what-do-you-want-me-to-do-for-you/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/what-do-you-want-me-to-do-for-you/jj-ying-9Qwbfa_RM94-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What do you want me to do for you?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you told Jesus what you want him to do for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not interested in ambition or covetousness or grasping or self-interest, and neither is he, but rather life and health and strength and deliverance and mercy. Have you told him what you want him to do for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As [Jesus] drew near to Jericho, a blind man was sitting by the roadside begging. And hearing a crowd going by, he inquired what this meant. They told him, “Jesus of Nazareth is passing by.” And he cried out, “Jesus, Son of David, have mercy on me!” And those who were in front rebuked him, telling him to be silent. But he cried out all the more, “Son of David, have mercy on me!” And Jesus stopped and commanded him to be brought to him. And when he came near, he asked him, “What do you want me to do for you?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:35-41a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this interesting? “What do you want me to do for you?” This question was asked by the Word of Life himself, the omniscient Creator God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through him, and without him was not any thing made that was made. In him was life, and the life was the light of men. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 1:1-5, 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus already knew this blind man whose name was Bartimaeus. He knew his hopes and his dreams and his heartbreak and the debilitating affliction of his blindness. He was and is the giver of life itself, the one who knows and the one who loves and the one who heals, and yet, “What do you want me to do for you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would Jesus ask this? Consider Bartimaeus&amp;rsquo; answer and what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He said, “Lord, let me recover my sight.”  And Jesus said to him, “Recover your sight; your faith has made you well.” And immediately he recovered his sight and followed him, glorifying God. And all the people, when they saw it, gave praise to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:41b-43&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much faith is articulated in that simple request, “Lord, let me recover my sight”? O my soul, if you would receive from Jesus you must believe. A previous encounter with two other blind men teaches us this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And as Jesus passed on from there, two blind men followed him, crying aloud, “Have mercy on us, Son of David.” When he entered the house, the blind men came to him, and Jesus said to them, “Do you believe that I am able to do this?” They said to him, “Yes, Lord.” Then he touched their eyes, saying, “According to your faith be it done to you.” And their eyes were opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 9:27-30a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, according to your faith be it done to you. Even if you are that desperate father of the boy with the unclean spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But if you can do anything, have compassion on us and help us.” And Jesus said to him, “‘If you can!’ All things are possible for one who believes.” Immediately the father of the child cried out and said, “I believe; help my unbelief!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 9:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you want Jesus to do for you? If you believe that he can, you must ask him. Did Jesus not say as much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we finish, there&amp;rsquo;s something to notice from the context of the account of Bartimaeus&amp;rsquo; healing in Luke&amp;rsquo;s gospel. Do not overlook that the Bible was written under the guiding influence of the Holy Spirit. It is hugely significant how the various accounts were assembled, so let&amp;rsquo;s see what else Luke put together here in what later became Chapter Eighteen of his gospel. There are five preceding paragraphs and they are all so very relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the parable of the persistent widow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he told them a parable to the effect that they ought always to pray and not lose heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, don&amp;rsquo;t give up telling Jesus what you want him to do for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is the parable of the Pharisee and the tax collector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For everyone who exalts himself will be humbled, but the one who humbles himself will be exalted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must ask Jesus as one crying out for mercy. You deserve nothing, so repudiate that spirit of entitlement which is always so eager to raise its head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third is of the little children whom the disciples rebuked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But Jesus called them to him, saying, “Let the children come to me, and do not hinder them, for to such belongs the kingdom of God. Truly, I say to you, whoever does not receive the kingdom of God like a child shall not enter it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/receiving-the-kingdom-of-god-like-a-little-child/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;be that little child and depend on Jesus&lt;/a&gt;. Has there ever been such an age as ours of rugged individualism? When Jesus asks, “What do you want me to do for you?” would you reply, “Ah, I&amp;rsquo;m alright thanks Jesus, I&amp;rsquo;ve got this”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth is the tragic story of the rich young ruler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus &amp;hellip; said to him, “One thing you still lack. Sell all that you have and distribute to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven; and come, follow me.” But when he heard these things, he became very sad, for he was extremely rich. Jesus, seeing that he had become sad, said, “How difficult it is for those who have wealth to enter the kingdom of God! For it is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich person to enter the kingdom of God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must want Jesus and his Kingdom above all else. And do not overlook what Jesus said next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But he said, “What is impossible with man is possible with God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not hold back in what you ask Jesus to do for you, even if it seems impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the fifth and final and by far the most important is Jesus again telling his disciples,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;See, we are going up to Jerusalem, and everything that is written about the Son of Man by the prophets will be accomplished. For he will be delivered over to the Gentiles and will be mocked and shamefully treated and spit upon. And after flogging him, they will kill him, and on the third day he will rise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:31-33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, the very Son of God poured out his life for you on that cross at Calvary, and today and every day he pours out his love. His death paid in full both your own debt and that of all humankind. His resurrection is victory over sin and death and all that drags you down. Praise, O my soul, the King of Heaven!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bartimaeus did not hold back in telling Jesus what he wanted him to do for him, and neither must you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“What do you want me to do for you?” He said, “Lord, let me recover my sight.” And Jesus said to him, “Recover your sight; your faith has made you well.” And immediately he recovered his sight and followed him, glorifying God. And all the people, when they saw it, gave praise to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:41-43&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is glorified when all the people see what Jesus does for humble sinners who ask in faith, believing and not doubting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, believe and do not doubt, and tell Jesus the full extent of what you want him to do for you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Cosmic power</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/cosmic-power/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/cosmic-power/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/cosmic-power/42916480792-cd4b5fcfdf-o.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Cosmic power" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most truly overwhelming outworking of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s discover that in the psalmist&amp;rsquo;s song of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; for he is beautiful, and a song of praise is fitting. The LORD builds up Jerusalem; he gathers the outcasts of Israel. He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds. He determines the number of the stars; he gives to all of them their names. Great is our Lord, and abundant in power; his understanding is beyond measure. The LORD lifts up the humble; he casts the wicked to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall as I &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/praise-the-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;explained to Amy&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;he is beautiful&lt;/em&gt;, the alternative translation given in the ESV is the correct one, the reason why it is good to praise the Lord, why a song of praise is fitting. Just pause and rejoice in that for a moment. Praise the Lord, for he is beautiful! Yes indeed he is, in every way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we praise the infinitely powerful Creator God of the Universe, let&amp;rsquo;s consider for a moment that cosmic power which is his to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a very real danger of feeling overwhelmed by the sheer enormity of the universe he has created. Here in our psalm we read that he determines the number of the stars and he gives to all of them their names. In the creation account we read similarly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God made the two great lights⸺the greater light to rule the day and the lesser light to rule the night⸺and the stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He made the sun and the moon, and by the way, he also made the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something of a by-the-way about the stars in our psalm too. Notice the order in which various praiseworthy attributes are listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He builds up the city of his people; he gathers the outcasts; he binds up the brokenhearted; oh, and by the way, he also determines the number of the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, can you see the remarkable truth here? Let&amp;rsquo;s not be so dazzled by the enormity of the physical universe that we lose sight of what is really on the Lord&amp;rsquo;s heart⸺his beloved ones, and especially among them, the brokenhearted, whom he so tenderly and with great compassion binds up and does his miraculous work of healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s instead be overwhelmed by this then, that the Lord has set his love on undeserving sinners, and especially on the outcast and the downtrodden and the brokenhearted. And furthermore that he works in them and for them with that very same cosmic power⸺a work of rescue and healing and liberation from the bonds of sin and lifting up of the humble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let&amp;rsquo;s remind ourselves of that passage in Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s prophecy from which Jesus read at the beginning of his earthly ministry, for we see there a similar priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he came to Nazareth, where he had been brought up. And as was his custom, he went to the synagogue on the Sabbath day, and he stood up to read. And the scroll of the prophet Isaiah was given to him. He unrolled the scroll and found the place where it was written,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 4:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading directly from Isaiah, as Jesus did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; to proclaim the year of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s favour, and the day of vengeance of our God; to comfort all who mourn; to grant to those who mourn in Zion⸺to give them a beautiful headdress instead of ashes, the oil of gladness instead of mourning, the garment of praise instead of a faint spirit; that they may be called oaks of righteousness, the planting of the LORD, that he may be glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And continuing in Luke&amp;rsquo;s gospel,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he rolled up the scroll and gave it back to the attendant and sat down. And the eyes of all in the synagogue were fixed on him. And he began to say to them, “Today this Scripture has been fulfilled in your hearing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 4:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, let&amp;rsquo;s be overwhelmed that the Creator God of the Universe cares quite so much about his beloved ones, his brokenhearted ones and those that are oppressed, that he sent his only son, Jesus. This was Jesus&amp;rsquo; mission, and it remains so⸺to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; to proclaim the year of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s favour, and to comfort all who mourn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you mourn? Know that the Lord is making beauty from the ashes of your own life. Receive his wonderful comfort and be clothed in his garment of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one more thing to notice here. These oaks of righteousness, the planting of the Lord⸺did you notice who they are? They are in fact these very rescued ones, these liberated captives, these ones with a faint spirit. How is it possible that the bruised and broken and downtrodden become mighty oaks of righteousness in the Kingdom? It is simply because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power in restoration and transforming grace⸺his cosmic power. And we are even told why, that is, why the Lord does this work of rescue and transformation and planting. It is so that he may be glorified. Praise and magnify his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is glorified when his character is revealed and made known to the nations⸺his character which is forgiveness and rescue and steadfast love and faithfulness, as he declared to Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that making the stars was indeed very much of a by-the-way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rest in the arms of your Heavenly Father who binds up the brokenhearted, and receive his rescue and healing and transforming grace! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A pure heart</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/bas-glaap-DEQS0GFk4AM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A pure heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you given much thought to what is pure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honourable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is pure then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The words of the LORD are pure words, like silver refined in a furnace on the ground, purified seven times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 12:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This psalm underlines the striking contrast between the purity of the Lord and his words and the double-mindedness of humankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everyone utters lies to his neighbour; with flattering lips and a double heart they speak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words of the Lord then are pure, but what else? Is the catalogue of what is pure in fact a very short list indeed? Could we add to that list? What else could be pure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this one beatitude stand out from among the others as utterly intimidating? Being poor in spirit, mourning, meekness, hunger and thirsting for righteousness, being merciful⸺isn&amp;rsquo;t our response to those others, yes Lord? But being pure in heart? Isn&amp;rsquo;t our response to this, O Lord have mercy on me, a sinner? Yes of course it is, at least it is if we have any honesty in our own self-evaluation. And that is because it seems to be utterly beyond us. But is it? Is it really? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this, and as we do, give thought to the prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you want to see God? Then resolve to do this, to be pure in heart. But how? How can we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job&amp;rsquo;s friend Eliphaz uttered much foolishness in his earnest desire to help Job. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can mortal man be in the right before God? Can a man be pure before his Maker?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 4:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He followed up with two rhetorical questions, revealing the limitations of his own understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is man, that he can be pure? Or he who is born of a woman, that he can be righteous?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 15:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was wrong, O my soul. Rejoice that he was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Eliphaz the Temanite: “My anger burns against you and against your two friends, for you have not spoken of me what is right, as my servant Job has.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:7b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s try to answer the question by understanding how. How is it possible to be pure before the Lord? There are three elements which must come together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleanse means purify. Jesus came and died for you and for me and for all of humankind, that we may be forgiven our sin, that we may be justified and redeemed, and that we may be purified from all unrighteousness. The justification and redemption were an immediate and once-and-for-all-time thing. The purification is a rest-of-our-life thing and is the ongoing work of the Holy Spirit. Without the body and blood of Jesus there can be no meaningful purification, so perhaps Eliphaz was not entirely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first and most fundamental element of purification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist points us to the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man keep his way pure? By guarding it according to your word. With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments! I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this. I am that young man, so desiring to keep my way pure and yet so aware of the challenge in that, and so aware of my own propensity to sin⸺so aware of how I fall short, and therefore so resolute in guarding my heart according to the revealed word of God. And seeking him will take my whole heart, but it will be so worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you, declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all my heart I will seek the Lord, ruthlessly and unrelentingly. No holding back. No compromise. No distractions. My heart-cry is, let me not wander from your commandments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you understand what it means to store up his word in your heart? Immerse yourself in the Bible. It is his precious gift to us. Read it. Savour it. Chew on it. Digest it. Commit it to memory. And do it. It will guard your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second element of purification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third? The third element is surprising and inclined to be overlooked in this regard, but it is in fact the game-changer, the red pill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third element is the extraordinary power of love, both the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great love which came first, and our love response to his rescue⸺our love for the Lord and our love for one another. Isn&amp;rsquo;t this simply astonishing? That the outworking of authentic and abounding love could be a pure heart? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fruit of righteousness comes through Jesus Christ, and is to the glory and praise of God. It is his own work in us, and it is all of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We love because he first loved us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 4:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is love from a grateful heart. But how can purity be the result of this love? Didn&amp;rsquo;t the Pharisees expend so much energy dotting every &lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt; and crossing every &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; in order to become pure? And there are so many commandments to keep. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it all utterly wearying, completely beyond us? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Owe no one anything, except to love each other, for the one who loves another has fulfilled the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:8, 10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law, and surely this is purity before the Lord. A pure heart then is the outworking of authentic and abounding love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who can say, “I have made my heart pure; I am clean from my sin?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 20:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will for you, so receive it and embrace it and pursue it with your whole heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
