<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>discouragement on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/discouragement/</link>
        <description>Recent content in discouragement on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/discouragement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>When God does not act</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/neom-GoLWB4p8JXw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post When God does not act" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will you do when God does not act?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that I say when and not if. I say when because he has already not acted, hasn&amp;rsquo;t he? O my soul, you are so very familiar with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the silence of the unanswered prayer&lt;/a&gt; and the emptiness of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s inaction. I know you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is your way not already fully committed? You know that it is! Do you not already trust him utterly and completely? You know that you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did he then act? No he did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of these words of Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened. Or which one of you, if his son asks him for bread, will give him a stone? Or if he asks for a fish, will give him a serpent? If you then, who are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father who is in heaven give good things to those who ask him!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you not asked? Yes of course you have, and many times. Has it then been given to you? No it has not. Have you received? No you have not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of Jesus&amp;rsquo; summing up of his parable of the persistent widow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the Lord said, “Hear what the unrighteous judge says. And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? I tell you, he will give justice to them speedily.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:6-8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you cry out to God day and night? Yes you did. And did you then receive this justice? And speedily? No you did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or these words that Jesus spoke to his disciples in the upper room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Truly, truly, I say to you, whoever believes in me will also do the works that I do; and greater works than these will he do, because I am going to the Father. Whatever you ask in my name, this I will do, that the Father may be glorified in the Son. If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you not already ask in his name, understanding full well the requirement to put aside self-interest and pray the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own heart? Yes, you did, in faith and humility and complete confidence in him. And did he do it? No he did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about what he said after cursing that fig tree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the disciples saw it, they marvelled, saying, “How did the fig tree wither at once?” And Jesus answered them, “Truly, I say to you, if you have faith and do not doubt, you will not only do what has been done to the fig tree, but even if you say to this mountain, ‘Be taken up and thrown into the sea,’ it will happen. And whatever you ask in prayer, you will receive, if you have faith.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 21:20-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you have faith? I know you do. And having cast yourself upon the Lord so completely, having trusted him with your very life, having believed and not doubted, having grown into possessing a faith that could so nearly move that mountain, where does that leave you in relation to these firm assurances? These trustworthy promises? From the one whose name is Faithful and True?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For isn&amp;rsquo;t the stark reality that the Lord has not in fact acted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you give up hoping? Will you give up trusting? Will you give up waiting? Will you give up believing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or will you continue in your walk of faith and hope and trust in the Lord? Which you choose is a matter of life and death. O my soul, make no mistake here. Your very life depends upon it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must cry out with Job,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Though he slay me, I will hope in him; yet I will argue my ways to his face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 13:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must hope in him, for there is no other. But argue your ways to his face. You must do this. He can take it. Are the psalms not full of it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the silence and the emptiness and the bewilderment and the heartbreak perhaps you have two questions for the Lord. Cry out to God with these two questions: Why? And how long?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But know that the question of why is confronted head on by the Lord&amp;rsquo;s rebuke of Job. A rebuke that came after a prolonged period of suffering. A prolonged period of waiting. A prolonged period of dismay and bewilderment. The rebuke came throughout Job chapters 38-42 and could be summarised like this: “I am the LORD Most High, Creator of Heaven and Earth. And who are you exactly?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not think that you are owed any explanation for you are not. You are a grasshopper before the Lord of Hosts. Surrender that spirit of entitlement that demands you understand why. For you do not and you cannot know these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless even though he was denied his explanation of why, Job was commended for pleading his case before the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After the LORD had spoken these words to Job, the LORD said to Eliphaz the Temanite: “My anger burns against you and against your two friends, for you have not spoken of me what is right, as my servant Job has.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must continue to argue your ways to the Lord, to his face. You must!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notwithstanding the absence of any real explanation we may know that a profound work is taking place. Is this not precisely what is revealed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this you rejoice, though now for a little while, if necessary, you have been grieved by various trials, so that the tested genuineness of your faith⸺more precious than gold that perishes though it is tested by fire⸺may be found to result in praise and glory and honour at the revelation of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time of silence and emptiness is a trial like no other. You must pass this test. Your faith is more precious than gold. Nurture that faith!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And recall how Jesus ended his summing up of his parable of the persistent widow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, when the Son of Man comes, will he find faith on earth?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:8b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, will he find faith in your own heart, faith more precious than gold? If he does know that there will be praise and honour and glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second question was Habakkuk&amp;rsquo;s own heart-cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O LORD, how long shall I cry for help, and you will not hear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord? We have &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;asked this before&lt;/a&gt;. And as before we may rejoice in the answer spoken to Habakkuk by the Lord, the everlasting God, the Holy One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days that you would not believe if told.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be assured that the Lord is indeed doing a great work, a wondrous work, a mighty work which cannot be told. It is a work of faithfulness and power. It is a good and kind work. It is a healing work. It is a work of deliverance and the fulfillment of promises. It is such a work that you would not believe if told!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will you do? You must do as Abraham was commanded, after his own waiting time of twenty-four years. Twenty-four years of waiting on the Lord for the fulfilment of that impossible promise. Twenty-four years of bewilderment. A time during which he had wrestled and struggled and stumbled badly. Perhaps you too have stumbled. But nevertheless,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must walk before the Lord and be blameless. The integrity with which you live your life is of the utmost importance. In this bewildering time of waiting, your own personal holiness will be life and health and strength both for you and for others. To walk before the Lord means to live in his presence, in the context of his goodness and kindness and faithfulness and all that he has promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, hold on to hope and trust in the Lord, walk before him and be blameless! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The ordinariness of the spiritual battle</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-ordinariness-of-the-spiritual-battle/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-ordinariness-of-the-spiritual-battle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-ordinariness-of-the-spiritual-battle/denny-muller-FXrcBTOy8Fw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The ordinariness of the spiritual battle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think the spiritual battle sounds exciting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it is not. It is mundane and energy sapping and potentially also demoralising and faith destroying. Or not. But which it is, you see, is entirely up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we do not wrestle against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the cosmic powers over this present darkness, against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly places.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must be wise, for the enemy is cunning and does not show himself. How then does he fight? He fights using broken down cars and cancelled flights and malfunctioning equipment and heavy traffic and spilt drinks. He fights using sickness and frailty and sleeplessness. He fights using bad weather and lost opportunities. He fights using scowling disapproval and the withholding of affirmation. He fights in a myriad of subtle and devious ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He fights and so you too must fight. And how? One who would fight in the spiritual battle must first understand what is being fought over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Count it all joy, my brothers, when you meet trials of various kinds, for you know that the testing of your faith produces steadfastness. And let steadfastness have its full effect, that you may be perfect and complete, lacking in nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 1:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is being fought over is your very faith. Will you let it wither and die because of your sense of entitlement, that you should somehow escape what others endure? How can faith become anything at all without testing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand that the enemy&amp;rsquo;s goal for you in the spiritual battle is the opposite of steadfastness, that you become uncertain, uncommitted, fluctuating, faltering, and ultimately too discouraged even to want to continue in the walk of faith. And he has such mundane weapons in his arsenal. But,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ! According to his great mercy, he has caused us to be born again to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, to an inheritance that is imperishable, undefiled, and unfading, kept in heaven for you, who by God&amp;rsquo;s power are being guarded through faith for a salvation ready to be revealed in the last time. In this you rejoice, though now for a little while, if necessary, you have been grieved by various trials, so that the tested genuineness of your faith⸺more precious than gold that perishes though it is tested by fire⸺may be found to result in praise and glory and honour at the revelation of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:3-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there not a clear and present danger, that through this testing the things of this world may drag you down or so captivate your heart that you lose your first love?⸺not first chronologically, but first in importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same faith is both the means and the end in this spiritual battle. Take up the shield of faith. Believe what Jesus has said and remember what he has done. The disappointments and frustrations and suffering of this world cannot penetrate that shield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely the psalmist knew this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Out of the mouth of babies and infants, you have established strength because of your foes, to still the enemy and the avenger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 8:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spiritual battle deploy that childlike faith which does not seek to understand, but knows how to trust the one whose name is Faithful and True⸺Jesus Christ the righteous one⸺Jesus the lover of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will rejoice and be glad in your steadfast love, because you have seen my affliction; you have known the distress of my soul, and you have not delivered me into the hand of the enemy; you have set my feet in a broad place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you face these present difficulties, do you think the Lord is somehow ignorant of or indifferent to your affliction? He has seen it, and he has known your distress, O my soul. And he has set your feet in a broad place. In case you have felt trapped by circumstances know that in fact you are free. Because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love and faithfulness, he has set your feet in a broad place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God so that at the proper time he may exalt you, casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. Be sober-minded; be watchful. Your adversary the devil prowls around like a roaring lion, seeking someone to devour. Resist him, firm in your faith, knowing that the same kinds of suffering are being experienced by your brotherhood throughout the world. And after you have suffered a little while, the God of all grace, who has called you to his eternal glory in Christ, will himself restore, confirm, strengthen, and establish you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 5:6-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And listen again to what Jesus said to those Philadelphians, commended without reservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because you have kept my word about patient endurance, I will keep you from the hour of trial that is coming on the whole world, to try those who dwell on the earth. I am coming soon. Hold fast what you have, so that no one may seize your crown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, will you let the mundane troubles and trials of life steal away your peace and security and trust in the Lord? Steal away your faith in a good, wise and kind God of infinite power? Steal away your hope in your future salvation? Steal away the joy of the Lord? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, Jesus is coming soon, so hold fast to faith and hope and love, so that no one may seize your crown! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Light up my eyes</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/imran-ali-HV9dUe3H5z8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Light up my eyes" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you discouraged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the heart-cry of the psalmist and know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever? How long will you hide your face from me? How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day? How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long must I take counsel in my soul? Discouragement is such a lonely place in which to be⸺after all, who wants to share their discouragement with another? So, lonely but not alone in that loneliness. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that the affliction of our age?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be done about this? And for how long must it be endured?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that I wrestled with that second question for Amy. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How long O Lord is truly the most unanswered question&lt;/a&gt;, although for good reasons. Recall those reasons and hold on to them in your discouragement and dismay for they will help you to endure. But what is endurance without deliverance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discouragement must be dealt with before it becomes despondency and then depression and then the sleep of death. So what can deliver us from this? Precisely: &lt;em&gt;O LORD my God, light up my eyes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light up my eyes! This is what is needed. O my soul, this is what you need. There is wisdom in the proverb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The light of the eyes rejoices the heart, and good news refreshes the bones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus explained why this is so vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The eye is the lamp of the body. So, if your eye is healthy, your whole body will be full of light, but if your eye is bad, your whole body will be full of darkness. If then the light in you is darkness, how great is the darkness!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eye is the means by which that light enters the body, because this is how we perceive, or choose to perceive, the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more than one cause for that light to be lost. Firstly, sin. Do not underestimate the consequences to your spiritual wellbeing of persisting in sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no soundness in my flesh because of your indignation; there is no health in my bones because of my sin. For my iniquities have gone over my head; like a heavy burden, they are too heavy for me. My wounds stink and fester because of my foolishness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart throbs; my strength fails me, and the light of my eyes⸺it also has gone from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 38:3-5, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, let this not be the cause of your discouragement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now that you have been set free from sin and have become slaves of God, the fruit you get leads to sanctification and its end, eternal life. For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, grief could be the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be gracious to me, O LORD, for I am in distress;
my eye is wasted from grief; my soul and my body also. For my life is spent with sorrow, and my years with sighing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:9-10a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various reasons to grieve but each one is a heartbreaking loss of something or someone. As you grieve know that you are not alone in that. Jesus also grieves and he grieves with you. Recall Martha and Mary&amp;rsquo;s dear brother Lazarus and the sisters&amp;rsquo; bewilderment and dismay that Jesus hadn&amp;rsquo;t saved him, at least at this point in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now when Mary came to where Jesus was and saw him, she fell at his feet, saying to him, “Lord, if you had been here, my brother would not have died.” When Jesus saw her weeping, and the Jews who had come with her also weeping, he was deeply moved in his spirit and greatly troubled. And he said, “Where have you laid him?” They said to him, “Lord, come and see.” Jesus wept. So the Jews said, “See how he loved him!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 11:32-36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus wept with Mary, and O my soul, know that he weeps also with you. But even in your grief beware lest sin creep in, as the psalmist continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My strength fails because of my iniquity, and my bones waste away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your weakness and vulnerability you must be ever vigilant against sin creeping in. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace and with the power of the Holy Spirit you simply must continue in personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But irrespective of the cause of discouragement, we must ask what is the source of this light for the eyes, if we are to be encouraged, to be lifted up from our grief, to be freed from sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proverb tells more than it knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The light of the eyes rejoices the heart, and good news refreshes the bones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this good news? It is the ultimate good news, the Gospel of Jesus Christ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Again Jesus spoke to them, saying, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will not walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people who walked in darkness have seen a great light; those who dwelt in a land of deep darkness, on them has light shone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For to us a child is born, to us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder, and his name shall be called Wonderful Counsellor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, Prince of Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 9:2, 6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so with this we can finally arrive at the psalmist&amp;rsquo;s destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have trusted in your steadfast love; my heart shall rejoice in your salvation. I will sing to the LORD, because he has dealt bountifully with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has indeed dealt bountifully with each one. Trust in his steadfast love and rejoice in your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, may Jesus himself light up your eyes with grace and truth and love, and may the light of his life shine on you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
