<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>disappointment on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/disappointment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in disappointment on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/disappointment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Why have you forsaken me?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/why-have-you-forsaken-me/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/why-have-you-forsaken-me/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/why-have-you-forsaken-me/massimiliano-sarno-0Zg-9QGS0gg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Why have you forsaken me?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to give up? To throw in the towel? Are you utterly spent? Empty and exhausted? Does it seem to you that you have been abandoned by God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My God, my God, why have you forsaken me? Why are you so far from saving me, from the words of my groaning? O my God, I cry by day, but you do not answer, and by night, but I find no rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the psalmist, crying out in bewilderment to God, my God: Why have you forsaken me? Unable to sleep. Exhausted. Empty. Groaning in misery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:1a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is no answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is what lies ahead simply too hard? Is this the end? Is the enemy too strong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many bulls encompass me; strong bulls of Bashan surround me; they open wide their mouths at me, like a ravening and roaring lion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am poured out like water, and all my bones are out of joint; my heart is like wax; it is melted within my breast; my strength is dried up like a potsherd, and my tongue sticks to my jaws; you lay me in the dust of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:12-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am truly poured out. Has God himself laid me in the dust of death? I have nothing left. I am completely spent. There is no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, but there is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For there are two voices in the psalm. It is a conversation, a to and fro. We have heard from despair. But there is also hope. Listen now to hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet you are holy, enthroned on the praises of Israel. In you our fathers trusted; they trusted, and you delivered them. To you they cried and were rescued; in you they trusted and were not put to shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:3-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is hope, and here are reasons for hope. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider four reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly and most obviously, the Lord is trustworthy. Those who went before us cried out to God, they trusted him, and he delivered them. He delivered them. They were not put to shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“For I the LORD do not change; therefore you, O children of Jacob, are not consumed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/malachi&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in the Lord does not disappoint. It never has. So hope in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a second and slightly less obvious reason for hope, which is that the Lord is holy, enthroned on the praises of his people. Why is this a reason?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All around us we see reason to despair, to lose hope, to give up. People are duplicitous and there are ulterior motives. Shady and shadowy conversations abound. Self-interest is everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Surely there is not a righteous man on earth who does good and never sins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 7:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Lord is not like that. He is set apart from all that contaminates and all that corrupts. He is holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice that the Lord is holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third reason?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet you are he who took me from the womb; you made me trust you at my mother&amp;rsquo;s breasts. On you was I cast from my birth, and from my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb you have been my God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, not only has the Lord been faithful to those who went before, he has been faithful to you, your whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which leads us to the fourth and by far the most important reason for hope. Because of course the psalm is prophetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For dogs encompass me; a company of evildoers encircles me; they have pierced my hands and feet⸺I can count all my bones⸺they stare and gloat over me; they divide my garments among them, and for my clothing they cast lots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rather doubt that David even knew why he was writing this. But we know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they brought [Jesus] to the place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they crucified him and divided his garments among them, casting lots for them, to decide what each should take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:22,24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, if you think you have been abandoned by God, you need to think again about who actually was abandoned on your behalf, and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And when the sixth hour had come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour. And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, “Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?” which means, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jesus uttered a loud cry and breathed his last. And the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:33,34,37,38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? The psalmist tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the ends of the earth shall remember and turn to the LORD, and all the families of the nations shall worship before you. For kingship belongs to the LORD, and he rules over the nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posterity shall serve him; it shall be told of the Lord to the coming generation; they shall come and proclaim his righteousness to a people yet unborn, that he has done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:27,28,30,31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has done it! The curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. Nothing now separates us from our Heavenly Father. Thank and praise the Lord that he has done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who shall bring any charge against God&amp;rsquo;s elect? It is God who justifies. Who is to condemn? Christ Jesus is the one who died⸺more than that, who was raised⸺who is at the right hand of God, who indeed is interceding for us. Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:33-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice that nothing can separate you from the love of Christ, no matter how hard the journey seems! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When God does not act</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/neom-GoLWB4p8JXw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post When God does not act" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will you do when God does not act?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that I say when and not if. I say when because he has already not acted, hasn&amp;rsquo;t he? O my soul, you are so very familiar with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the silence of the unanswered prayer&lt;/a&gt; and the emptiness of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s inaction. I know you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is your way not already fully committed? You know that it is! Do you not already trust him utterly and completely? You know that you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did he then act? No he did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of these words of Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened. Or which one of you, if his son asks him for bread, will give him a stone? Or if he asks for a fish, will give him a serpent? If you then, who are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father who is in heaven give good things to those who ask him!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you not asked? Yes of course you have, and many times. Has it then been given to you? No it has not. Have you received? No you have not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of Jesus&amp;rsquo; summing up of his parable of the persistent widow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the Lord said, “Hear what the unrighteous judge says. And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? I tell you, he will give justice to them speedily.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:6-8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you cry out to God day and night? Yes you did. And did you then receive this justice? And speedily? No you did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or these words that Jesus spoke to his disciples in the upper room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Truly, truly, I say to you, whoever believes in me will also do the works that I do; and greater works than these will he do, because I am going to the Father. Whatever you ask in my name, this I will do, that the Father may be glorified in the Son. If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you not already ask in his name, understanding full well the requirement to put aside self-interest and pray the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own heart? Yes, you did, in faith and humility and complete confidence in him. And did he do it? No he did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about what he said after cursing that fig tree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the disciples saw it, they marvelled, saying, “How did the fig tree wither at once?” And Jesus answered them, “Truly, I say to you, if you have faith and do not doubt, you will not only do what has been done to the fig tree, but even if you say to this mountain, ‘Be taken up and thrown into the sea,’ it will happen. And whatever you ask in prayer, you will receive, if you have faith.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 21:20-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you have faith? I know you do. And having cast yourself upon the Lord so completely, having trusted him with your very life, having believed and not doubted, having grown into possessing a faith that could so nearly move that mountain, where does that leave you in relation to these firm assurances? These trustworthy promises? From the one whose name is Faithful and True?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For isn&amp;rsquo;t the stark reality that the Lord has not in fact acted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you give up hoping? Will you give up trusting? Will you give up waiting? Will you give up believing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or will you continue in your walk of faith and hope and trust in the Lord? Which you choose is a matter of life and death. O my soul, make no mistake here. Your very life depends upon it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must cry out with Job,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Though he slay me, I will hope in him; yet I will argue my ways to his face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 13:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must hope in him, for there is no other. But argue your ways to his face. You must do this. He can take it. Are the psalms not full of it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the silence and the emptiness and the bewilderment and the heartbreak perhaps you have two questions for the Lord. Cry out to God with these two questions: Why? And how long?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But know that the question of why is confronted head on by the Lord&amp;rsquo;s rebuke of Job. A rebuke that came after a prolonged period of suffering. A prolonged period of waiting. A prolonged period of dismay and bewilderment. The rebuke came throughout Job chapters 38-42 and could be summarised like this: “I am the LORD Most High, Creator of Heaven and Earth. And who are you exactly?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not think that you are owed any explanation for you are not. You are a grasshopper before the Lord of Hosts. Surrender that spirit of entitlement that demands you understand why. For you do not and you cannot know these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless even though he was denied his explanation of why, Job was commended for pleading his case before the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After the LORD had spoken these words to Job, the LORD said to Eliphaz the Temanite: “My anger burns against you and against your two friends, for you have not spoken of me what is right, as my servant Job has.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must continue to argue your ways to the Lord, to his face. You must!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notwithstanding the absence of any real explanation we may know that a profound work is taking place. Is this not precisely what is revealed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this you rejoice, though now for a little while, if necessary, you have been grieved by various trials, so that the tested genuineness of your faith⸺more precious than gold that perishes though it is tested by fire⸺may be found to result in praise and glory and honour at the revelation of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time of silence and emptiness is a trial like no other. You must pass this test. Your faith is more precious than gold. Nurture that faith!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And recall how Jesus ended his summing up of his parable of the persistent widow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, when the Son of Man comes, will he find faith on earth?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:8b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, will he find faith in your own heart, faith more precious than gold? If he does know that there will be praise and honour and glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second question was Habakkuk&amp;rsquo;s own heart-cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O LORD, how long shall I cry for help, and you will not hear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord? We have &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;asked this before&lt;/a&gt;. And as before we may rejoice in the answer spoken to Habakkuk by the Lord, the everlasting God, the Holy One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days that you would not believe if told.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be assured that the Lord is indeed doing a great work, a wondrous work, a mighty work which cannot be told. It is a work of faithfulness and power. It is a good and kind work. It is a healing work. It is a work of deliverance and the fulfillment of promises. It is such a work that you would not believe if told!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will you do? You must do as Abraham was commanded, after his own waiting time of twenty-four years. Twenty-four years of waiting on the Lord for the fulfilment of that impossible promise. Twenty-four years of bewilderment. A time during which he had wrestled and struggled and stumbled badly. Perhaps you too have stumbled. But nevertheless,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must walk before the Lord and be blameless. The integrity with which you live your life is of the utmost importance. In this bewildering time of waiting, your own personal holiness will be life and health and strength both for you and for others. To walk before the Lord means to live in his presence, in the context of his goodness and kindness and faithfulness and all that he has promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, hold on to hope and trust in the Lord, walk before him and be blameless! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Plan B</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/senjuti-kundu-JfolIjRnveY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Plan B" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life as God had intended?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was hated by his brothers to the extent that they wanted to murder him. Narrowly escaping death at their hands he was sold into slavery at the age of seventeen and then thrown into prison in Egypt for a crime he didn&amp;rsquo;t commit, where he was incarcerated for more than ten years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this what God had intended for him? Why had this all happened? Is this what the Lord&amp;rsquo;s perfect plans and purposes look like for those he loves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means! We simply must account for human folly and foolishness. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s own life and his whole family were dominated by these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Israel loved Joseph more than any other of his sons, because he was the son of his old age. And he made him a robe of many colours. But when his brothers saw that their father loved him more than all his brothers, they hated him and could not speak peacefully to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacob, now called Israel, fathered Joseph in his old age and doted upon him, unwisely favouring him above his brothers whose subsequent envy grew to become hatred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Joseph demonstrated that he was his father&amp;rsquo;s son through his own lack of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Joseph, being seventeen years old, was pasturing the flock with his brothers. He was a boy with the sons of Bilhah and Zilpah, his father&amp;rsquo;s wives. And Joseph brought a bad report of them to their father.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At seventeen shouldn&amp;rsquo;t he have known better how to get on with his brothers than telling tales about them to their own father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Joseph had a dream, and when he told it to his brothers they hated him even more. He said to them, “Hear this dream that I have dreamed: Behold, we were binding sheaves in the field, and behold, my sheaf arose and stood upright. And behold, your sheaves gathered around it and bowed down to my sheaf.” His brothers said to him, “Are you indeed to reign over us? Or are you indeed to rule over us?” So they hated him even more for his dreams and for his words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph&amp;rsquo;s dream was from the Lord and revealed a glorious future. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that. But this revelation caused his brothers to hate him even more. They hated him even more because he was unwise enough to tell them of that prophecy which did indeed come to pass, eventually. Nevertheless, sharing it with his brothers as he did was both foolish and inflammatory. He was his father&amp;rsquo;s son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was a mistake he repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he dreamed another dream and told it to his brothers and said, “Behold, I have dreamed another dream. Behold, the sun, the moon, and eleven stars were bowing down to me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps such things are better kept to one&amp;rsquo;s self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later when he arrived in Egypt as a slave he was equally naive. Let&amp;rsquo;s first notice how this foreign slave without credentials or experience became the trusted overseer of the household of Potiphar, the captain of the guard of the Pharaoh of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD was with Joseph, and he became a successful man, and he was in the house of his Egyptian master. His master saw that the LORD was with him and that the LORD caused all that he did to succeed in his hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t this blessing from the Lord all entirely undeserved? Grace and favour were raining down from heaven on this naive young man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then he was accused by Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife of attempted rape. But notice again the pattern here. Just as Joseph had been unwise to share that dream with his brothers, so also he was unwise to be in the house alone with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now Joseph was handsome in form and appearance. And after a time his master&amp;rsquo;s wife cast her eyes on Joseph and said, “Lie with me.” But he refused &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as she spoke to Joseph day after day, he would not listen to her, to lie beside her or to be with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:6-8, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it continued day after day. His woeful encounter with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife was not an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As soon as his master heard the words that his wife spoke to him, “This is the way your servant treated me,” his anger was kindled. And Joseph&amp;rsquo;s master took him and put him into the prison, the place where the king&amp;rsquo;s prisoners were confined, and he was there in prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph again got what he deserved for his own foolishness, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? But what do we find, again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But the LORD was with Joseph and showed him steadfast love and gave him favour in the sight of the keeper of the prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The undeserved steadfast love of the Lord continued to rain down upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And whatever he did, the LORD made it succeed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually⸺and never was a word so appropriate as here in Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life⸺eventually, Joseph came before Pharaoh himself, in a way which was indeed by the hand of the Lord, interpreted his dream, and was freed to a great and glorious future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Pharaoh said to Joseph, “Since God has shown you all this, there is none so discerning and wise as you are. You shall be over my house, and all my people shall order themselves as you command. Only as regards the throne will I be greater than you.” And Pharaoh said to Joseph, “See, I have set you over all the land of Egypt.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 41:39-41&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ironic. Through those long years of incarceration God had transformed that foolish youth into a man so discerning and wise. What a miracle of grace. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you know the rest. Famine in Canaan caused Jacob to send his sons to Egypt to buy food. After some scheming by Joseph which we could see as teaching his brothers a lesson (and who could blame him for that?) there was an emotional reconciliation. And then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus Israel settled in the land of Egypt, in the land of Goshen. And they gained possessions in it, and were fruitful and multiplied greatly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 47:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this story all about then? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s incredible rescue of Joseph&amp;rsquo;s family from famine in their own land? Yes, certainly it is that. A family reconciliation after separation caused by hatred and betrayal? Yes, that too. Rescue and restoration of a naive young man from the consequences of his own foolishness? Indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ultimately isn&amp;rsquo;t this in fact all about the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for undeserving sinners? A Plan B so good and full of grace it seems to improve upon that hypothetical Plan A which never transpired. This Plan B which was wrought out of folly and foolishness and disappointment and shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much had gone wrong, but none of this pain and heartbreak and suffering was intended by the Lord nor attributable to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with us. He is the great rescuer, fully able to pick up the pieces of ruined lives and work all things together for good. His plans and purposes are not thwarted by our mistakes nor by our foolishness. Praise the Lord! And throughout Joseph&amp;rsquo;s story never once did God&amp;rsquo;s grace and steadfast love and faithfulness reach its limit. His grace is sufficient. Yes, the rescue took its time, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t it so well worth the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for your own ruined life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The dam on the river</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/vlad-d-5j6tOZ4LdN4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The dam on the river" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you build a dam across the river of living water? Would you reduce to a trickle that which has been flowing so abundantly? Would you be a busy little beaver, hoarding and assembling your pain and disappointment and cementing it all in place with  unforgiveness and resentment? Would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that I do understand why you would want to build your dam. I acknowledge that you have been treated heinously and that you have been brushed aside and disregarded. And I know that you&amp;rsquo;re hurting, really hurting, and from time to time you want to assert that nobody cares. You want to shout it out across the rooftops at the top of your voice: nobody cares. It&amp;rsquo;s a lie, by the way, that nobody cares. For sure, there are some who don&amp;rsquo;t, perhaps several, and others who are only pretending. But there remain those who are loving and kind and faithful and true. Be grateful for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those insolent ones whose behaviour has been so heinous⸺those who should care and yet do not? Beware, my soul, of how you regard them in return. This is perilous ground indeed upon which you stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul. This means that you must forgive and you must let go of all resentment. You must do these things! And you must not build that dam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me remind you just what is at stake here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, ‘Out of his heart will flow rivers of living water.’” Now this he said about the Spirit, whom those who believed in him were to receive, for as yet the Spirit had not been given, because Jesus was not yet glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 7:37-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you thirst? Do you thirst for love and wholeness and relational authenticity? Come to Jesus and drink. Believe in him and listen to him. Listen to him in your sorrow and pain and dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But I say to you, Do not resist the one who is evil. But if anyone slaps you on the right cheek, turn to him the other also.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Judge not, and you will not be judged; condemn not, and you will not be condemned; forgive, and you will be forgiven; give, and it will be given to you. Good measure, pressed down, shaken together, running over, will be put into your lap. For with the measure you use it will be measured back to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive and you will be forgiven. Extend love and kindness to those who do not, and it will be measured back to you, O my soul, how it will! And rivers of living water will flow out of your heart and you will be a blessing to many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t the way these insolent ones carry on simply egregious? Yes of course it is, and appallingly so. What&amp;rsquo;s to be done then about their heinous behaviour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin; ponder in your own hearts on your beds, and be silent. Offer right sacrifices, and put your trust in the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry, O my soul. Be angry and do not sin. Notice it is “and” not “but”. Interesting! The dam on the river is not made of anger. Was Jesus angry when he cleared the temple? Yes of course he was and rightly so. There is a righteous anger and it is of the Lord. Be angry and do not sin. The behaviour is egregious and it cannot be excused. It can only be forgiven, and this you must do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And listen to the heart-cry of the Psalmist to the Lord. Make it your own as you put your trust in the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal bountifully with your servant, that I may live and keep your word. Open my eyes, that I may behold
wondrous things out of your law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You rebuke the insolent, accursed ones, who wander from your commandments. Take away from me scorn and contempt, for I have kept your testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:17-18, 21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the one who rebukes these insolent ones. And there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word of the LORD came to me: “Son of man, prophesy against the shepherds of Israel; prophesy, and say to them, even to the shepherds, Thus says the Lord GOD: Ah, shepherds of Israel who have been feeding yourselves! Should not shepherds feed the sheep? You eat the fat, you clothe yourselves with the wool, you slaughter the fat ones, but you do not feed the sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says the Lord GOD, Behold, I am against the shepherds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:1-3,10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is good news indeed for these poor sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I myself will be the shepherd of my sheep, and I myself will make them lie down, declares the Lord GOD. I will seek the lost, and I will bring back the strayed, and I will bind up the injured, and I will strengthen the weak, and the fat and the strong I will destroy. I will feed them in justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beware, O my soul, there is a warning also to these very same sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it not enough for you to feed on the good pasture, that you must tread down with your feet the rest of your pasture; and to drink of clear water, that you must muddy the rest of the water with your feet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will rescue my flock; they shall no longer be a prey. And I will judge between sheep and sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:18,22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then are we to do? Two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Forgive, and you will be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you pour yourself out for the hungry and satisfy the desire of the afflicted, then shall your light rise in the darkness and your gloom be as the noonday. And the LORD will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must do what those insolent ones will not, and then you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water. You must forgive, and love and care for the hungry and the afflicted, and pursue humility and hope and joy in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>That was yesterday</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/istrfry-marcus-NX0WjgdQl58-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post That was yesterday" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened yesterday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were you hoping for great things? Were you expecting great things? And are you tempted to say, “nothing”? That nothing happened? (You would be so very wrong about that, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that nothing happened yesterday, now what? What will you do now? Where is hope? How can hope survive the passing of yet another day, the unrelenting accumulation of which become inexorable years? How can faith survive this, O my soul? How will this rollercoaster of expectation and disappointment not simply grind you down into the dust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How indeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how. There are three reasons. The first reason is to understand that disappointment is a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointment is a lie because it presupposes failure. But what failure would that be, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Joshua, now old and well advanced in years, passing on some wisdom at the end of his own life to those who would come after him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now I am about to go the way of all the earth, and you know in your hearts and souls, all of you, that not one word has failed of all the good things that the LORD your God promised concerning you. All have come to pass for you; not one of them has failed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not one of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promises had failed, nor has failed, nor will fail. Know that he is faithful and true, O my soul, to all that he has said, and to all that he is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that what you were hoping for yesterday didn&amp;rsquo;t happen, what you were expecting, what you were so committed in faith to receiving, then listen to the Lord himself, speaking through Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me, declaring the end from the beginning and from ancient times things not yet done, saying, ‘My counsel shall stand, and I will accomplish all my purpose,’ calling a bird of prey from the east, the man of my counsel from a far country. I have spoken, and I will bring it to pass; I have purposed, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 46:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sure, there are things not yet done, but there is none like God, declaring the end from the beginning, from ancient times. O my soul, he will do it! He will accomplish all he has purposed! Know that nothing has failed. Trust him still and praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason is because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts. Poured out for you, O my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we have been justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ. Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope, and hope does not put us to shame, because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will have to return another time to rejoicing in our sufferings but for now consider just that final verse, for which the Berean Standard Bible rendition is particularly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And hope does not disappoint us, because God has poured out His love into our hearts through the Holy Spirit, whom He has given us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:5 BSB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope does not disappoint. God himself is both the giver and the one who pours. It is his own great love. He poured out that same love at Calvary, O my soul. Rejoice in hope of the glory of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and final reason is to understand at least something of what did actually happen yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was I hoping for? Isaiah knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Oh that you would rend the heavens and come down, that the mountains might quake at your presence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that the Creator God of the Universe, awesome in power and terrifying in purity but also so very good and kind, would break into this impossible situation, breathing out grace and truth and power into my own life and those around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So did he?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From of old no one has heard or perceived by the ear, no eye has seen a God besides you, who acts for those who wait for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah tells us that the Lord acts. Not that he will act, or even that he did act, but that he acts, in the present tense. He is working right now with great power for those who wait for him. Will you be that, O my soul? Will you continue to be that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is it that he is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habbakuk knows and it cannot be told. The Lord himself declares it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days that you would not believe if told.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonder and be astounded, O my soul, at what the Lord is already doing in your life, and renounce disappointment! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
