<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>mercy on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/mercy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in mercy on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/mercy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A wondrous reason</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/a-wondrous-reason/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/a-wondrous-reason/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/a-wondrous-reason/federico-burgalassi-K7M-TG05LTo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A wondrous reason" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you think by now things would have changed? That the God of all power and knowledge of every last detail about you and your situation, and being deeply invested in both, would have acted? And has he still not? Even after all this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We considered this quite recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the silence and in the inaction you must continue to trust in him. You must! And even as you wait on him, believing and not doubting, know that he is doing a mighty work of transformation in you, building love and holiness and faith⸺so much faith!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, the longing does not go away, does it?⸺longing for deliverance, for mercy, and for judgment on that which dishonours the Lord. Because there is plenty that dishonours his Holy Name, and it is close at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s now discover another reason for the waiting, for the delay, for the apparent inaction. And may our discovery be faith-building, as we marvel once again at the goodness and mercy of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you long for God to act with mighty power to deal with all that you face and all that is faced by this broken world, do be careful what you wish for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think that the Lord doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel similarly about today&amp;rsquo;s world and today&amp;rsquo;s evil?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what he had done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then God said, “Let us make man in our image, after our likeness. And let them have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the heavens and over the livestock and over all the earth and over every creeping thing that creeps on the earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So God created man in his own image, in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humankind had been created in God&amp;rsquo;s own image with such capacity for love, for goodness, for kindness, and for holiness. But in his infinite wisdom and out of love God had not created automata, programmed simply to follow the Maker&amp;rsquo;s desired path. For love is defined by the ability to choose to love, goodness and kindness by the ability to choose them, and holiness too. And with that ability to choose comes the ability to choose not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a risk God had taken in creating such beings. And now he regretted that he had made humankind on the earth and it grieved him to his heart. Tremble at his intent to deal with the wickedness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet at the same time be grateful that there was one who stayed his hand, that there was a but.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Noah found favour in the eyes of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the generations of Noah. Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation. Noah walked with God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 6:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One righteous man was the reason that God did not blot out humankind from the face of the earth. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it almost unfathomable that a single human life lived with holiness and in honour of the Lord could have had such a profound impact upon the whole human race? O my soul, do not underestimate the value of living a God-honouring life of personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why are we even here considering Noah in the context of our opening question? Simply because of what the Apostle Peter wrote, and what he wrote is profound. He wrote first and foremost about facing trials and suffering and evil in the world, and he was clearly familiar with waiting and hoping and longing for deliverance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, all of you, have unity of mind, sympathy, brotherly love, a tender heart, and a humble mind. Do not repay evil for evil or reviling for reviling, but on the contrary, bless, for to this you were called, that you may obtain a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 3:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He continues by quoting Psalm 34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whoever desires to love life and see good days, let him keep his tongue from evil and his lips from speaking deceit; let him turn away from evil and do good; let him seek peace and pursue it. For the eyes of the Lord are on the righteous, and his ears are open to their prayer. But the face of the Lord is against those who do evil.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 3:10-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your place of hoping and longing and waiting, immerse yourself in Psalm 34, and know that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s ears are open to your prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will bless the LORD at all times; his praise shall continually be in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I sought the LORD, and he answered me and delivered me from all my fears.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who look to him are radiant, and their faces shall never be ashamed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is near to the brokenhearted and saves the crushed in spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD redeems the life of his servants; none of those who take refuge in him will be condemned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we must move on to Peter&amp;rsquo;s point about Noah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Christ also suffered once for sins, the righteous for the unrighteous, that he might bring us to God, being put to death in the flesh but made alive in the spirit, in which he went and proclaimed to the spirits in prison, because they formerly did not obey, when God&amp;rsquo;s patience waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was being prepared, in which a few, that is, eight persons, were brought safely through water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 3:18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? God&amp;rsquo;s patience waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was being prepared. It is not inaction at all that we see from the Lord, but rather patience. And why is he patient?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Peter 3:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there we have it. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s strong desire is that none should perish but that all should reach repentance. And so he holds back, as he himself is waiting, is longing, is hoping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be patient yourself, trust the Lord, and keep waiting and longing and hoping! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>New mercy</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/karl-magnuson-HQR_JXd-fPs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post New mercy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is far more significant than the new year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is new mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;As I remarked previously&lt;/a&gt; the context of these verses is the destruction of Jerusalem after Nebuchadnezzar&amp;rsquo;s siege of a year-and-a-half, and the exile of Judah to Babylon⸺the grimmest of times indeed, and moreover, the judgment of the Lord on his own people for their ongoing waywardness and apostasy. Enough was enough. But we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have unceasing steadfast love and mercy, &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt;, which so often go together and are surely &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/love-mercy/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Lord&amp;rsquo;s most defining attributes&lt;/a&gt; as he revealed on Mount Sinai in response to Moses&amp;rsquo; request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.” And Moses quickly bowed his head toward the earth and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:18, 34:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of such power and love and mercy, Moses&amp;rsquo; response was the only one possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s description of himself was &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;nâsâh&lt;/em&gt;, the last of which means forgiving, or so beautifully, lifting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, take a breath right now and worship the Lord of Hosts, whose name is love and mercy and forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must not move past this revelation of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s character without noticing where it came in the sequence of events. Moses had previously been with the Lord on Mount Sinai for forty days and forty nights, during which time he received instruction on how the Israelites were to live to honour the Lord, which was written on those two tablets of stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he gave to Moses, when he had finished speaking with him on Mount Sinai, the two tablets of the testimony, tablets of stone, written with the finger of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 31:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what did Moses find when he descended from the mountain of God? The Israelites had made for themselves a golden calf which they worshipped. In dismay Moses threw the tablets to the ground and broke them, and directed the faithful remnant, the Levites, to strap on swords and execute their brothers and neighbours throughout the camp, about three thousand. More subsequently died of the plague sent by the Lord in judgment on his people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this relevant? Because of what happened next. Moses was instructed to make new tablets, and the Lord revealed himself again as the God of love and mercy and forgiveness and also vengeance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said, “Behold, I am making a covenant. Before all your people I will do marvels, such as have not been created in all the earth or in any nation. And all the people among whom you are shall see the work of the LORD, for it is an awesome thing that I will do with you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they were given instructions. Again. Including this. Again. O my soul, grieve that this was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You shall not make for yourself any gods of cast metal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But also, interestingly, this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You shall not offer the blood of my sacrifice with anything leavened, or let the sacrifice of the Feast of the Passover remain until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which echoes in this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the flesh of the sacrifice of his peace offerings for thanksgiving shall be eaten on the day of his offering. He shall not leave any of it until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/leviticus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 7:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sacrifice was not to be left until the morning. But why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is precisely where we came in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s mercy is new every morning. It is simply not appropriate that the sacrifice remain until the next morning because new mercy has flooded in and it is overwhelmingly sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is new about this mercy? It is precisely because of the context of these verses⸺the propensity of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people to continue in their waywardness and apostasy, as it ever has been and still remains to this day. His mercy is new every morning and so very needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not be deceived. There are two mistakes you must avoid. The first is to think that somehow your own heart is different from those Israelites, that you are somehow better. You are not. That propensity for waywardness and unbelief and sin remains, and so you must be vigilant and disciplined and repentant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second mistake is to doubt the sufficiency of that new mercy. But his mercy is more, and his mercy is new every morning! And his forgiveness is a lifting up anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So rejoice in the very next verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The LORD is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is indeed my portion and my inheritance. He is all I need and therefore I will hope in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just as with Moses, there is only one possible response to this revelation of the character of God, and it is worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bless the LORD, O my soul, and all that is within me, bless his holy name! Bless the LORD, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits, who forgives all your iniquity, who heals all your diseases, who redeems your life from the pit, who crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, who satisfies you with good so that your youth is renewed like the eagle&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 103:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt;. He crowns you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, worship the one who crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, and put all your hope in him for this brave new year! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
