<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>faithfulness on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/faithfulness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in faithfulness on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/faithfulness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The answer</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/neil-mark-thomas-hgIJfyEaQQQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The answer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this answer that the psalmist received when he told the Lord of his ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And why is this followed by an immediate and urgent plea to be taught his statutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what even was the question that demanded an answer? Do you see a question here from the psalmist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s answer is not so much an answer to a question but something far deeper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find something similar in the previous psalm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Out of my distress I called on the LORD; the LORD answered me and set me free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling on the Lord is no sort of question. This is a cry for help. So what is the answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joel tells of an answer of a similar kind. In the context of the day of the Lord, that fearful day of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s righteous judgment of his own wayward people, that day of destruction, that day of reckoning, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD became jealous for his land and had pity on his people. The LORD answered and said to his people, “Behold, I am sending to you grain, wine, and oil, and you will be satisfied; and I will no more make you a reproach among the nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one question in sight here, and it is found in the prayer of the ministers of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spare your people, O LORD, and make not your heritage a reproach, a byword among the nations. Why should they say among the peoples, “Where is their God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where indeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s first understand what it means for the Lord to become jealous for his land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the LORD said to Abram, “Go from your country and your kindred and your father&amp;rsquo;s house to the land that I will show you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To your offspring I will give this land.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 12:1, 7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land was hugely symbolic of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s covenant promise to his chosen people. The Lord is faithful even when his people are not. He never once forgot that covenant promise. He never once forgot that covenant love poured out at Calvary and he never will. He is faithful in covenant love to his people even when they are not. O my soul, praise the God of your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was his answer for his chosen people in the midst of that divine and righteous judgment of the day of the Lord? It was presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LORD answered and said to his people,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be glad, O children of Zion, and rejoice in the LORD your God, for he has given the early rain for your vindication; he has poured down for you abundant rain, the early and the latter rain, as before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall eat in plenty and be satisfied, and praise the name of the LORD your God, who has dealt wondrously with you. And my people shall never again be put to shame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And it shall come to pass that everyone who calls on the name of the LORD shall be saved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:19, 23, 26, 32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compassion and kindness rain down from heaven on undeserving sinners. Praise the Lord, who has dealt wondrously with us all! And everyone who calls on the name of the Lord shall be saved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is where we started. Let&amp;rsquo;s examine the context of our opening verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to the dust; give me life according to your word! When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes! Make me understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your wondrous works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:25-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context is one in need of rescue, clinging to the dust, despairing of life itself. When I told of my ways⸺when I gave an account to the Lord of my own ruined life, when I acknowledged before him my own complete and utter inadequacy⸺he answered me, and his answer is presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice in this answer! Rejoice in the God of your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these statutes? Why does my heart cry out to the Lord, teach me your statutes? Because the only possible response from the one who understands the magnitude of the rescue is this: to live a right life, a noble life, a life that honours the Lord in every way and in every thought and in every deed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the desire we see in the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Teach me your statutes! &amp;hellip;  Make me understand the way of your precepts &amp;hellip; Put false ways far from me
and graciously teach me your law! &amp;hellip; I set your rules before me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:26, 27, 29, 30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been rescued by the God of my salvation, the Creator of the Universe, and my life now belongs to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, praise the God of your salvation for this answer in Christ, and live for him alone! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The turning point</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/Fotos_del_Gran_Canaria_2010_PWA_Pozo_Izquierdo_Grand_Prix.Santa_Lucia.Gran_Canaria_%284778010692%29.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The turning point" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long does it take to get from clinging on in the dust despairing of life itself to running in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commandments having had one&amp;rsquo;s heart set free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the answer is seven verses. Seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to the dust; give me life according to your word! When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes! Make me understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your wondrous works. My soul melts away for sorrow; strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me and graciously teach me your law! I have chosen the way of faithfulness; I set your rules before me. I cling to your testimonies, O LORD; let me not be put to shame! I will run in the way of your commandments for you set my heart free!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:25-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth that last verse is in the future tense, and the mainline translation is “when you enlarge my heart”. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is going on here that leads to such a turnaround?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul melts away for sorrow. Do you know what that is like? To live with such vulnerability in that place right on the edge of crumpling into a heap and sobbing uncontrollably? The place of clinging on when all strength is gone? The place of crying out for life itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some heart-cries here for the Lord to act with compassion and great power: Give me life according to your word! Make me understand the way of your precepts! Strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me! But these in and of themselves are not the turning point. The turning point comes next and it is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have chosen the way of faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the turning point. In weakness and in sorrow, clinging on in the dust, with courage and determination the psalmist chooses the way of faithfulness. Everything follows from this. O my soul, choose the way of faithfulness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s be clear about whose faithfulness this is. Recall the Lord&amp;rsquo;s introduction of himself to Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses said to the LORD, “See, you say to me, ‘Bring up this people,’ but you have not let me know whom you will send with me. Yet you have said, ‘I know you by name, and you have also found favour in my sight.’ Now therefore, if I have found favour in your sight, please show me now your ways, that I may know you in order to find favour in your sight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:12-13, 18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Lord, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of faithfulness is the way of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness. So what does it mean to choose this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vindicate me, O LORD, for I have walked in my integrity, and I have trusted in the LORD without wavering. Prove me, O LORD, and try me; test my heart and my mind. For your steadfast love is before my eyes, and I walk in your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 26:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To choose the way of faithfulness and to walk in it is to trust in the Lord without wavering. It is to rely on him whatever else is happening, reminding oneself of his steadfast love. Prove me, O Lord, and try me. Know that I do not doubt you. I do not doubt your goodness and your mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what do you suppose is this proving? This trying? This testing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to see beyond current circumstances with eyes of faith, beyond current suffering, to assert with the psalmist out of the darkest valley, out of the deepest sorrow, out of the most wrenching pain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I know, O LORD, that your rules are righteous, and that in faithfulness you have afflicted me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:75&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to assert confidence in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness and to wait upon him, trusting and not doubting. Beyond the point of understanding, beyond the point of being able to see is where trust is tried, tested, and proven. And in this time of testing, this waiting time, it is to walk in one&amp;rsquo;s integrity, keeping covenant with the Holy One, surrendering all to him as an act of worship, perhaps in tears and bewilderment, but surrendering nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what must one do while walking in this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I set your rules before me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your heart is breaking, set his rules before you and walk in them, and know this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the paths of the LORD are steadfast love and faithfulness, for those who keep his covenant and his testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be sure to keep his covenant and his testimonies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now what about that future tense of the running?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will run in the way of your commandments when you enlarge my heart!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is breaking and I simply lack the capacity for this. How can I endure this waiting time? My strength is almost gone. But the Lord himself enlarges my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These sterile and barren bodies of ours are yearning for full deliverance. That is why waiting does not diminish us, any more than waiting diminishes a pregnant mother. We are enlarged in the waiting. We, of course, don’t see what is enlarging us. But the longer we wait, the larger we become, and the more joyful our expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:23-25 MSG&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will run, O my soul, I will! I will run in the way of his commandments, trusting and not doubting. I choose the way of faithfulness. I choose to trust the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, trust in the Lord with all your heart and choose the way of his steadfast love and faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>This is the day!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/robert-lukeman-_RBcxo9AU-U-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post This is the day!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do you expect change will come?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many years spent hoping and trusting, holding on to your promise from the Lord and yet still waiting, are you tempted to give up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you still somehow expect that the Lord will act with great power to fulfil that promise? And when exactly do you expect that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one answer which honours the Lord and that is today. You must continue to expect it and you must expect it today! It is imperative that you do so. Your very faith depends upon it. Your life and health and strength depend upon it. How else could you live a life that honours him, other than in complete trust and dependence upon him, and other than in expectation of the imminent outworking of his great power in your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who promised is indeed faithful. His very name is Faithful and True (Rev 19:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is it quite so important to hold fast to this hope, this expectation of imminent fulfilment, without wavering?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the midst of a spiritual battle and the fighting is fierce. To expect anything other than imminent fulfilment would open the door to doubt ⸺that doubt which is so ready to creep in and steal away hope and joy and expectation. That doubt which would cause all to unravel and expose the tattered remains of a faith which once was. That doubt which must be resisted with all strength. Be steadfast, O my soul! Cry out to the Faithful One, Lord I believe! Help my unbelief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Ahab sent to all the people of Israel and gathered the prophets together at Mount Carmel. And Elijah came near to all the people and said, “How long will you go limping between two different opinions? If the LORD is God, follow him; but if Baal, then follow him.” And the people did not answer him a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they took the bull that was given them, and they prepared it and called upon the name of Baal from morning until noon, saying, “O Baal, answer us!” But there was no voice, and no one answered. And they limped around the altar that they had made. And at noon Elijah mocked them, saying, “Cry aloud, for he is a god. Either he is musing, or he is relieving himself, or he is on a journey, or perhaps he is asleep and must be awakened.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:20-21, 26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you tempted to such thoughts while you wait on the living God, the God of your life? Repudiate them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And at the time of the offering of the oblation, Elijah the prophet came near and said, “O LORD, God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let it be known this day that you are God in Israel, and that I am your servant, and that I have done all these things at your word. Answer me, O LORD, answer me, that this people may know that you, O LORD, are God, and that you have turned their hearts back.” Then the fire of the LORD fell and consumed the burnt offering and the wood and the stones and the dust, and licked up the water that was in the trench. And when all the people saw it, they fell on their faces and said, “The LORD, he is God; the LORD, he is God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:36-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord, he is God! Praise him, O my soul!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s answer to our most earnest praying, the outworking of his mighty strength in our lives to fulfil all that he has promised, is that all may know that the Lord, he is God! And his grace and kindness is that you, O my soul, may know it. Expect it today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our experience of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power being outworked in our lives is limited only by our faith to believe it, our faith to receive it. This is why it is quite so important that we do not hold back in expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And as Jesus passed on from there, two blind men followed him, crying aloud, “Have mercy on us, Son of David.” When he entered the house, the blind men came to him, and Jesus said to them, “Do you believe that I am able to do this?” They said to him, “Yes, Lord.” Then he touched their eyes, saying, “According to your faith be it done to you.” And their eyes were opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 9:27-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you believe that he is able to do this? According to your faith be it done to you. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s yet more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him. Whoever believes in him is not condemned, but whoever does not believe is condemned already, because he has not believed in the name of the only Son of God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you dare to believe, O my soul, of the only Son of God. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the day that the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the day, O my soul! Expect great things in it! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hope in God</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/jeremy-bishop-DLICfSD33as-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hope in God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you downcast?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your life not as it once was? Are you grieving for things that once were and are no longer?  So was the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These things I remember, as I pour out my soul: how I would go with the throng and lead them in procession to the house of God with glad shouts and songs of praise, a multitude keeping festival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a man who used to live a life of affirmation and exaltation. But things changed and he became a pariah, even in his own church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As with a deadly wound in my bones, my adversaries taunt me, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, O my soul, does the Lord seem to have withdrawn? Are you no longer enjoying that intimacy, the sweetness of his felt presence in your life? Nor was the psalmist. But the desire for that had not left him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul thirsts for God, for the living God. When shall I come and appear before God? My tears have been my food day and night, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multitude keeping festival, those privileged and self-satisfied ones, had closed ranks, and he was no longer among them. And it seemed to him that God himself had passed him by, forgotten him, rejected him. He was oppressed, scorned, and despised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any hope? Is anything to be done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why are you cast down, O my soul, and why are you in turmoil within me? Hope in God; for I shall again praise him, my salvation and my God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:5-6, also v11 and Psalm 43:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you cast down, O my soul? This is not a question in search of an answer. This is a rebuke. It is a rebuke delivered to one who has taken their eyes off the Lord, and has become overwhelmed by their own difficulties and disappointments, defeated by them and yet dwelling in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in God, O my soul! Hope in the only one in whom you really can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul does indeed thirst for God. But where is hope?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By day the LORD commands his steadfast love, and at night his song is with me, a prayer to the God of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His love is steadfast. All his paths are steadfast love and faithfulness (Psalm 25:10). And he is the God of my life⸺the God of my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is not ignorant of nor indifferent to what is happening in my life. He has plans and purposes for me that are beyond my understanding. He is ambitious for me in ways that would blow my mind if I only knew. He is transforming me into the likeness of Christ, and he knows how to do it, O how he knows! He is the God of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What must I do then? I must trust. I must trust the God of my life, who knows his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is this song that is with me through the night, when tears are my only food? The psalmist knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is my strength and my song; he has become my salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Behold, God is my salvation; I will trust, and will not be afraid; for the LORD GOD is my strength and my song, and he has become my salvation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these are borrowed words. They are Moses&amp;rsquo; words. This is Moses&amp;rsquo; song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is my strength and my song, and he has become my salvation; this is my God, and I will praise him, my father&amp;rsquo;s God, and I will exalt him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 15:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is the context of Moses&amp;rsquo; song?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Moses stretched out his hand over the sea, and the LORD drove the sea back by a strong east wind all night and made the sea dry land, and the waters were divided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the LORD saved Israel that day from the hand of the Egyptians, and Israel saw the Egyptians dead on the seashore. Israel saw the great power that the LORD used against the Egyptians, so the people feared the LORD, and they believed in the LORD and in his servant Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 14:21, 30-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song must be the refrain of your life: the habit of remembering who the Lord is and what he has done. It is the habit of remembering as you do the dishes, as you drive to work, as you grapple with the challenges of life. It is the habit of remembering the God of your life and the great power that he uses to rescue those he loves. Dwell in that, my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not underestimate the discipline and determination required to sing this song, to make it the habit of your life, but this you must do, single-mindedly, doggedly, courageously.  It is a matter of life and death. Take your eyes off yourself, look to the Lord and hope in him.  There is no other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in the Lord, O my soul, for there is no other! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
