<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>waiting on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/waiting/</link>
        <description>Recent content in waiting on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/waiting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Light up my eyes</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/imran-ali-HV9dUe3H5z8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Light up my eyes" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you discouraged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the heart-cry of the psalmist and know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever? How long will you hide your face from me? How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day? How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long must I take counsel in my soul? Discouragement is such a lonely place in which to be⸺after all, who wants to share their discouragement with another? So, lonely but not alone in that loneliness. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that the affliction of our age?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be done about this? And for how long must it be endured?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that I wrestled with that second question for Amy. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How long O Lord is truly the most unanswered question&lt;/a&gt;, although for good reasons. Recall those reasons and hold on to them in your discouragement and dismay for they will help you to endure. But what is endurance without deliverance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discouragement must be dealt with before it becomes despondency and then depression and then the sleep of death. So what can deliver us from this? Precisely: &lt;em&gt;O LORD my God, light up my eyes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light up my eyes! This is what is needed. O my soul, this is what you need. There is wisdom in the proverb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The light of the eyes rejoices the heart, and good news refreshes the bones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus explained why this is so vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The eye is the lamp of the body. So, if your eye is healthy, your whole body will be full of light, but if your eye is bad, your whole body will be full of darkness. If then the light in you is darkness, how great is the darkness!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eye is the means by which that light enters the body, because this is how we perceive, or choose to perceive, the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more than one cause for that light to be lost. Firstly, sin. Do not underestimate the consequences to your spiritual wellbeing of persisting in sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no soundness in my flesh because of your indignation; there is no health in my bones because of my sin. For my iniquities have gone over my head; like a heavy burden, they are too heavy for me. My wounds stink and fester because of my foolishness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart throbs; my strength fails me, and the light of my eyes⸺it also has gone from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 38:3-5, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, let this not be the cause of your discouragement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now that you have been set free from sin and have become slaves of God, the fruit you get leads to sanctification and its end, eternal life. For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, grief could be the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be gracious to me, O LORD, for I am in distress;
my eye is wasted from grief; my soul and my body also. For my life is spent with sorrow, and my years with sighing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:9-10a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various reasons to grieve but each one is a heartbreaking loss of something or someone. As you grieve know that you are not alone in that. Jesus also grieves and he grieves with you. Recall Martha and Mary&amp;rsquo;s dear brother Lazarus and the sisters&amp;rsquo; bewilderment and dismay that Jesus hadn&amp;rsquo;t saved him, at least at this point in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now when Mary came to where Jesus was and saw him, she fell at his feet, saying to him, “Lord, if you had been here, my brother would not have died.” When Jesus saw her weeping, and the Jews who had come with her also weeping, he was deeply moved in his spirit and greatly troubled. And he said, “Where have you laid him?” They said to him, “Lord, come and see.” Jesus wept. So the Jews said, “See how he loved him!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 11:32-36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus wept with Mary, and O my soul, know that he weeps also with you. But even in your grief beware lest sin creep in, as the psalmist continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My strength fails because of my iniquity, and my bones waste away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your weakness and vulnerability you must be ever vigilant against sin creeping in. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace and with the power of the Holy Spirit you simply must continue in personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But irrespective of the cause of discouragement, we must ask what is the source of this light for the eyes, if we are to be encouraged, to be lifted up from our grief, to be freed from sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proverb tells more than it knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The light of the eyes rejoices the heart, and good news refreshes the bones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this good news? It is the ultimate good news, the Gospel of Jesus Christ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Again Jesus spoke to them, saying, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will not walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people who walked in darkness have seen a great light; those who dwelt in a land of deep darkness, on them has light shone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For to us a child is born, to us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder, and his name shall be called Wonderful Counsellor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, Prince of Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 9:2, 6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so with this we can finally arrive at the psalmist&amp;rsquo;s destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have trusted in your steadfast love; my heart shall rejoice in your salvation. I will sing to the LORD, because he has dealt bountifully with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has indeed dealt bountifully with each one. Trust in his steadfast love and rejoice in your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, may Jesus himself light up your eyes with grace and truth and love, and may the light of his life shine on you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blessed in the waiting</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/49820769116_8868b8d012_o.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blessed in the waiting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the hardest thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, what is the hardest thing to endure?  That which leads you to think you have been forgotten by the Lord and he has withdrawn himself? That which is the loneliest path to walk? That which keeps you in sorrow throughout the day? That which makes you cry out with that most earnest and desperate question, how long, O Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it not waiting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever? How long will you hide your face from me? How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day? How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does not that waiting time seem like death or defeat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death, lest my enemy say, “I have prevailed over him,” lest my foes rejoice because I am shaken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That waiting time can be unspeakably awful, seemingly almost too hard to bear. And isn&amp;rsquo;t it all such a terrible waste of time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to notice something. O my soul, you must notice quite how much waiting is done by those in whom and through whom the Lord does great works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses waited for forty years. In the wilderness. Tending sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph waited for more than ten. In prison. Apparently forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus himself waited thirty years. In obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be that somehow the waiting time is when the Lord does his most important work of preparation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what happened at the end of Moses&amp;rsquo; waiting time, his forty years in the wilderness of Midian, that apparently wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, and I have come down to deliver them out of the hand of the Egyptians and to bring them up out of that land to a good and broad land, a land flowing with milk and honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Come, I will send you to Pharaoh that you may bring my people, the children of Israel, out of Egypt.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:7-8, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally Moses was ready to be used by the Lord for this great task. How do we know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But Moses said to God, “Who am I that I should go to Pharaoh and bring the children of Israel out of Egypt?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses had become nothing. He had died to self. It had taken forty years, because there had previously been so much pride in his heart. He had previously been so full of Moses, so pleased with himself. And now he regarded himself as nothing at all. But he wasn&amp;rsquo;t. He was finally ready to be used greatly by the Lord. And he was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Joseph? After more than ten years in prison, he had to wait yet another seven before the Lord used him to rescue the people of Israel from famine in the land of Canaan. What was his testimony then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before the year of famine came, two sons were born to Joseph. Asenath, the daughter of Potiphera priest of On, bore them to him. Joseph called the name of the firstborn Manasseh. “For,” he said, “God has made me forget all my hardship and all my father&amp;rsquo;s house.” The name of the second he called Ephraim, “For God has made me fruitful in the land of my affliction.”⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 41:50-52&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, praise the Lord for his faithfulness to Joseph, and rest in that same faithfulness. He knows precisely what he is doing, and all his paths are steadfast love and faithfulness. He takes the years that are required, and those years are not wasted. Rather they are the time of preparation and meticulous restoration and transforming grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know how a diamond is formed? Under intense pressure and heat and a billion years of waiting. Are those wasted years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jesus? Even as a twelve year old he displayed such understanding. Do you not think he would have wanted to heal the sick and the brokenhearted and rescue the lost when he was seventeen? When he was twenty-three? When he was twenty-eight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own waiting time know that Jesus understands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since then we have a great high priest who has passed through the heavens, Jesus, the Son of God, let us hold fast our confession. For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but one who in every respect has been tempted as we are, yet without sin. Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 4:14-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the greatest temptation in the waiting time? Is it not to doubt the goodness and faithfulness and sufficiency of God? Repent of those doubts and trust the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did you notice that question which was asked four times by the psalmist and still not answered? How long O Lord? How long? This is the most unanswered question, and painfully so. But what is the psalmist really asking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not really an answer to his question that the psalmist is seeking. It is the answer which is the presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notice too how this answer is received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have trusted in your steadfast love; my heart shall rejoice in your salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own waiting time you must trust in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love. And here is trust. It is to assert and to dwell in the wisdom and kindness and faithfulness and sufficiency of the Lord &lt;em&gt;right in the middle of that painful longing&lt;/em&gt;. Right there in the middle of the waiting is the only opportunity to trust. So do that, and rejoice in his salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will sing to the LORD, because he has dealt bountifully with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, sing to the Lord, because he has already dealt bountifully with you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
