<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>waiting on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/waiting/</link>
        <description>Recent content in waiting on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/waiting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>When God does not act</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/when-god-does-not-act/neom-GoLWB4p8JXw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post When God does not act" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will you do when God does not act?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that I say when and not if. I say when because he has already not acted, hasn&amp;rsquo;t he? O my soul, you are so very familiar with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/unanswered-prayer/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the silence of the unanswered prayer&lt;/a&gt; and the emptiness of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s inaction. I know you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is your way not already fully committed? You know that it is! Do you not already trust him utterly and completely? You know that you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did he then act? No he did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of these words of Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened. Or which one of you, if his son asks him for bread, will give him a stone? Or if he asks for a fish, will give him a serpent? If you then, who are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father who is in heaven give good things to those who ask him!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you not asked? Yes of course you have, and many times. Has it then been given to you? No it has not. Have you received? No you have not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of Jesus&amp;rsquo; summing up of his parable of the persistent widow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the Lord said, “Hear what the unrighteous judge says. And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? I tell you, he will give justice to them speedily.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:6-8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you cry out to God day and night? Yes you did. And did you then receive this justice? And speedily? No you did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or these words that Jesus spoke to his disciples in the upper room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Truly, truly, I say to you, whoever believes in me will also do the works that I do; and greater works than these will he do, because I am going to the Father. Whatever you ask in my name, this I will do, that the Father may be glorified in the Son. If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you not already ask in his name, understanding full well the requirement to put aside self-interest and pray the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own heart? Yes, you did, in faith and humility and complete confidence in him. And did he do it? No he did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about what he said after cursing that fig tree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the disciples saw it, they marvelled, saying, “How did the fig tree wither at once?” And Jesus answered them, “Truly, I say to you, if you have faith and do not doubt, you will not only do what has been done to the fig tree, but even if you say to this mountain, ‘Be taken up and thrown into the sea,’ it will happen. And whatever you ask in prayer, you will receive, if you have faith.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 21:20-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you have faith? I know you do. And having cast yourself upon the Lord so completely, having trusted him with your very life, having believed and not doubted, having grown into possessing a faith that could so nearly move that mountain, where does that leave you in relation to these firm assurances? These trustworthy promises? From the one whose name is Faithful and True?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For isn&amp;rsquo;t the stark reality that the Lord has not in fact acted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you give up hoping? Will you give up trusting? Will you give up waiting? Will you give up believing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or will you continue in your walk of faith and hope and trust in the Lord? Which you choose is a matter of life and death. O my soul, make no mistake here. Your very life depends upon it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must cry out with Job,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Though he slay me, I will hope in him; yet I will argue my ways to his face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 13:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must hope in him, for there is no other. But argue your ways to his face. You must do this. He can take it. Are the psalms not full of it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the silence and the emptiness and the bewilderment and the heartbreak perhaps you have two questions for the Lord. Cry out to God with these two questions: Why? And how long?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But know that the question of why is confronted head on by the Lord&amp;rsquo;s rebuke of Job. A rebuke that came after a prolonged period of suffering. A prolonged period of waiting. A prolonged period of dismay and bewilderment. The rebuke came throughout Job chapters 38-42 and could be summarised like this: “I am the LORD Most High, Creator of Heaven and Earth. And who are you exactly?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not think that you are owed any explanation for you are not. You are a grasshopper before the Lord of Hosts. Surrender that spirit of entitlement that demands you understand why. For you do not and you cannot know these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless even though he was denied his explanation of why, Job was commended for pleading his case before the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After the LORD had spoken these words to Job, the LORD said to Eliphaz the Temanite: “My anger burns against you and against your two friends, for you have not spoken of me what is right, as my servant Job has.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must continue to argue your ways to the Lord, to his face. You must!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notwithstanding the absence of any real explanation we may know that a profound work is taking place. Is this not precisely what is revealed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this you rejoice, though now for a little while, if necessary, you have been grieved by various trials, so that the tested genuineness of your faith⸺more precious than gold that perishes though it is tested by fire⸺may be found to result in praise and glory and honour at the revelation of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time of silence and emptiness is a trial like no other. You must pass this test. Your faith is more precious than gold. Nurture that faith!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And recall how Jesus ended his summing up of his parable of the persistent widow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, when the Son of Man comes, will he find faith on earth?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:8b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, will he find faith in your own heart, faith more precious than gold? If he does know that there will be praise and honour and glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second question was Habakkuk&amp;rsquo;s own heart-cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O LORD, how long shall I cry for help, and you will not hear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long, O Lord? We have &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;asked this before&lt;/a&gt;. And as before we may rejoice in the answer spoken to Habakkuk by the Lord, the everlasting God, the Holy One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days that you would not believe if told.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be assured that the Lord is indeed doing a great work, a wondrous work, a mighty work which cannot be told. It is a work of faithfulness and power. It is a good and kind work. It is a healing work. It is a work of deliverance and the fulfillment of promises. It is such a work that you would not believe if told!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will you do? You must do as Abraham was commanded, after his own waiting time of twenty-four years. Twenty-four years of waiting on the Lord for the fulfilment of that impossible promise. Twenty-four years of bewilderment. A time during which he had wrestled and struggled and stumbled badly. Perhaps you too have stumbled. But nevertheless,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must walk before the Lord and be blameless. The integrity with which you live your life is of the utmost importance. In this bewildering time of waiting, your own personal holiness will be life and health and strength both for you and for others. To walk before the Lord means to live in his presence, in the context of his goodness and kindness and faithfulness and all that he has promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, hold on to hope and trust in the Lord, walk before him and be blameless! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Open your own eyes</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/ben-white-EMZxDosijJ4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Open your own eyes" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you desire that the Lord light up your eyes, what are you doing about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you surprised that I ask what you are doing, as if it could make any difference? Whether the Lord chooses to light up your eyes is entirely out of your hands isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen again to the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The law of the LORD is perfect, reviving the soul; the testimony of the LORD is sure, making wise the simple; the precepts of the LORD are right, rejoicing the heart; the commandment of the LORD is pure, enlightening the eyes; the fear of the LORD is clean, enduring forever; the rules of the LORD are true, and righteous altogether. More to be desired are they than gold, even much fine gold; sweeter also than honey and drippings of the honeycomb. Moreover, by them is your servant warned; in keeping them there is great reward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 19:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by noticing the pure commandment of the Lord which enlightens the eyes. But we must ingest the whole of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you desire the rules of the Lord? Do you know their sweetness? Do you know that great reward which is keeping them? Do you desire to be revived? Are you feeding and watering that desire that it may flourish, and you with it? Do you even know how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is telling it, over and over. The law of the Lord is perfect. The testimony of the Lord is sure. The precepts of the Lord are right. The commandment of the Lord is pure. These revive the soul, make wise the simple, rejoice the heart, and enlighten the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my question to you is, have you immersed yourself in these and do you continue to do so? Do you begin each new day by plunging into the word of God, his law, his testimony, his precepts, and his commandments? And if not, why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is joy here in the face of a demoralising and depressing world. There is power here in the face of the overwhelming and apparently insoluble problems of the world⸺oppression, self-interest, corruption, exploitation, hatred, and war. In such contrast to the world&amp;rsquo;s murkiness and moral ambiguity, the commandment of the Lord is pure and it enlightens the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, steep yourself in the word of God, each morning and throughout the day. Wrap yourself in it and walk in it, with rejoicing and a grateful heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you have been waiting for deliverance now for so long you have started to think there is nothing else you can do. O my soul, you must not wallow in your waiting, as if there is nothing to be done. That could not be further from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your waiting, as days become weeks and weeks become months and with each passing year, are you growing in your desire for the Lord? Are you growing in faith? Are you growing in love and holiness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, this year is so very rapidly approaching its end. Ask yourself, does my heart desire the Lord more so now than at its beginning? Is my faith stronger and more resilient? Have I grown in love and holiness? If not, it has surely been a waste of a year. Do not be so negligent as to waste the next one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your own longing for change listen to the longing of the psalmist. It is above all a longing for personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are those whose way is blameless,
who walk in the law of the LORD! Blessed are those who keep his testimonies, who seek him with their whole heart, who also do no wrong, but walk in his ways! You have commanded your precepts to be kept diligently. Oh that my ways may be steadfast in keeping your statutes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is both longing and determination here, and also realism, for doesn&amp;rsquo;t this task seem to be utterly beyond us? But it is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your testimonies are wonderful; therefore my soul keeps them. The unfolding of your words gives light; it imparts understanding to the simple. I open my mouth and pant, because I long for your commandments. Turn to me and be gracious to me, as is your way with those who love your name. Keep steady my steps according to your promise, and let no iniquity get dominion over me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:129-133&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, you must be diligent to let no iniquity get dominion over you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three more things that remain to be done, and these can be learnt from the Apostle Paul in just half a sentence. The whole sentence is simply too overwhelming to take in at one go, because this is Paul! He has just been describing our glorious inheritance in Christ and the guarantee we have in the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this reason, because I have heard of your faith in the Lord Jesus and your love toward all the saints, I do not cease to give thanks for you, remembering you in my prayers, that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of him, having the eyes of your hearts enlightened &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:15-18a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these three things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is to exercise faith in the Lord Jesus, so it may grow. Are you waiting on an impossible promise from the Lord? Then keep on waiting, believing and not doubting, and he will light up your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is to pray. This is Paul&amp;rsquo;s prayer for the saints in Ephesus. Make it your own and not only yours. Pray for the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of the Lord to light up the eyes of your heart, those eyes of faith, which must shine in expectation and reflected glory. And pray this also for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third is to love. Do not hold back from loving all the saints. The saints are simply the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people, although some are not yet so very saintly to be sure, being still in the early stages of sanctification and humility. But you must love, and you must not overlook that little word &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt;. If you desire that the Lord light up your eyes, then you must love all the saints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desiring the law of the Lord and his testimonies and his precepts and his commandments and his rules is ultimately an outworking of love itself, our love for the Lord in response to his own great love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you starting to understand how to put yourself in the place of the Lord lighting up your eyes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, love the Lord and do not hold back! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Light up my eyes</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/light-up-my-eyes/imran-ali-HV9dUe3H5z8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Light up my eyes" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you discouraged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the heart-cry of the psalmist and know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever? How long will you hide your face from me? How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day? How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long must I take counsel in my soul? Discouragement is such a lonely place in which to be⸺after all, who wants to share their discouragement with another? So, lonely but not alone in that loneliness. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that the affliction of our age?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be done about this? And for how long must it be endured?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that I wrestled with that second question for Amy. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-long-o-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How long O Lord is truly the most unanswered question&lt;/a&gt;, although for good reasons. Recall those reasons and hold on to them in your discouragement and dismay for they will help you to endure. But what is endurance without deliverance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discouragement must be dealt with before it becomes despondency and then depression and then the sleep of death. So what can deliver us from this? Precisely: &lt;em&gt;O LORD my God, light up my eyes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light up my eyes! This is what is needed. O my soul, this is what you need. There is wisdom in the proverb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The light of the eyes rejoices the heart, and good news refreshes the bones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus explained why this is so vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The eye is the lamp of the body. So, if your eye is healthy, your whole body will be full of light, but if your eye is bad, your whole body will be full of darkness. If then the light in you is darkness, how great is the darkness!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eye is the means by which that light enters the body, because this is how we perceive, or choose to perceive, the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more than one cause for that light to be lost. Firstly, sin. Do not underestimate the consequences to your spiritual wellbeing of persisting in sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no soundness in my flesh because of your indignation; there is no health in my bones because of my sin. For my iniquities have gone over my head; like a heavy burden, they are too heavy for me. My wounds stink and fester because of my foolishness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart throbs; my strength fails me, and the light of my eyes⸺it also has gone from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 38:3-5, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, let this not be the cause of your discouragement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now that you have been set free from sin and have become slaves of God, the fruit you get leads to sanctification and its end, eternal life. For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, grief could be the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be gracious to me, O LORD, for I am in distress;
my eye is wasted from grief; my soul and my body also. For my life is spent with sorrow, and my years with sighing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:9-10a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various reasons to grieve but each one is a heartbreaking loss of something or someone. As you grieve know that you are not alone in that. Jesus also grieves and he grieves with you. Recall Martha and Mary&amp;rsquo;s dear brother Lazarus and the sisters&amp;rsquo; bewilderment and dismay that Jesus hadn&amp;rsquo;t saved him, at least at this point in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now when Mary came to where Jesus was and saw him, she fell at his feet, saying to him, “Lord, if you had been here, my brother would not have died.” When Jesus saw her weeping, and the Jews who had come with her also weeping, he was deeply moved in his spirit and greatly troubled. And he said, “Where have you laid him?” They said to him, “Lord, come and see.” Jesus wept. So the Jews said, “See how he loved him!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 11:32-36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus wept with Mary, and O my soul, know that he weeps also with you. But even in your grief beware lest sin creep in, as the psalmist continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My strength fails because of my iniquity, and my bones waste away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your weakness and vulnerability you must be ever vigilant against sin creeping in. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace and with the power of the Holy Spirit you simply must continue in personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But irrespective of the cause of discouragement, we must ask what is the source of this light for the eyes, if we are to be encouraged, to be lifted up from our grief, to be freed from sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proverb tells more than it knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The light of the eyes rejoices the heart, and good news refreshes the bones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this good news? It is the ultimate good news, the Gospel of Jesus Christ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Again Jesus spoke to them, saying, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will not walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people who walked in darkness have seen a great light; those who dwelt in a land of deep darkness, on them has light shone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For to us a child is born, to us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder, and his name shall be called Wonderful Counsellor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, Prince of Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 9:2, 6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so with this we can finally arrive at the psalmist&amp;rsquo;s destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have trusted in your steadfast love; my heart shall rejoice in your salvation. I will sing to the LORD, because he has dealt bountifully with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has indeed dealt bountifully with each one. Trust in his steadfast love and rejoice in your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, may Jesus himself light up your eyes with grace and truth and love, and may the light of his life shine on you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blessed in the waiting</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/49820769116_8868b8d012_o.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blessed in the waiting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the hardest thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, what is the hardest thing to endure?  That which leads you to think you have been forgotten by the Lord and he has withdrawn himself? That which is the loneliest path to walk? That which keeps you in sorrow throughout the day? That which makes you cry out with that most earnest and desperate question, how long, O Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it not waiting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever? How long will you hide your face from me? How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day? How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does not that waiting time seem like death or defeat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death, lest my enemy say, “I have prevailed over him,” lest my foes rejoice because I am shaken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That waiting time can be unspeakably awful, seemingly almost too hard to bear. And isn&amp;rsquo;t it all such a terrible waste of time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to notice something. O my soul, you must notice quite how much waiting is done by those in whom and through whom the Lord does great works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses waited for forty years. In the wilderness. Tending sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph waited for more than ten. In prison. Apparently forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus himself waited thirty years. In obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be that somehow the waiting time is when the Lord does his most important work of preparation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what happened at the end of Moses&amp;rsquo; waiting time, his forty years in the wilderness of Midian, that apparently wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, and I have come down to deliver them out of the hand of the Egyptians and to bring them up out of that land to a good and broad land, a land flowing with milk and honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Come, I will send you to Pharaoh that you may bring my people, the children of Israel, out of Egypt.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:7-8, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally Moses was ready to be used by the Lord for this great task. How do we know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But Moses said to God, “Who am I that I should go to Pharaoh and bring the children of Israel out of Egypt?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses had become nothing. He had died to self. It had taken forty years, because there had previously been so much pride in his heart. He had previously been so full of Moses, so pleased with himself. And now he regarded himself as nothing at all. But he wasn&amp;rsquo;t. He was finally ready to be used greatly by the Lord. And he was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Joseph? After more than ten years in prison, he had to wait yet another seven before the Lord used him to rescue the people of Israel from famine in the land of Canaan. What was his testimony then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before the year of famine came, two sons were born to Joseph. Asenath, the daughter of Potiphera priest of On, bore them to him. Joseph called the name of the firstborn Manasseh. “For,” he said, “God has made me forget all my hardship and all my father&amp;rsquo;s house.” The name of the second he called Ephraim, “For God has made me fruitful in the land of my affliction.”⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 41:50-52&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, praise the Lord for his faithfulness to Joseph, and rest in that same faithfulness. He knows precisely what he is doing, and all his paths are steadfast love and faithfulness. He takes the years that are required, and those years are not wasted. Rather they are the time of preparation and meticulous restoration and transforming grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know how a diamond is formed? Under intense pressure and heat and a billion years of waiting. Are those wasted years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jesus? Even as a twelve year old he displayed such understanding. Do you not think he would have wanted to heal the sick and the brokenhearted and rescue the lost when he was seventeen? When he was twenty-three? When he was twenty-eight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own waiting time know that Jesus understands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since then we have a great high priest who has passed through the heavens, Jesus, the Son of God, let us hold fast our confession. For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but one who in every respect has been tempted as we are, yet without sin. Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 4:14-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the greatest temptation in the waiting time? Is it not to doubt the goodness and faithfulness and sufficiency of God? Repent of those doubts and trust the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did you notice that question which was asked four times by the psalmist and still not answered? How long O Lord? How long? This is the most unanswered question, and painfully so. But what is the psalmist really asking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not really an answer to his question that the psalmist is seeking. It is the answer which is the presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notice too how this answer is received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have trusted in your steadfast love; my heart shall rejoice in your salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own waiting time you must trust in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love. And here is trust. It is to assert and to dwell in the wisdom and kindness and faithfulness and sufficiency of the Lord &lt;em&gt;right in the middle of that painful longing&lt;/em&gt;. Right there in the middle of the waiting is the only opportunity to trust. So do that, and rejoice in his salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will sing to the LORD, because he has dealt bountifully with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, sing to the Lord, because he has already dealt bountifully with you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
