<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>holiness on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/holiness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in holiness on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/holiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The open door</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/chris-meads-VDHn0YmjIw4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The open door" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does an open door constitute a reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia write: ‘The words of the holy one, the true one, who has the key of David, who opens and no one will shut, who shuts and no one opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works. Behold, I have set before you an open door, which no one is able to shut.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:7-8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the seven churches only Smyrna was able to join with Philadelphia in being commended by Jesus without reservation. Jesus knew their works. What a joy it must have been for him to commend their faithfulness and to richly reward them. So let&amp;rsquo;s consider the reward of that open door. And let&amp;rsquo;s start by asking, how does that even constitute a reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t an open door simply an opportunity presenting itself? Indeed Paul uses exactly this metaphor on several occasions. Here are two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I will stay in Ephesus until Pentecost, for a wide door for effective work has opened to me, and there are many adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 16:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving. At the same time, pray also for us, that God may open to us a door for the word, to declare the mystery of Christ, on account of which I am in prison⸺that I may make it clear, which is how I ought to speak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 4:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly the opportunity here was not presenting itself but rather was being presented as a sovereign work of the Lord. Paul was most concerned about the open door for declaring the mystery of Christ, that he may make it clear⸺of course he was. But I am not persuaded that this was the nature of the reward for the Philadelphians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Jesus&amp;rsquo; next letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is not knocking on the Philadelphian door because it is already open and he is right there among them. This is the door to heaven itself, just as John&amp;rsquo;s vision continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After this I looked, and behold, a door standing open in heaven! And the first voice, which I had heard speaking to me like a trumpet, said, “Come up here, and I will show you what must take place after this.” At once I was in the Spirit, and behold, a throne stood in heaven, with one seated on the throne. And he who sat there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian, and around the throne was a rainbow that had the appearance of an emerald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a door this is! And it is wide open and cannot be shut. What a reward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In passing we must enjoy to notice John&amp;rsquo;s ludicrous attempt to describe the indescribable, the one seated on the throne. He who was seated there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian. Really? Is that the best he could have done? It tells us nothing. Except of course of the ineffability of the Creator God of the Universe, reigning and ruling in majesty and splendour. Praise his holy name! And praise his indescribable being!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we continue to think about that door, let&amp;rsquo;s consider what was being rewarded, for it seems to be so very little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that you have but little power, and yet you have kept my word and have not denied my name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you have kept my word about patient endurance &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:8b, 10a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s the entirety of it! But make no mistake, this is not so very little at all. We need to understand what this means, to keep Jesus&amp;rsquo; word and not to deny his name. It is in fact about absolute trust and complete surrender and living an uncompromised life which is fully consistent and perfectly aligned with Jesus being Lord of all. And it is about that personal holiness which is an ongoing act of worship to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; name is his character. It is who he is. So what would deny his name? Would it not be anxiety or doubt or inconsistency or pretence or pride or holding anything back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you understand the magnitude of what was being commended? Marvel at it, and now go and do likewise! And if you think you simply lack the strength to live like this, observe that the Philadelphians also had but little power. The power to live like this is all the Lord&amp;rsquo;s and it is his gift of grace. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But back to this open door. Jesus tells us a bit more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So Jesus again said to them, “Truly, truly, I say to you, I am the door of the sheep. All who came before me are thieves and robbers, but the sheep did not listen to them. I am the door. If anyone enters by me, he will be saved and will go in and out and find pasture. The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the door, and he is the door to life itself. Jesus came that we may have life and have it abundantly. O my soul, are you starting to understand the magnitude of the Philadelphian reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is something else which must not be overlooked. What does Jesus say of those who have not lived this pure and holy and surrendered life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and they will learn that I have loved you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:9b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, have you learnt this? Have you learnt that the King of the Universe has loved you with an everlasting love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, do not overlook that the abundant life is this life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 3:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, live like those Philadelphians, and receive from Jesus the reward of that open door! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Repent!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/repent/cj-botha-PTztNC4yKY0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Repent!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent call to repent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This call to repent went out long ago to the church in Thyatira and it remains today. But let&amp;rsquo;s first marvel at Jesus&amp;rsquo; generous assessment of that church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Thyatira write: ‘The words of the Son of God, who has eyes like a flame of fire, and whose feet are like burnished bronze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works, your love and faith and service and patient endurance, and that your latter works exceed the first.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the church in Thyatira were these commended by Jesus for their love and faith and service and patient endurance. O my soul, how are your own love and faith and service and patient endurance? Jesus knows! His eyes are like a flame of fire and nothing is hidden from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did you notice the generosity in his assessment? Their latter works exceeded the first⸺some were slow starters. Jesus did not dwell on what came before. He commended them for how they were now. O my soul, leave the past behind! Jesus does not dwell on what came before and nor must you. Know that he is generous in his assessment also of you, desiring for you only what is good. He loves you and is committed to you and demands reciprocity in these. Rejoice that it is so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was not all good news in Thyatira.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have this against you, that you tolerate that woman Jezebel, who calls herself a prophetess and is teaching and seducing my servants to practice sexual immorality and to eat food sacrificed to idols. I gave her time to repent, but she refuses to repent of her sexual immorality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we come specifically to the seduction and the sexual immorality, let&amp;rsquo;s notice something significant here⸺a similarity and a difference with what we read in Jesus&amp;rsquo; letter to the church in Ephesus. Here we have a woman calling herself a prophetess and leading the church astray. In the church in Ephesus there were false apostles also leading the church astray. If that is the similarity what is the difference? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it that she was given time to repent and they were not? Recall that there was no call to repentance for those false apostles in Ephesus. They were simply excluded by Jesus and rejected. Tremble at that judgment and that rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now our instinct may be to characterise Jezebel&amp;rsquo;s sin as utterly heinous, far worse than what was happening in Ephesus, but pause to consider that Jesus did in fact give her that time to repent. This is not something we can understand in its entirety but surely warns us off ranking sins and ranking sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those she was leading astray?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I will throw her onto a sickbed, and those who commit adultery with her I will throw into great tribulation, unless they repent of her works, and I will strike her children dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:22-23a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repent! O my soul, notice the urgency to repent. Jesus came to break the chains of bondage to sin and death and to give life in all its abundance, and repentance and faith are the means to receive this precious and lavish gift. But her children, her spiritual offspring who refuse this gift will be struck dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is this death? Is it not that final, second death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. The one who conquers will not be hurt by the second death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then of the specifics of the sin⸺sexual immorality and eating of food sacrificed to idols. Of the former we can say one thing immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you not know that your bodies are members of Christ? Shall I then take the members of Christ and make them members of a prostitute? Never!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flee from sexual immorality. Every other sin a person commits is outside the body, but the sexually immoral person sins against his own body. Or do you not know that your body is a temple of the Holy Spirit within you, whom you have from God? You are not your own, for you were bought with a price. So glorify God in your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 6:15, 18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How different this is from how our own world views such things. Sexual immorality deeply grieves the Lord, for it is a corruption and a debasement of his wonderful gift to those he made in his own image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is something wider going on here. The pagan worship of the day was centred around ritual sexual acts with temple prostitutes and eating of food sacrificed to idols, and this had come in to the church. How this dishonoured the Lord! It was the worldliness of the day invading his church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of worldliness invading the church in our own time? How this dishonours the Lord! And lest you be thinking that what was being rebuked in Thyatira was merely outward behaviour, think again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And all the churches will know that I am he who searches mind and heart, and I will give to each of you according to your works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:23b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the one who searches mind and heart. Mind and heart are where the Lord is first honoured or dishonoured. As Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What comes out of a person is what defiles him. For from within, out of the heart of man, come evil thoughts, sexual immorality, theft, murder, adultery, coveting, wickedness, deceit, sensuality, envy, slander, pride, foolishness. All these evil things come from within, and they defile a person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 7:20-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what must &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; repent of? O my soul, do not brush this question aside in complacency. Jesus searches mind and heart, and so must you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hear again Jesus&amp;rsquo; own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Just so, I tell you, there is joy before the angels of God over one sinner who repents.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 15:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, repent, leave the past behind, and bring joy before the angels of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Small victories?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/robert-collins-tvc5imO5pXk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Small victories?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that the smallest things are in fact the most important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s notice something in Jesus&amp;rsquo; letter to the church in Pergamum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“And to the angel of the church in Pergamum write: ‘The words of him who has the sharp two-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘I know where you dwell, where Satan&amp;rsquo;s throne is. Yet you hold fast my name, and you did not deny my faith even in the days of Antipas my faithful witness, who was killed among you, where Satan dwells.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Pergamum was dominated by worship of pagan deities and so the church there was right in the thick of the spiritual battle. But doesn&amp;rsquo;t Jesus&amp;rsquo; commendation seem to be of such a small thing? Simply holding fast his name? Is that all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not underestimate what such apparently small things are ultimately all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of forgiving a brother in Christ who has caused much pain, Paul writes this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this is why I wrote, that I might test you and know whether you are obedient in everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 2:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you obedient in everything? Even in apparently small things? Let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one such. Recall something Jesus said in the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You have heard that it was said, ‘You shall not commit adultery.’ But I say to you that everyone who looks at a woman with lustful intent has already committed adultery with her in his heart.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:27-28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this not an area which requires honest self-evaluation and ruthless self-discipline? And isn&amp;rsquo;t this precisely one of these apparently small things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider. As you drive through the student quarter on a balmy summer afternoon, are you noticing the oh-so-attractive and rather scantily clad students parading themselves? And what do your eyes do then? And where do your thoughts take you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what your eyes are doing, because no-one sees? And where your thoughts are taking you, because no-one knows? It matters! Our Heavenly Father sees and our Heavenly Father knows. The choice between looking to the left or looking to the right is in fact the choice between disobedience and disrespect, or personal holiness and an act of worship. An act of worship to the one who loves you. The one who rescued you. The one who grieves over the vestigial sin in your life. O my soul, choose to honour him in this! Make every small victory over sin an act of worship, and keep your eyes to the right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the contexts of giving and praying and fasting, Jesus follows up with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:4, 6, 18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David knew this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you, Solomon my son, know the God of your father and serve him with a whole heart and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches all hearts and understands every plan and thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every plan. Every thought. And the intent behind each and every thought. Every motive which wanted to remain hidden is in fact fully exposed to the Lord who searches all hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that if you present yourselves to anyone as obedient slaves, you are slaves of the one whom you obey, either of sin, which leads to death, or of obedience, which leads to righteousness?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding fast Jesus&amp;rsquo; name is in truth all about consistency and integrity in the secret heart. Do you realise your character is the product of a thousand seemingly insignificant choices? You simply cannot do one thing and become another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God. Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth. For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God. When Christ who is your life appears, then you also will appear with him in glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whatever you do, in word or deed, do everything in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:1-4, 17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must also take heed of Jesus&amp;rsquo; sharp two-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart. And no creature is hidden from his sight, but all are naked and exposed to the eyes of him to whom we must give account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 4:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, notice that Antipas chose martyrdom rather than deny Jesus. And his reward? To bear the same description as of Jesus himself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Grace to you and peace from him who is and who was and who is to come, and from the seven spirits who are before his throne, and from Jesus Christ the faithful witness, the firstborn of the dead, and the ruler of kings on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the faithful witness and he bestowed upon Antipas the very same title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be ruthlessly consistent in how you approach all these apparently small things, and be Jesus&amp;rsquo; faithful witness in everything! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Created for his glory</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/mohamed-nohassi-odxB5oIG_iA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Created for his glory" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, why do you exist? What were you created for? You must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading in Isaiah, and I am overwhelmed by what I read. Before we come to my question though, let&amp;rsquo;s consider how the Lord regards us, his beloved ones. Let&amp;rsquo;s lose ourselves in the love letter which is Isaiah Chapter 43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD, he who created you, O Jacob, he who formed you, O Israel: “Fear not, for I have redeemed you; I have called you by name, you are mine.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember Jacob? He was that despicable little man, that man entirely without honour, a liar and a cheat. The man who wrestled with God, all night. The man to whom God gave a new name, Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So these words addressed to Jacob, who are they for? Their setting was the Babylonian exile. Jacob had been dead for perhaps a thousand years. Not for him then! These words are for his descendants⸺not his physical descendants, but the children of the promise⸺and that includes us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, these words are spoken to you by the God who created you, who formed you, who continues to form you⸺and he is not done with the forming by any means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that you may be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness. Fear not, O my soul. You have been redeemed by the Creator God of the universe. Called by him. Known by him. Belonging to him. Rejoice in that ineffable truth and embrace the forming of purity and blamelessness in your own life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this: you are called by name. Your name is who you are. It is your character. You are fully known by the one who calls. There is nothing that the Lord could subsequently learn about you which would change how he regards you. You are called and you are known and you are his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember God&amp;rsquo;s question to Jacob after the wrestling?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said to him, “What is your name?” And he said, “Jacob.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is God asking here? He is the omniscient and all powerful Creator God of the universe and he asks, “What is your name?” He is not seeking information! The question to Jacob is, what kind of man are you? And Jacob confesses his name⸺the cheat, the deceiver, vile and despicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he said, “Your name shall no longer be called Jacob, but Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold! God is the one who makes all things new! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And marvel at the extent to which the Lord will go to do this. Isaiah continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am the LORD your God, the Holy One of Israel, your Saviour. I give Egypt as your ransom, Cush and Seba in exchange for you. Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is my saviour. He is your saviour. The ransom is costly and there is no limit to where he will go for the rescue, because I am precious in his eyes, and honoured. Because you are precious, and he loves you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, he gave one man in particular in return for you: Jesus Christ, the only Son of God, in exchange for your life. In exchange for mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ransom is costly. But fear not, O my soul, he has redeemed you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are you here? Why do you exist? What were you created for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; bring my sons from afar and my daughters from the end of the earth, everyone who is called by my name, whom I created for my glory, whom I formed and made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1, 4, 6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You were created for the glory of God. He set his love upon you, called you by name, poured out that great love at Calvary, and redeemed you. There is no higher calling than for the glory of God. It is why I am here. It is why you are here. And as we receive that great Calvary love may all see it for what it is and give God the glory due his name. Be filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wrestling is done, O my soul. It&amp;rsquo;s time for that to end. You have been bought at a price⸺an unfathomable price. But that price has been paid, and in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now may your love abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, to know the magnitude of the reason why you are here. It is for the glory of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
