<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>holiness on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/holiness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in holiness on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/holiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>After midnight</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/after-midnight/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/after-midnight/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/after-midnight/graddes-fcavMQtHIXg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post After midnight" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why has the Lord not acted? Why are you still waiting? You were prepared to be taken to the eleventh hour, waiting and hoping and trusting, but now it&amp;rsquo;s after midnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After midnight for Cinderella: the coach has turned back into a pumpkin, the horses into mice and the footmen lizards. And here too are we, so long past midnight in our own waiting on the Lord. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it now all far too late?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who promised is indeed faithful. Rejoice in this wonderful verse, and hold fast without wavering. Hold fast without wavering for his name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so holding fast, we must now carefully read this verse in context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, brothers, since we have confidence to enter the holy places by the blood of Jesus, by the new and living way that he opened for us through the curtain, that is, through his flesh, and since we have a great priest over the house of God, let us draw near with a true heart in full assurance of faith, with our hearts sprinkled clean from an evil conscience and our bodies washed with pure water. Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful. And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:19-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin by reminding ourselves about this curtain, which was originally specified in meticulous detail by the Lord in the context of the tabernacle, that tent the Israelites were instructed to construct even while they were in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now even the first covenant had regulations for worship and an earthly place of holiness. For a tent was prepared, the first section, in which were the lampstand and the table and the bread of the Presence. It is called the Holy Place. Behind the second curtain was a second section called the Most Holy Place, having the golden altar of incense and the ark of the covenant covered on all sides with gold, in which was a golden urn holding the manna, and Aaron&amp;rsquo;s staff that budded, and the tablets of the covenant. Above it were the cherubim of glory overshadowing the mercy seat. Of these things we cannot now speak in detail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 9:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No indeed, we have not time to speak of these things in detail, or we would be reading the original six chapters in Exodus rather than these few verses in Hebrews. But those chapters are worth reading in their entirety to gain some insight into the holiness of God, and the astonishing level of consecration the priests were required to undergo before they could enter the holy place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do you remember that holy anointing oil made of myrrh and cassia and cinnamon and olive oil? Hear again the Lord&amp;rsquo;s instructions to Moses, and marvel anew at the ineffable holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“With it you shall anoint the tent of meeting and the ark of the testimony, and the table and all its utensils, and the lampstand and its utensils, and the altar of incense, and the altar of burnt offering with all its utensils and the basin and its stand. You shall consecrate them, that they may be most holy. Whatever touches them will become holy. You shall anoint Aaron and his sons, and consecrate them, that they may serve me as priests. And you shall say to the people of Israel, ‘This shall be my holy anointing oil throughout your generations. It shall not be poured on the body of an ordinary person, and you shall make no other like it in composition. It is holy, and it shall be holy to you. Whoever compounds any like it or whoever puts any of it on an outsider shall be cut off from his people.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 30:26-33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realise I am trying to do the impossible here, to convey something of the awe-inspiring holiness of God in just a couple of minutes, for this simply cannot be done. So go and read those chapters in their entirety with a view to being overwhelmed by the splendour and majesty and profound holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For we cannot understand our Cinderella story without having some grasp of the holiness of God, and the stupendous power poured out at the cross, and what this curtain is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now from the sixth hour there was darkness over all the land until the ninth hour. And about the ninth hour Jesus cried out with a loud voice, saying, “Eli, Eli, lema sabachthani?” that is, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?” And some of the bystanders, hearing it, said, “This man is calling Elijah.” And one of them at once ran and took a sponge, filled it with sour wine, and put it on a reed and gave it to him to drink. But the others said, “Wait, let us see whether Elijah will come to save him.” And Jesus cried out again with a loud voice and yielded up his spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And behold, the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. And the earth shook, and the rocks were split. The tombs also were opened. And many bodies of the saints who had fallen asleep were raised, and coming out of the tombs after his resurrection they went into the holy city and appeared to many. When the centurion and those who were with him, keeping watch over Jesus, saw the earthquake and what took place, they were filled with awe and said, “Truly this was the Son of God!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 27:45-54&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story is so familiar that we are in danger of reading straight past what is happening. So I will slow down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And behold, the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. And the earth shook, and the rocks were split. The tombs also were opened. And many bodies of the saints who had fallen asleep were raised, and coming out of the tombs after his resurrection they went into the holy city and appeared to many.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 27:51-53&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curtain separating off the Most Holy Place was torn in two, from top to bottom. The earth shook. Rocks were split. Tombs were opened and the dead were raised to life. And there were many witnesses of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular one doesn&amp;rsquo;t become a centurion in Caesar&amp;rsquo;s legions without surviving the horrors of war and the savagery unleashed on the battlefield. So pay attention to the comment from this battle-hardened veteran who was so very familiar with the awful and the terrible, and yet here was filled with awe. “Truly this was the Son of God!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this so relevant for the one waiting on the Lord?⸺the one waiting and longing and hoping? Because it shows the enormity of the power that was released when Jesus gave up his life and the curtain of the temple was torn in two from top to bottom. From top to bottom, mind you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because of the holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a new heaven and a new earth, for the first heaven and the first earth had passed away, and the sea was no more. And I saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband. And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man. He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. He will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain anymore, for the former things have passed away.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that glorious day the dwelling of God will be with his people. But make no mistake. His holiness will not be compromised. He will not lower his standards to let grubby sinners in to his perfect heaven. By no means! He will welcome in all who are holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore lift your drooping hands and strengthen your weak knees, and make straight paths for your feet, so that what is lame may not be put out of joint but rather be healed. Strive for peace with everyone, and for the holiness without which no one will see the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:12-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that holiness without which no-one will see the Lord we must be transformed, even as we are now being transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since we have these promises, beloved, let us cleanse ourselves from every defilement of body and spirit, bringing holiness to completion in the fear of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 7:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is what happens after midnight. It is after midnight in the crucible of life when it seems that all has failed that the Lord does his most profound work of transforming grace in our lives, but only as we surrender to his will, trusting without reservation and without holding back from the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, how he will! So trust him, even and especially after midnight, because that is when the things of this world are losing their grip on you. Make the most of your remaining time to repent of all that is unholy, to banish each and every shameful thought and deed, knowing that the power to do this is found only in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We know that our old self was crucified with him in order that the body of sin might be brought to nothing, so that we would no longer be enslaved to sin. For one who has died has been set free from sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For it is well after midnight and the new day is fast approaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the Day drawing near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, trust the Lord and prepare yourself for the new day which even now is drawing near! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The things that are revealed</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/vladimir-soares-3fer5_PzDkM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The things that are revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When is a mystery not a mystery? Why, when it has been revealed of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider just what has been revealed and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically on this Good Friday I want to consider the revelation of the mystery of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will, according to his purpose, from my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;desert island&lt;/a&gt; chapter of the Bible. And of course it is all and entirely about Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of our trespasses, according to the riches of his grace, which he lavished upon us, in all wisdom and insight making known to us the mystery of his will, according to his purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time, to unite all things in him, things in heaven and things on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack this slowly and carefully, for the words are so familiar we are at risk of progressing past them without really noticing what they&amp;rsquo;re even saying, when in fact we should again be completely overwhelmed by the goodness and kindness and sovereignty and justice of the Father, and by the riches of his grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jesus we have redemption. Thayer defines redemption as a releasing effected by payment of a ransom. So we must remind ourselves from what we have been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you were dead in the trespasses and sins in which you once walked, following the course of this world, following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience⸺among whom we all once lived in the passions of our flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind, and were by nature children of wrath, like the rest of mankind.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was dead in my trespasses and sins, and this was the norm as I merely followed the course of this world along with several billion others. How ironic that those who live in the passions of their flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind thinking they are free to do so are in fact slaves to sin, in bondage, children of wrath by their very nature, like the whole of mankind. We cannot understand the magnitude of this redemption⸺this release⸺without first understanding the sheer wretchedness and utter hopelessness of the previous state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was more wretched and more hopeless even than that. I was obliviously following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience. Satan has such a hold on those sometimes seen merely as worldly, and so many remain in ignorance of this. It is entirely a spiritual battle, and without Christ the battle is hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are not without Christ! And realising this and the magnitude of the rescue, how can humble gratitude not come flooding into our hearts, and love for our wonderful Saviour? And worship and adoration of our Heavenly Father whose purpose this is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was the ransom that was paid to release us from that previous state? It was the blood of the Lamb, the very Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they brought [Jesus] to the place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they crucified him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the sixth hour had come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour. And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, “Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?” which means, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:22,24a,33-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold the only Son of God crying out in anguish, forsaken by the Father who turned his face away from his only and most beloved Son. And you and I both know the reason why, the answer to Jesus&amp;rsquo; most desperate question. We know it only because in all wisdom and insight our Heavenly Father has made known to us the mystery of his will. This is no secret⸺it has been revealed to us according the riches of his grace. Jesus was forsaken on that cross so that we may not be. The debt that he paid was entirely ours. Our redemption is through the blood of the Lamb, poured out at Calvary for the forgiveness of sins, such a costly sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father turned his face away from his beloved Son precisely so that he could turn it towards us, previously miserable, hopeless and helpless sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was all according to God&amp;rsquo;s purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time. So it&amp;rsquo;s worth asking when he did this. When exactly did he set forth this plan? Behold! It was right at the beginning!  Only moments after sin first came into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD God said to the serpent, “Because you have done this, cursed are you above all livestock and above all beasts of the field; on your belly you shall go, and dust you shall eat all the days of your life. I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rescue was planned so far ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have obtained an inheritance, having been predestined according to the purpose of him who works all things according to the counsel of his will, so that we who were the first to hope in Christ might be to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of the fullness of time? Yet more revelation, this time through John the Apostle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw an angel coming down from heaven, holding in his hand the key to the bottomless pit and a great chain. And he seized the dragon, that ancient serpent, who is the devil and Satan, and bound him for a thousand years, and threw him into the pit, and shut it and sealed it over him, so that he might not deceive the nations any longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 20:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But finally, we must remember why it is that these things are revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apostle Paul expands upon this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father chose us in him before the foundation of the world that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this we must do, out of gratitude and adoration for our wonderful Saviour, as an act of worship, and in the power and grace of our risen Lord Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still the real mystery remains. Why would he do this? Why would the Creator God of the Universe set his love upon what is unlovely, those dead in trespasses and sins, at such great cost? We cannot fathom this. We can only thank and praise and worship and adore the one who made it so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, this mystery is revealed and yet remains. Worship and adore its divine author! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Walk before me and be blameless</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/anton-darius-zjGa2RQphRA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Walk before me and be blameless" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How on earth will you walk before the Lord and be blameless?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless, that I may make my covenant between me and you, and may multiply you greatly.” Then Abram fell on his face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall why Abraham fell on his face. Despite holding that impossible promise from the Lord for all those years, his life had been defined by cowardice and lies and failure and shame. He was at this time living with the consequence of having tried to fulfil that promise in his own strength, by fathering a child with the slave-girl Hagar. And I&amp;rsquo;m quite sure he enjoyed that at the time, having sex with the youthful Egyptian slave-girl rather than his ancient wife. But not now. Not when confronted with his sin and his shame and his failure by the Holy God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thirteen long years of living with the mess of that shameful failure all together in close proximity in that dysfunctional household,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham was overwhelmed by his own sin and shame and wretchedness, and when confronted by the holiness of God and his command, “Walk before me, and be blameless,” he fell on his face. There is nothing else he could have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whatever your situation, whatever shameful failure lies in your own past, and whatever the stumbling in more recent times, this is also addressed to you. It is exactly that to which each one of us is called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been chosen for you, but how on earth will you walk before this Holy God yourself and be holy and blameless? You must do this if you would enjoy his strong support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the eyes of the LORD run to and fro throughout the whole earth, to give strong support to those whose heart is blameless toward him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:9a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t this all too much to ask of an unholy people? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Creator God of the Universe chose each one of us in Christ, even before the foundation of the world, to be holy and blameless before him. He chose you for this and he chose me. You and I both must surrender to the choice of the one who is wise and strong and who knows how to achieve his plans and purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Job&amp;rsquo;s profession of faith after he had been confronted by the overwhelming greatness and majesty of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Job answered the LORD and said: “I know that you can do all things, and that no purpose of yours can be thwarted.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same overwhelmingly great and majestic God has a purpose for you and for me both, that we should be holy and blameless before him. So cry out to him along with the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfils his purpose for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not think you can resist the irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many are the plans in the mind of a man, but it is the purpose of the LORD that will stand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 19:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must surrender your life to the Holy Spirit as he does his sanctifying work in you. Resistance is futile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can unholy creatures be made holy? The answer is found only in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you, who once were alienated and hostile in mind, doing evil deeds, he has now reconciled in his body of flesh by his death, in order to present you holy and blameless and above reproach before him, if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has reconciled each one to himself in Christ&amp;rsquo;s body and by his death in order to present each one holy and blameless and above reproach before him. So do not shift from the hope of the gospel that you have heard, but which may not just now be in the forefront of your mind. Make it so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can we become holy, even according to his purposes? His strong and sure work of grace in our lives? If you desire this end, you must set your heart upon it. But isn&amp;rsquo;t it all just too hard? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I am up against. So how then can I co-operate with the Spirit of Christ in being transformed and made holy? Simply by noticing this: the strong connection between blamelessness and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now may our God and Father himself, and our Lord Jesus, direct our way to you, and may the Lord make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all, as we do for you, so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father, at the coming of our Lord Jesus with all his saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 3:11-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the Lord himself make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all precisely so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father. Oh my!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love that abounds more and more is the way to become pure and blameless for the day of Christ, and also quite remarkably how to fulfil the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Love does no wrong to a neighbour; therefore love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the power of love that will transform each one, and this fruit of righteousness comes only through Jesus. So set your course with determination to love the Lord with all your heart, soul, mind, and strength, and to love your neighbour as yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even as you wait on the Lord, even as you cry out to him through these long years of waiting, walk before him and be blameless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will sing of steadfast love and justice; to you, O LORD, I will make music. I will ponder the way that is blameless. Oh when will you come to me? I will walk with integrity of heart within my house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 101:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the waiting and the longing here? Oh when will you come to me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But above all, know that you will only be able to do any of this because of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to keep you from stumbling and to present you blameless before the presence of his glory with great joy, to the only God, our Saviour, through Jesus Christ our Lord, be glory, majesty, dominion, and authority, before all time and now and forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/jude&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude 1:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even in the waiting time, even in the heartbreak and the desperate longing, ensure to increase and abound in love, and so walk before him and be blameless! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Humbled by stumbling</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/humbled-by-stumbling/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/humbled-by-stumbling/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/humbled-by-stumbling/k-mitch-hodge-IqSaG9zv2e0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Humbled by stumbling" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are you going with your &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/approaching-holiness/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;holiness&lt;/a&gt; and repudiation of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/the-perils-of-worldliness/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;worldliness&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you embarrassed, ashamed even, of how feeble is your ability to live a right life which honours the Lord? Are you occasionally skewered by thoughts which take you to places you know you should not go, and in fact later you bitterly regret visiting? Do you find yourself stumbling? Again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not understand my own actions. For I do not do what I want, but I do the very thing I hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was written by the Apostle Paul, the very same man who had encountered Jesus personally and dramatically on the Damascus Road. The same man who had been taken up into the third heaven, into paradise, to hear things which man may not utter, however we grapple to understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I know a man in Christ who fourteen years ago was caught up to the third heaven⸺whether in the body or out of the body I do not know, God knows. And I know that this man was caught up into paradise⸺whether in the body or out of the body I do not know, God knows⸺and he heard things that cannot be told, which man may not utter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 12:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul knows this man in Christ for it is himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet after these amazing encounters and being filled with the Holy Spirit now we find Paul writing this, and in the present tense no less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not understand my own actions. For I do not do what I want, but I do the very thing I hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is Paul struggling with the very same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we must do is acknowledge that the spiritual battle is real and that it must be fought every day. Every single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then we must be wise to what we are up against. Again, listen to Paul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out. For I do not do the good I want, but the evil I do not want is what I keep on doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you somehow think that you have the ability to do that which was beyond the apostle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So I find it to be a law that when I want to do right, evil lies close at hand. For I delight in the law of God, in my inner being, but I see in my members another law waging war against the law of my mind and making me captive to the law of sin that dwells in my members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians through the ages have struggled to understand what Paul is saying here, for does it not seem to be both defeatist and without hope? It is neither of these things. It is gritty reality, the astute observation of one for whom there is no pretending, and the humble acknowledgement of the extent to which the hooks of sin remain in one&amp;rsquo;s life even after eternal salvation has been secured by Christ&amp;rsquo;s death and resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a war being waged then it must be fought. But it must be fought with the right weapons and in the grace of God. Let us first recognise that which is our own responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For those who live according to the flesh set their minds on the things of the flesh, but those who live according to the Spirit set their minds on the things of the Spirit. For to set the mind on the flesh is death, but to set the mind on the Spirit is life and peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what is your mind set upon? The Lord knows! And it is this which is the key to victory in the spiritual battle for our own holiness⸺earnest desire to honour the Lord in every last detail of our lives, and a longing for that which is good, right, and true to have the victory over sin in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what? Well then we must fully engage with Paul&amp;rsquo;s argument, for it is hope and strength and life and peace to each one burdened by ongoing and besetting sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now if I do what I do not want, I agree with the law, that it is good. So now it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if I do what I do not want, it is no longer I who do it, but sin that dwells within me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:16-17, 20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is precisely that earnest desire to live a right life in humble gratitude to my saviour that is evidence of this: I am not my sin! It no longer defines me. And so along with Paul and with a grateful heart I can declare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wretched man that I am! Who will deliver me from this body of death? Thanks be to God through Jesus Christ our Lord! So then, I myself serve the law of God with my mind, but with my flesh I serve the law of sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only through Jesus&amp;rsquo; death and resurrection can I be delivered from this wretched state. Praise my Saviour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more. Much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is therefore now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus. For the law of the Spirit of life has set you free in Christ Jesus from the law of sin and death. For God has done what the law, weakened by the flesh, could not do. By sending his own Son in the likeness of sinful flesh and for sin, he condemned sin in the flesh, in order that the righteous requirement of the law might be fulfilled in us, who walk not according to the flesh but according to the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the victory. It is in Christ and it is Christ. And for those who are in Christ there is no condemnation. Instead there is freedom⸺freedom in Christ. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tension between the flesh and the Spirit remains but notice that the Lord has condemned sin in the flesh. He did this in order that the righteous requirement of the law might be fulfilled in each one of us, that is, in order that each one of us may become holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And furthermore notice this phenomenal promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But if Christ is in you, although the body is dead because of sin, the Spirit is life because of righteousness. If the Spirit of him who raised Jesus from the dead dwells in you, he who raised Christ Jesus from the dead will also give life to your mortal bodies through his Spirit who dwells in you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is nothing if not a promise of sanctification through the indwelling Spirit of Christ Jesus. These very mortal bodies which are dead because of sin will be given life. Victory over sin is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s gift of grace, the sanctifying work of the Spirit. Yes, it is utterly beyond us, but it is not beyond him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are we to do when we stumble? Simply cry out to the Lord in anguish over our ongoing sin, confess that sin, repent, and receive forgiveness and restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even when you stumble, especially when you stumble, repent, set your mind on the things of the Spirit, be lifted up once more, and by doing so choose life and peace! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Approaching holiness</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/approaching-holiness/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/approaching-holiness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/approaching-holiness/pablo-heimplatz-EAvS-4KnGrk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Approaching holiness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you desire to be holy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me ask something else. Do you desire to see the Lord? Because in fact this is the very same question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Strive &amp;hellip; for the holiness without which no one will see the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake. Without holiness you will not see the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several words for holiness in the New Testament. The holiness without which no-one will see the Lord is &lt;em&gt;hagiasmos&lt;/em&gt;, which means purity, or consecration, or sanctification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you desire this then? You had better, for the Lord desires it of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For this is the will of God, your sanctification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For God has not called us for impurity, but in holiness. Therefore whoever disregards this, disregards not man but God, who gives his Holy Spirit to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 4:3, 7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words translated here as sanctification and holiness are the very same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this then to which we are called? It is about putting on a whole new self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now this I say and testify in the Lord, that you must no longer walk as the Gentiles do, in the futility of their minds. They are darkened in their understanding, alienated from the life of God because of the ignorance that is in them, due to their hardness of heart. They have become callous and have given themselves up to sensuality, greedy to practice every kind of impurity. But that is not the way you learned Christ!⸺assuming that you have heard about him and were taught in him, as the truth is in Jesus, to put off your old self, which belongs to your former manner of life and is corrupt through deceitful desires, and to be renewed in the spirit of your minds, and to put on the new self, created after the likeness of God in true righteousness and holiness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:17-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old self is corrupt through deceitful desires. They are deceitful because they claim to lead to satisfaction and contentment but in fact they lead to death and destruction. Beware these deceitful desires! But the new self is created after the likeness of God in true righteousness and holiness. O my soul, you must put on this new self, and find satisfaction and contentment and joy in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting on the new self is so important that Paul lists with exceeding clarity in several places exactly what are its consequences, highlighting the stark contrast between the new self and the old self. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I say, walk by the Spirit, and you will not gratify the desires of the flesh. For the desires of the flesh are against the Spirit, and the desires of the Spirit are against the flesh, for these are opposed to each other, to keep you from doing the things you want to do. But if you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law. Now the works of the flesh are evident: sexual immorality, impurity, sensuality, idolatry, sorcery, enmity, strife, jealousy, fits of anger, rivalries, dissensions, divisions, envy, drunkenness, orgies, and things like these. I warn you, as I warned you before, that those who do such things will not inherit the kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:16-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we must be so careful in approaching these lists of Paul&amp;rsquo;s, because we are absolutely not called to box-ticking, as if we could somehow measure up. So let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can understand the main point here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, recognize the battle that is being waged in the inner being. The desires of the flesh are against the Spirit, and the desires of the Spirit are against the flesh, for these are opposed to each other. Paul expands upon this in his letter to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For we know that the law is spiritual, but I am of the flesh, sold under sin. For I do not understand my own actions. For I do not do what I want, but I do the very thing I hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I find it to be a law that when I want to do right, evil lies close at hand. For I delight in the law of God, in my inner being, but I see in my members another law waging war against the law of my mind and making me captive to the law of sin that dwells in my members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:14-15, 21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation appears to be desperate, and for the one who would honour the Lord through living a life of personal holiness it seems to be hopeless. This must be both acknowledged and then repudiated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wretched man that I am! Who will deliver me from this body of death? Thanks be to God through Jesus Christ our Lord!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is victory through Jesus and only through him. There is simply no other way to achieve this holiness. And so what must fuel this desire for holiness is humility and a grateful heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God chose what is low and despised in the world, even things that are not, to bring to nothing things that are, so that no human being might boast in the presence of God. And because of him you are in Christ Jesus, who became to us wisdom from God, righteousness and sanctification and redemption, so that, as it is written, “Let the one who boasts, boast in the Lord.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 1:28-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no badge of honour in living a holy life. That idea is straight out of the Pharisaical heart. The holy life is evidence of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s victory over the sin in our lives, and the glory is his alone. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, weep in gratitude to your Saviour and Redeemer, who alone has the power to transform you in this way.  And know that the transformation is a matter of life and death. For how does Paul conclude his shocking list?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I warn you, as I warned you before, that those who do such things will not inherit the kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:21b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, know that you will never earn your own way in this regard. And rejoice in this blessed truth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But if you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/galatians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Galatians 5:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you understand what it means to be led by the Spirit? Recall &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/led-by-the-spirit/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;what I wrote previously&lt;/a&gt; about this, based on the insight of J.I. Packer. Being led by the Spirit is about putting to death the deeds of the body and not gratifying the desires of the flesh. It is all about the power of the sanctified will. This has nothing to do with understanding or insight! It is about doing rather than discerning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We absolutely must learn to live in this power, to surrender our unholy wills to the holy and righteous will of God. This is the very crux of the spiritual battle! The life of personal holiness must be an outworking of gratitude and love and worship to our rescuer, the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of us could possibly live up to the law and attain any of this. But rejoice because that is not what we are called to do. Those who are led by the Spirit, who have surrendered their will to the Lord to live in submission and humility are not under the law. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, put aside any thought that you could possibly live a holy life in your own strength, surrender your will to the sanctifying work of the Spirit, and weep in gratitude as this great love and transforming grace are poured out in your life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Open your own eyes</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/ben-white-EMZxDosijJ4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Open your own eyes" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you desire that the Lord light up your eyes, what are you doing about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you surprised that I ask what you are doing, as if it could make any difference? Whether the Lord chooses to light up your eyes is entirely out of your hands isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen again to the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The law of the LORD is perfect, reviving the soul; the testimony of the LORD is sure, making wise the simple; the precepts of the LORD are right, rejoicing the heart; the commandment of the LORD is pure, enlightening the eyes; the fear of the LORD is clean, enduring forever; the rules of the LORD are true, and righteous altogether. More to be desired are they than gold, even much fine gold; sweeter also than honey and drippings of the honeycomb. Moreover, by them is your servant warned; in keeping them there is great reward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 19:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by noticing the pure commandment of the Lord which enlightens the eyes. But we must ingest the whole of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you desire the rules of the Lord? Do you know their sweetness? Do you know that great reward which is keeping them? Do you desire to be revived? Are you feeding and watering that desire that it may flourish, and you with it? Do you even know how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is telling it, over and over. The law of the Lord is perfect. The testimony of the Lord is sure. The precepts of the Lord are right. The commandment of the Lord is pure. These revive the soul, make wise the simple, rejoice the heart, and enlighten the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my question to you is, have you immersed yourself in these and do you continue to do so? Do you begin each new day by plunging into the word of God, his law, his testimony, his precepts, and his commandments? And if not, why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is joy here in the face of a demoralising and depressing world. There is power here in the face of the overwhelming and apparently insoluble problems of the world⸺oppression, self-interest, corruption, exploitation, hatred, and war. In such contrast to the world&amp;rsquo;s murkiness and moral ambiguity, the commandment of the Lord is pure and it enlightens the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, steep yourself in the word of God, each morning and throughout the day. Wrap yourself in it and walk in it, with rejoicing and a grateful heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you have been waiting for deliverance now for so long you have started to think there is nothing else you can do. O my soul, you must not wallow in your waiting, as if there is nothing to be done. That could not be further from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your waiting, as days become weeks and weeks become months and with each passing year, are you growing in your desire for the Lord? Are you growing in faith? Are you growing in love and holiness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, this year is so very rapidly approaching its end. Ask yourself, does my heart desire the Lord more so now than at its beginning? Is my faith stronger and more resilient? Have I grown in love and holiness? If not, it has surely been a waste of a year. Do not be so negligent as to waste the next one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your own longing for change listen to the longing of the psalmist. It is above all a longing for personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are those whose way is blameless,
who walk in the law of the LORD! Blessed are those who keep his testimonies, who seek him with their whole heart, who also do no wrong, but walk in his ways! You have commanded your precepts to be kept diligently. Oh that my ways may be steadfast in keeping your statutes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is both longing and determination here, and also realism, for doesn&amp;rsquo;t this task seem to be utterly beyond us? But it is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your testimonies are wonderful; therefore my soul keeps them. The unfolding of your words gives light; it imparts understanding to the simple. I open my mouth and pant, because I long for your commandments. Turn to me and be gracious to me, as is your way with those who love your name. Keep steady my steps according to your promise, and let no iniquity get dominion over me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:129-133&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, you must be diligent to let no iniquity get dominion over you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three more things that remain to be done, and these can be learnt from the Apostle Paul in just half a sentence. The whole sentence is simply too overwhelming to take in at one go, because this is Paul! He has just been describing our glorious inheritance in Christ and the guarantee we have in the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this reason, because I have heard of your faith in the Lord Jesus and your love toward all the saints, I do not cease to give thanks for you, remembering you in my prayers, that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of him, having the eyes of your hearts enlightened &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:15-18a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these three things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is to exercise faith in the Lord Jesus, so it may grow. Are you waiting on an impossible promise from the Lord? Then keep on waiting, believing and not doubting, and he will light up your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is to pray. This is Paul&amp;rsquo;s prayer for the saints in Ephesus. Make it your own and not only yours. Pray for the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of the Lord to light up the eyes of your heart, those eyes of faith, which must shine in expectation and reflected glory. And pray this also for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third is to love. Do not hold back from loving all the saints. The saints are simply the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people, although some are not yet so very saintly to be sure, being still in the early stages of sanctification and humility. But you must love, and you must not overlook that little word &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt;. If you desire that the Lord light up your eyes, then you must love all the saints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desiring the law of the Lord and his testimonies and his precepts and his commandments and his rules is ultimately an outworking of love itself, our love for the Lord in response to his own great love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you starting to understand how to put yourself in the place of the Lord lighting up your eyes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, love the Lord and do not hold back! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The open door</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-open-door/chris-meads-VDHn0YmjIw4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The open door" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does an open door constitute a reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia write: ‘The words of the holy one, the true one, who has the key of David, who opens and no one will shut, who shuts and no one opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works. Behold, I have set before you an open door, which no one is able to shut.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:7-8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the seven churches only Smyrna was able to join with Philadelphia in being commended by Jesus without reservation. Jesus knew their works. What a joy it must have been for him to commend their faithfulness and to richly reward them. So let&amp;rsquo;s consider the reward of that open door. And let&amp;rsquo;s start by asking, how does that even constitute a reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t an open door simply an opportunity presenting itself? Indeed Paul uses exactly this metaphor on several occasions. Here are two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I will stay in Ephesus until Pentecost, for a wide door for effective work has opened to me, and there are many adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 16:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving. At the same time, pray also for us, that God may open to us a door for the word, to declare the mystery of Christ, on account of which I am in prison⸺that I may make it clear, which is how I ought to speak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 4:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truly the opportunity here was not presenting itself but rather was being presented as a sovereign work of the Lord. Paul was most concerned about the open door for declaring the mystery of Christ, that he may make it clear⸺of course he was. But I am not persuaded that this was the nature of the reward for the Philadelphians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s a clue in Jesus&amp;rsquo; next letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is not knocking on the Philadelphian door because it is already open and he is right there among them. This is the door to heaven itself, just as John&amp;rsquo;s vision continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After this I looked, and behold, a door standing open in heaven! And the first voice, which I had heard speaking to me like a trumpet, said, “Come up here, and I will show you what must take place after this.” At once I was in the Spirit, and behold, a throne stood in heaven, with one seated on the throne. And he who sat there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian, and around the throne was a rainbow that had the appearance of an emerald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 4:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a door this is! And it is wide open and cannot be shut. What a reward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In passing we must enjoy to notice John&amp;rsquo;s ludicrous attempt to describe the indescribable, the one seated on the throne. He who was seated there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian. Really? Is that the best he could have done? It tells us nothing. Except of course of the ineffability of the Creator God of the Universe, reigning and ruling in majesty and splendour. Praise his holy name! And praise his indescribable being!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we continue to think about that door, let&amp;rsquo;s consider what was being rewarded, for it seems to be so very little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that you have but little power, and yet you have kept my word and have not denied my name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you have kept my word about patient endurance &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:8b, 10a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s the entirety of it! But make no mistake, this is not so very little at all. We need to understand what this means, to keep Jesus&amp;rsquo; word and not to deny his name. It is in fact about absolute trust and complete surrender and living an uncompromised life which is fully consistent and perfectly aligned with Jesus being Lord of all. And it is about that personal holiness which is an ongoing act of worship to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; name is his character. It is who he is. So what would deny his name? Would it not be anxiety or doubt or inconsistency or pretence or pride or holding anything back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you understand the magnitude of what was being commended? Marvel at it, and now go and do likewise! And if you think you simply lack the strength to live like this, observe that the Philadelphians also had but little power. The power to live like this is all the Lord&amp;rsquo;s and it is his gift of grace. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But back to this open door. Jesus tells us a bit more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So Jesus again said to them, “Truly, truly, I say to you, I am the door of the sheep. All who came before me are thieves and robbers, but the sheep did not listen to them. I am the door. If anyone enters by me, he will be saved and will go in and out and find pasture. The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the door, and he is the door to life itself. Jesus came that we may have life and have it abundantly. O my soul, are you starting to understand the magnitude of the Philadelphian reward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is something else which must not be overlooked. What does Jesus say of those who have not lived this pure and holy and surrendered life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and they will learn that I have loved you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:9b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, have you learnt this? Have you learnt that the King of the Universe has loved you with an everlasting love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, do not overlook that the abundant life is this life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 3:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, live like those Philadelphians, and receive from Jesus the reward of that open door! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Repent!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/repent/cj-botha-PTztNC4yKY0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Repent!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent call to repent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This call to repent went out long ago to the church in Thyatira and it remains today. But let&amp;rsquo;s first marvel at Jesus&amp;rsquo; generous assessment of that church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Thyatira write: ‘The words of the Son of God, who has eyes like a flame of fire, and whose feet are like burnished bronze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works, your love and faith and service and patient endurance, and that your latter works exceed the first.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the church in Thyatira were these commended by Jesus for their love and faith and service and patient endurance. O my soul, how are your own love and faith and service and patient endurance? Jesus knows! His eyes are like a flame of fire and nothing is hidden from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did you notice the generosity in his assessment? Their latter works exceeded the first⸺some were slow starters. Jesus did not dwell on what came before. He commended them for how they were now. O my soul, leave the past behind! Jesus does not dwell on what came before and nor must you. Know that he is generous in his assessment also of you, desiring for you only what is good. He loves you and is committed to you and demands reciprocity in these. Rejoice that it is so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was not all good news in Thyatira.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have this against you, that you tolerate that woman Jezebel, who calls herself a prophetess and is teaching and seducing my servants to practice sexual immorality and to eat food sacrificed to idols. I gave her time to repent, but she refuses to repent of her sexual immorality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we come specifically to the seduction and the sexual immorality, let&amp;rsquo;s notice something significant here⸺a similarity and a difference with what we read in Jesus&amp;rsquo; letter to the church in Ephesus. Here we have a woman calling herself a prophetess and leading the church astray. In the church in Ephesus there were false apostles also leading the church astray. If that is the similarity what is the difference? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it that she was given time to repent and they were not? Recall that there was no call to repentance for those false apostles in Ephesus. They were simply excluded by Jesus and rejected. Tremble at that judgment and that rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now our instinct may be to characterise Jezebel&amp;rsquo;s sin as utterly heinous, far worse than what was happening in Ephesus, but pause to consider that Jesus did in fact give her that time to repent. This is not something we can understand in its entirety but surely warns us off ranking sins and ranking sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those she was leading astray?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I will throw her onto a sickbed, and those who commit adultery with her I will throw into great tribulation, unless they repent of her works, and I will strike her children dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:22-23a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repent! O my soul, notice the urgency to repent. Jesus came to break the chains of bondage to sin and death and to give life in all its abundance, and repentance and faith are the means to receive this precious and lavish gift. But her children, her spiritual offspring who refuse this gift will be struck dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is this death? Is it not that final, second death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. The one who conquers will not be hurt by the second death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then of the specifics of the sin⸺sexual immorality and eating of food sacrificed to idols. Of the former we can say one thing immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you not know that your bodies are members of Christ? Shall I then take the members of Christ and make them members of a prostitute? Never!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flee from sexual immorality. Every other sin a person commits is outside the body, but the sexually immoral person sins against his own body. Or do you not know that your body is a temple of the Holy Spirit within you, whom you have from God? You are not your own, for you were bought with a price. So glorify God in your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 6:15, 18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How different this is from how our own world views such things. Sexual immorality deeply grieves the Lord, for it is a corruption and a debasement of his wonderful gift to those he made in his own image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is something wider going on here. The pagan worship of the day was centred around ritual sexual acts with temple prostitutes and eating of food sacrificed to idols, and this had come in to the church. How this dishonoured the Lord! It was the worldliness of the day invading his church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of worldliness invading the church in our own time? How this dishonours the Lord! And lest you be thinking that what was being rebuked in Thyatira was merely outward behaviour, think again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And all the churches will know that I am he who searches mind and heart, and I will give to each of you according to your works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:23b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the one who searches mind and heart. Mind and heart are where the Lord is first honoured or dishonoured. As Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What comes out of a person is what defiles him. For from within, out of the heart of man, come evil thoughts, sexual immorality, theft, murder, adultery, coveting, wickedness, deceit, sensuality, envy, slander, pride, foolishness. All these evil things come from within, and they defile a person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 7:20-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what must &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; repent of? O my soul, do not brush this question aside in complacency. Jesus searches mind and heart, and so must you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hear again Jesus&amp;rsquo; own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Just so, I tell you, there is joy before the angels of God over one sinner who repents.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 15:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, repent, leave the past behind, and bring joy before the angels of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Small victories?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/small-victories/robert-collins-tvc5imO5pXk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Small victories?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that the smallest things are in fact the most important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s notice something in Jesus&amp;rsquo; letter to the church in Pergamum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“And to the angel of the church in Pergamum write: ‘The words of him who has the sharp two-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘I know where you dwell, where Satan&amp;rsquo;s throne is. Yet you hold fast my name, and you did not deny my faith even in the days of Antipas my faithful witness, who was killed among you, where Satan dwells.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Pergamum was dominated by worship of pagan deities and so the church there was right in the thick of the spiritual battle. But doesn&amp;rsquo;t Jesus&amp;rsquo; commendation seem to be of such a small thing? Simply holding fast his name? Is that all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not underestimate what such apparently small things are ultimately all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of forgiving a brother in Christ who has caused much pain, Paul writes this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this is why I wrote, that I might test you and know whether you are obedient in everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 2:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you obedient in everything? Even in apparently small things? Let&amp;rsquo;s consider just one such. Recall something Jesus said in the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You have heard that it was said, ‘You shall not commit adultery.’ But I say to you that everyone who looks at a woman with lustful intent has already committed adultery with her in his heart.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:27-28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this not an area which requires honest self-evaluation and ruthless self-discipline? And isn&amp;rsquo;t this precisely one of these apparently small things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider. As you drive through the student quarter on a balmy summer afternoon, are you noticing the oh-so-attractive and rather scantily clad students parading themselves? And what do your eyes do then? And where do your thoughts take you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what your eyes are doing, because no-one sees? And where your thoughts are taking you, because no-one knows? It matters! Our Heavenly Father sees and our Heavenly Father knows. The choice between looking to the left or looking to the right is in fact the choice between disobedience and disrespect, or personal holiness and an act of worship. An act of worship to the one who loves you. The one who rescued you. The one who grieves over the vestigial sin in your life. O my soul, choose to honour him in this! Make every small victory over sin an act of worship, and keep your eyes to the right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the contexts of giving and praying and fasting, Jesus follows up with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And your Father who sees in secret will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:4, 6, 18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David knew this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you, Solomon my son, know the God of your father and serve him with a whole heart and with a willing mind, for the LORD searches all hearts and understands every plan and thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Chronicles 28:9a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every plan. Every thought. And the intent behind each and every thought. Every motive which wanted to remain hidden is in fact fully exposed to the Lord who searches all hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you not know that if you present yourselves to anyone as obedient slaves, you are slaves of the one whom you obey, either of sin, which leads to death, or of obedience, which leads to righteousness?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 6:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding fast Jesus&amp;rsquo; name is in truth all about consistency and integrity in the secret heart. Do you realise your character is the product of a thousand seemingly insignificant choices? You simply cannot do one thing and become another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God. Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth. For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God. When Christ who is your life appears, then you also will appear with him in glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whatever you do, in word or deed, do everything in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:1-4, 17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must also take heed of Jesus&amp;rsquo; sharp two-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart. And no creature is hidden from his sight, but all are naked and exposed to the eyes of him to whom we must give account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 4:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, notice that Antipas chose martyrdom rather than deny Jesus. And his reward? To bear the same description as of Jesus himself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Grace to you and peace from him who is and who was and who is to come, and from the seven spirits who are before his throne, and from Jesus Christ the faithful witness, the firstborn of the dead, and the ruler of kings on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the faithful witness and he bestowed upon Antipas the very same title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be ruthlessly consistent in how you approach all these apparently small things, and be Jesus&amp;rsquo; faithful witness in everything! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Created for his glory</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/mohamed-nohassi-odxB5oIG_iA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Created for his glory" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, why do you exist? What were you created for? You must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading in Isaiah, and I am overwhelmed by what I read. Before we come to my question though, let&amp;rsquo;s consider how the Lord regards us, his beloved ones. Let&amp;rsquo;s lose ourselves in the love letter which is Isaiah Chapter 43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD, he who created you, O Jacob, he who formed you, O Israel: “Fear not, for I have redeemed you; I have called you by name, you are mine.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember Jacob? He was that despicable little man, that man entirely without honour, a liar and a cheat. The man who wrestled with God, all night. The man to whom God gave a new name, Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So these words addressed to Jacob, who are they for? Their setting was the Babylonian exile. Jacob had been dead for perhaps a thousand years. Not for him then! These words are for his descendants⸺not his physical descendants, but the children of the promise⸺and that includes us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, these words are spoken to you by the God who created you, who formed you, who continues to form you⸺and he is not done with the forming by any means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that you may be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness. Fear not, O my soul. You have been redeemed by the Creator God of the universe. Called by him. Known by him. Belonging to him. Rejoice in that ineffable truth and embrace the forming of purity and blamelessness in your own life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this: you are called by name. Your name is who you are. It is your character. You are fully known by the one who calls. There is nothing that the Lord could subsequently learn about you which would change how he regards you. You are called and you are known and you are his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember God&amp;rsquo;s question to Jacob after the wrestling?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said to him, “What is your name?” And he said, “Jacob.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is God asking here? He is the omniscient and all powerful Creator God of the universe and he asks, “What is your name?” He is not seeking information! The question to Jacob is, what kind of man are you? And Jacob confesses his name⸺the cheat, the deceiver, vile and despicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he said, “Your name shall no longer be called Jacob, but Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold! God is the one who makes all things new! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And marvel at the extent to which the Lord will go to do this. Isaiah continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am the LORD your God, the Holy One of Israel, your Saviour. I give Egypt as your ransom, Cush and Seba in exchange for you. Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is my saviour. He is your saviour. The ransom is costly and there is no limit to where he will go for the rescue, because I am precious in his eyes, and honoured. Because you are precious, and he loves you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, he gave one man in particular in return for you: Jesus Christ, the only Son of God, in exchange for your life. In exchange for mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ransom is costly. But fear not, O my soul, he has redeemed you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are you here? Why do you exist? What were you created for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; bring my sons from afar and my daughters from the end of the earth, everyone who is called by my name, whom I created for my glory, whom I formed and made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1, 4, 6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You were created for the glory of God. He set his love upon you, called you by name, poured out that great love at Calvary, and redeemed you. There is no higher calling than for the glory of God. It is why I am here. It is why you are here. And as we receive that great Calvary love may all see it for what it is and give God the glory due his name. Be filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wrestling is done, O my soul. It&amp;rsquo;s time for that to end. You have been bought at a price⸺an unfathomable price. But that price has been paid, and in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now may your love abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, to know the magnitude of the reason why you are here. It is for the glory of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
