<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>praise on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/praise/</link>
        <description>Recent content in praise on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/praise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The sacrifice of thanksgiving</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-thanksgiving/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-thanksgiving/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-thanksgiving/velizar-ivanov-V_Giq2h5jak-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The sacrifice of thanksgiving" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you grateful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, really, joyously grateful to the one who has rescued you, redeemed you, blessed you, and given you hope and a future. Are you grateful to him with all your heart? It matters that you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the way to Jerusalem he was passing along between Samaria and Galilee. And as he entered a village, he was met by ten lepers, who stood at a distance and lifted up their voices, saying, “Jesus, Master, have mercy on us.” When he saw them he said to them, “Go and show yourselves to the priests.” And as they went they were cleansed. Then one of them, when he saw that he was healed, turned back, praising God with a loud voice; and he fell on his face at Jesus&amp;rsquo; feet, giving him thanks. Now he was a Samaritan. Then Jesus answered, “Were not ten cleansed? Where are the nine? Was no one found to return and give praise to God except this foreigner?” And he said to him, “Rise and go your way; your faith has made you well.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:11-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten lepers were healed but only one was sufficiently grateful to return to Jesus, to thank him and to praise God. What did Jesus say to this one alone? “Your faith has made you well.” Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this leave us wondering, what of the others? Did they remain healed? We don&amp;rsquo;t know and we can&amp;rsquo;t know. I suspect the generosity of the Lord towards ungrateful sinners is that they did in fact remain healed. But really, shame on them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will give thanks to the LORD with my whole heart; I will recount all of your wonderful deeds. I will be glad and exult in you; I will sing praise to your name, O Most High.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 9:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So is this what gratitude must be? Ensuring to thank the Lord with your whole heart as and when you receive blessing and healing and deliverance, with the expectation of further blessing to come? By no means! O my soul, you must not settle for such an impoverished understanding of thankfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul gives us a clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all circumstances you must give thanks, even acknowledging that some of these circumstances are hard to bear. For this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider David, fleeing for his life from Saul. Listen to his words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be merciful to me, O God, be merciful to me,
for in you my soul takes refuge; in the shadow of your wings I will take refuge, till the storms of destruction pass by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul is in the midst of lions; I lie down amid fiery beasts⸺the children of man, whose teeth are spears and arrows, whose tongues are sharp swords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:1, 4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this sound remotely like one who is receiving blessing and healing and deliverance? And yet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be exalted, O God, above the heavens! Let your glory be over all the earth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even in the midst of peril how does he end his psalm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will give thanks to you, O Lord, among the peoples; I will sing praises to you among the nations. For your steadfast love is great to the heavens, your faithfulness to the clouds. Be exalted, O God, above the heavens! Let your glory be over all the earth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something profound here which must be understood, and it is the nature of &lt;em&gt;sacrifice&lt;/em&gt; in thanksgiving. Another psalmist articulates it like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I love the LORD, because he has heard my voice and my pleas for mercy. Because he inclined his ear to me, therefore I will call on him as long as I live. The snares of death encompassed me; the pangs of Sheol laid hold on me; I suffered distress and anguish. Then I called on the name of the LORD: “O LORD, I pray, deliver my soul!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 116:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in times such as these that it is costly to give thanks, and yet it is precisely because of this that the thanksgiving becomes a sacrifice. The psalmist continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Precious in the sight of the LORD is the death of his saints. O LORD, I am your servant; I am your servant, the son of your maidservant. You have loosed my bonds. I will offer to you the sacrifice of thanksgiving and call on the name of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 116:15-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has he been saved or will his death imminently become precious in the sight of the Lord? It seems somewhat ambiguous to me. Is this why his thanksgiving is a sacrifice? Perhaps he will not even survive the time of crisis and yet still he gives thanks to God. This is the sacrifice of thanksgiving, and it is costly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, I know your heartbreak and your longing. In these you must give thanks. And yes, that is so very painful, but you simply must. Be encouraged by the words of the Apostle Paul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There remain two observations still to be made and it is vital that they be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is that giving thanks &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; a situation of pain and grief and heartbreak is not giving thanks &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; these things, in some kind of passive-aggressive “thank you for hurting me” way. But it is never too difficult to find something truly worthy of thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this surely remains a sacrifice of thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second may seem to be quite close to “thank-you for hurting me”, but in fact it is not. It is the place where joy and sorrow meet and are inextricably intertwined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It is for discipline that you have to endure. God is treating you as sons. For what son is there whom his father does not discipline?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O sons and daughters dearly loved, know that your Heavenly Father is so deeply invested in you there is nothing he won&amp;rsquo;t do for your eternal good. And some of these things are painful indeed to endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the moment all discipline seems painful rather than pleasant, but later it yields the peaceful fruit of righteousness to those who have been trained by it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of the most painful experience, offer up to God your sacrifice of thanksgiving for such commitment and investment that he has made in you, that he will see through to completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asaph speaks the word of the Lord to those who may have forgotten this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who offers thanksgiving as his sacrifice glorifies me; to one who orders his way rightly I will show the salvation of God!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 50:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, offer up to the Lord your sacrifice of thanksgiving however much you are hurting! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What to think about</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/redd-f-LP3PabHuyiE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What to think about" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you thinking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking again about those insolent ones? And if so, why? Why would you continue to think about them? Thinking about them is not blessing you. Be assured that they are not thinking about you! Or are you dwelling on other things which drag you down? Why would you continue to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Like a dog that returns to his vomit is a fool who repeats his folly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 26:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what are you doing? Would you be building that dam on the river of life? Stop! Stop thinking about those things which drag you down. Stop dwelling on them. Stop living in them. Think instead about something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then? What must you think about? Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honourable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about these things and be lifted up and encouraged. So what are they, these things that we must think about? Rejoice that they are many and varied, and fill your mind with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw heaven opened, and behold, a white horse! The one sitting on it is called Faithful and True, and in righteousness he judges and makes war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Here is Jesus in all of his resurrection power and splendour, whose very name is Faithful and True. In righteousness he judges and makes war on all that is unholy. And he is victorious. Think about him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now, O Lord GOD, you are God, and your words are true, and you have promised this good thing to your servant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Samuel 7:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words of the Lord are true. What he has promised is true. His name is Faithful and True. Think about this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is just.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours in full. If we confess our sins and cry out to God for mercy it is his justice that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment precisely because he is just. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I the LORD love justice; I hate robbery and wrong; I will faithfully give them their recompense, and I will make an everlasting covenant with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1,8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that the Lord loves justice. In power and compassion Jesus came to do justice for the poor and the oppressed. Think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn to do good; seek justice, correct oppression; bring justice to the fatherless, plead the widow&amp;rsquo;s cause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about how to do justice⸺the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own justice which binds up the brokenhearted and proclaims liberty to the captives and the opening of the prison to those who are bound. Think about how to do this in his Spirit and by his power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about what is worthy of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I looked, and I heard around the throne and the living creatures and the elders the voice of many angels, numbering myriads of myriads and thousands of thousands, saying with a loud voice, “Worthy is the Lamb who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and might and honour and glory and blessing!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the sound of a hundred million angels singing praise to the risen Lord Jesus in his resurrection power and splendour. And hear his own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I turned to see the voice that was speaking to me, and on turning I saw seven golden lampstands, and in the midst of the lampstands one like a son of man, clothed with a long robe and with a golden sash around his chest. The hairs of his head were white, like white wool, like snow. His eyes were like a flame of fire, his feet were like burnished bronze, refined in a furnace, and his voice was like the roar of many waters. In his right hand he held seven stars, from his mouth came a sharp two-edged sword, and his face was like the sun shining in full strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw him, I fell at his feet as though dead. But he laid his right hand on me, saying, “Fear not, I am the first and the last, and the living one. I died, and behold I am alive forevermore, and I have the keys of Death and Hades.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:12-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear not, O my soul, and think about this. He is the first and the last and the living one, who died and rose again to life, and he is alive forevermore. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, why finally? Why does Paul say finally? We need to look at what came before. And what came before is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about those insolent ones or about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about these true, just, praiseworthy things, O my soul, and pray with thanksgiving, and know that the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your heart and your mind in Christ Jesus! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
