<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>power on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/power/</link>
        <description>Recent content in power on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What child is this?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/what-child-is-this/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/what-child-is-this/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/what-child-is-this/taksh-Ss3bXajj-po-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What child is this?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this broken world need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Ukraine need? And Palestine? And Syria? And South Sudan? And the U.S.? And New Zealand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do the downtrodden and the brokenhearted need? And O my soul, what do you need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is God&amp;rsquo;s rescue plan for this broken world and for each broken heart. But the answer has already come and it came in weakness and frailty and obscurity the form of a little baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Joseph also went up from Galilee, from the town of Nazareth, to Judea, to the city of David, which is called Bethlehem, because he was of the house and lineage of David, to be registered with Mary, his betrothed, who was with child. And while they were there, the time came for her to give birth. And she gave birth to her firstborn son and wrapped him in swaddling cloths and laid him in a manger, because there was no place for them in the inn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 2:4-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an inauspicious start to an incredible, lavish, and costly rescue⸺a couple of nobodies away from home in a busy city with no place to stay, laying this newborn baby down in an animal&amp;rsquo;s food trough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perspective is everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And in the same region there were shepherds out in the field, keeping watch over their flock by night. And an angel of the Lord appeared to them, and the glory of the Lord shone around them, and they were filled with great fear. And the angel said to them, “Fear not, for behold, I bring you good news of great joy that will be for all the people. For unto you is born this day in the city of David a Saviour, who is Christ the Lord. And this will be a sign for you: you will find a baby wrapped in swaddling cloths and lying in a manger.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 2:8-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you marvel at the sheer audacity of sending a helpless baby to be the Saviour of the World, ensure to do so as Mary and not as Zechariah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the angel said to her, “Do not be afraid, Mary, for you have found favour with God. And behold, you will conceive in your womb and bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus. He will be great and will be called the Son of the Most High. And the Lord God will give to him the throne of his father David, and he will reign over the house of Jacob forever, and of his kingdom there will be no end.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Mary said to the angel, “How will this be, since I am a virgin?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the angel answered her &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Mary said, “Behold, I am the servant of the Lord; let it be to me according to your word.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:30-35, 38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is at the same time so similar to and yet so very different from Zechariah&amp;rsquo;s response to a parallel revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the angel said to him, “Do not be afraid, Zechariah, for your prayer has been heard, and your wife Elizabeth will bear you a son, and you shall call his name John. And you will have joy and gladness, and many will rejoice at his birth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Zechariah said to the angel, “How shall I know this? For I am an old man, and my wife is advanced in years.” And the angel answered him, “I am Gabriel. I stand in the presence of God, and I was sent to speak to you and to bring you this good news. And behold, you will be silent and unable to speak until the day that these things take place, because you did not believe my words, which will be fulfilled in their time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:13-14, 18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that Mary&amp;rsquo;s question asked from her surrendered heart sounded to all intents and purposes just like Zechariah&amp;rsquo;s from his doubting heart, but it was in fact so very different. “How will this be?” was asked in faith and obedience, whereas “How shall I know this?” was asked in unbelief and scepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must be Mary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Behold, I am the servant of the Lord; let it be to me according to your word.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in hope and faith and with a surrendered heart, let us ask why and how. Why would the Creator God of the Universe and Lord of All choose such an apparently risky and fragile plan? And how could this helpless baby change everything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitally Jesus was both fully man and fully God, but there is another factor here, and it is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the angel answered her &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For nothing will be impossible with God.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 1:35, 37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this not God demonstrating exactly this, revealing his great power made perfect in weakness? He is absolutely the God of the impossible. O my soul, he is the God of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/impossible/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;your own impossible&lt;/a&gt;. Consider even this one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have a helpless newborn baby and a tyrant king out to kill him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Herod summoned the wise men secretly and ascertained from them what time the star had appeared. And he sent them to Bethlehem, saying, “Go and search diligently for the child, and when you have found him, bring me word, that I too may come and worship him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Herod, when he saw that he had been tricked by the wise men, became furious, and he sent and killed all the male children in Bethlehem and in all that region who were two years old or under, according to the time that he had ascertained from the wise men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 2:7-9, 16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet Mary and Joseph escaped with the baby Jesus to Egypt where they lived for a while as refugees in a foreign land. How was &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; even possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the why is the God of the impossible demonstrating his great power, rescuing and redeeming his creation and the whole of humankind through this little baby. And how? Isaiah tells it and Handel composed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For to us a child is born, to us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder, and his name shall be called Wonderful Counsellor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, Prince of Peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 9:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This little baby would not remain weak and helpless. He was and is the great I Am, Mighty God, one with the Father, everlasting, reigning and ruling in majesty and splendour. The Prince of Peace indeed. Praise him! Praise his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And never was the birth of a baby so anticipated, so eagerly awaited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The people who walked in darkness have seen a great light; those who dwelt in a land of deep darkness, on them has light shone. You have multiplied the nation; you have increased its joy; they rejoice before you as with joy at the harvest, as they are glad when they divide the spoil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 9:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the spoil is divided, &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what child is this? John tells it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through him, and without him was not any thing made that was made. In him was life, and the life was the light of men. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 1:1-5, 14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God the Son, the Creator of the Universe and the one who sustains all things by his powerful word, became flesh, became a little baby, and dwelt among us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that all things were made through him and for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He is the image of the invisible God, the firstborn of all creation. For by him all things were created, in heaven and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities⸺all things were created through him and for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 11:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, marvel at the power and wisdom and goodness and mercy of the God of the impossible, and the rescue and redemption and healing of Jesus Christ who was that little baby and is the Lord of All, and praise him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Cosmic power</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/cosmic-power/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/cosmic-power/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/cosmic-power/42916480792-cd4b5fcfdf-o.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Cosmic power" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most truly overwhelming outworking of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s discover that in the psalmist&amp;rsquo;s song of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; for he is beautiful, and a song of praise is fitting. The LORD builds up Jerusalem; he gathers the outcasts of Israel. He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds. He determines the number of the stars; he gives to all of them their names. Great is our Lord, and abundant in power; his understanding is beyond measure. The LORD lifts up the humble; he casts the wicked to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:1-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall as I &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/praise-the-lord/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;explained to Amy&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;he is beautiful&lt;/em&gt;, the alternative translation given in the ESV is the correct one, the reason why it is good to praise the Lord, why a song of praise is fitting. Just pause and rejoice in that for a moment. Praise the Lord, for he is beautiful! Yes indeed he is, in every way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we praise the infinitely powerful Creator God of the Universe, let&amp;rsquo;s consider for a moment that cosmic power which is his to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a very real danger of feeling overwhelmed by the sheer enormity of the universe he has created. Here in our psalm we read that he determines the number of the stars and he gives to all of them their names. In the creation account we read similarly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God made the two great lights⸺the greater light to rule the day and the lesser light to rule the night⸺and the stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He made the sun and the moon, and by the way, he also made the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something of a by-the-way about the stars in our psalm too. Notice the order in which various praiseworthy attributes are listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He builds up the city of his people; he gathers the outcasts; he binds up the brokenhearted; oh, and by the way, he also determines the number of the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, can you see the remarkable truth here? Let&amp;rsquo;s not be so dazzled by the enormity of the physical universe that we lose sight of what is really on the Lord&amp;rsquo;s heart⸺his beloved ones, and especially among them, the brokenhearted, whom he so tenderly and with great compassion binds up and does his miraculous work of healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s instead be overwhelmed by this then, that the Lord has set his love on undeserving sinners, and especially on the outcast and the downtrodden and the brokenhearted. And furthermore that he works in them and for them with that very same cosmic power⸺a work of rescue and healing and liberation from the bonds of sin and lifting up of the humble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let&amp;rsquo;s remind ourselves of that passage in Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s prophecy from which Jesus read at the beginning of his earthly ministry, for we see there a similar priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he came to Nazareth, where he had been brought up. And as was his custom, he went to the synagogue on the Sabbath day, and he stood up to read. And the scroll of the prophet Isaiah was given to him. He unrolled the scroll and found the place where it was written,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 4:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading directly from Isaiah, as Jesus did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; to proclaim the year of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s favour, and the day of vengeance of our God; to comfort all who mourn; to grant to those who mourn in Zion⸺to give them a beautiful headdress instead of ashes, the oil of gladness instead of mourning, the garment of praise instead of a faint spirit; that they may be called oaks of righteousness, the planting of the LORD, that he may be glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And continuing in Luke&amp;rsquo;s gospel,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he rolled up the scroll and gave it back to the attendant and sat down. And the eyes of all in the synagogue were fixed on him. And he began to say to them, “Today this Scripture has been fulfilled in your hearing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 4:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, let&amp;rsquo;s be overwhelmed that the Creator God of the Universe cares quite so much about his beloved ones, his brokenhearted ones and those that are oppressed, that he sent his only son, Jesus. This was Jesus&amp;rsquo; mission, and it remains so⸺to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; to proclaim the year of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s favour, and to comfort all who mourn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you mourn? Know that the Lord is making beauty from the ashes of your own life. Receive his wonderful comfort and be clothed in his garment of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one more thing to notice here. These oaks of righteousness, the planting of the Lord⸺did you notice who they are? They are in fact these very rescued ones, these liberated captives, these ones with a faint spirit. How is it possible that the bruised and broken and downtrodden become mighty oaks of righteousness in the Kingdom? It is simply because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power in restoration and transforming grace⸺his cosmic power. And we are even told why, that is, why the Lord does this work of rescue and transformation and planting. It is so that he may be glorified. Praise and magnify his holy name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is glorified when his character is revealed and made known to the nations⸺his character which is forgiveness and rescue and steadfast love and faithfulness, as he declared to Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that making the stars was indeed very much of a by-the-way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rest in the arms of your Heavenly Father who binds up the brokenhearted, and receive his rescue and healing and transforming grace! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
