<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>humility on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/humility/</link>
        <description>Recent content in humility on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/humility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Knitting</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/knitting/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/knitting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/knitting/tanaphong-toochinda-WddCult7llk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Knitting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you know about knitting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the Apostle Paul&amp;rsquo;s most earnest desire for the Colossians and for those at Laodicea and for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I want you to know how great a struggle I have for you and for those at Laodicea and for all who have not seen me face to face, that their hearts may be encouraged, being knit together in love, to reach all the riches of full assurance of understanding and the knowledge of God&amp;rsquo;s mystery, which is Christ, in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul desires that hearts may be encouraged by being knit together in love.  So let&amp;rsquo;s think about knitting for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essence of knitting is that the integrity of the whole garment is determined by the integrity of each and every stitch.  Every stitch matters for if any single one fails the whole garment unravels into a tangled and useless mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each and every one matters, and the integrity and well-being of each and every one is essential to the integrity and well-being of the whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not only is it about being knit together, it is about being knit together &lt;em&gt;in love&lt;/em&gt;.  It is only love which can provide stitches of sufficient strength to withstand the trials of life and the attacks of the evil one.  Paul expands upon this in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I therefore, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to walk in a manner worthy of the calling to which you have been called, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; speaking the truth in love, we are to grow up in every way into him who is the head, into Christ, from whom the whole body, joined and held together by every joint with which it is equipped, when each part is working properly, makes the body grow so that it builds itself up in love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:1-2,15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word for held together is the very same as our word for knitting.  The whole body is knit together by each and every joint with which it is equipped, by each and every one, and this is from Christ, so that the body builds itself up in love.  It is entirely love and building up and knitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each part must be working properly.  O my soul, is each part in fact working properly?  Or are some parts neglected or rejected or denied the freedom to function as intended by the Creator?  The body must build itself up in love.  It must! And every stitch must be protected and nourished and cherished. It must!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is Paul&amp;rsquo;s exhortation here quite so earnest and so urgent.  He tells us precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I say this in order that no one may delude you with plausible arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See to it that no one takes you captive by philosophy and empty deceit, according to human tradition, according to the elemental spirits of the world, and not according to Christ. For in him the whole fullness of deity dwells bodily, and you have been filled in him, who is the head of all rule and authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore let no one pass judgment on you in questions of food and drink, or with regard to a festival or a new moon or a Sabbath. These are a shadow of the things to come, but the substance belongs to Christ. Let no-one disqualify you, insisting on asceticism and worship of angels, going on in detail about visions, puffed up without reason by his sensuous mind, and not holding fast to the Head, from whom the whole body, nourished and knit together through its joints and ligaments, grows with a growth that is from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:4,8-10,16-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware!  The danger here is from within the church, and it is real and present.  Beware those who go on about visions, puffed up without reason by self-importance and their sensuous minds.  Beware oh-so-plausible arguments.  Beware those who insist on asceticism.  Beware empty deceit according to human tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will save us from these real and present dangers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk in him, rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christ who saves, and we must be abounding in thanksgiving, for thanksgiving is the great leveller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified by his grace as a gift, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:23-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is thanksgiving that says I am nothing but a recipient of unmerited grace, and yet at the same time this unmerited grace is all I need.  Thank you Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what?  Paul already told us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I therefore, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to walk in a manner worthy of the calling to which you have been called, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let each one walk worthy with the humility that comes from being rescued, with gentleness and patience, bearing with one another in love.  Imagine if we all stuck to our knitting, loving and looking after and building up the body of Christ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, stick to your knitting and love one another! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Together</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/together/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/together/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/together/Titanic_lifeboat.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Together" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you enjoy the favour of the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I mean? I mean would you like him to shine on you and smile on you and bless you abundantly?⸺for that is the favour of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would enjoy that favour then you must stand together with his people and be one with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember me, O LORD, when you show favour to your people; help me when you save them, that I may look upon the prosperity of your chosen ones, that I may rejoice in the gladness of your nation, that I may glory with your inheritance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see the psalmist desiring to count himself among the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people. Help me when you save them, Lord, that we may prosper together. That we may rejoice in gladness together. That we may glory with one another together with your inheritance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to stand with those who are being blessed. But what is the other side of this coin called together?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the psalmist&amp;rsquo;s confession as he stands together with his people in their sin and shame and wretchedness, and counts himself one with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Both we and our fathers have sinned; we have committed iniquity; we have done wickedness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other side of this coin is to stand together with sinners⸺with those who have committed iniquity, who have done wickedness⸺and not to set ourselves apart. For what was Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s confession upon being overwhelmed by the beauty and the holiness and majesty of the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I said: “Woe is me! For I am lost; for I am a man of unclean lips, and I dwell in the midst of a people of unclean lips; for my eyes have seen the King, the LORD of hosts!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sin of his people did not excuse or diminish Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s own in any way, but rather magnified it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But aren&amp;rsquo;t there limits to the sin of our brothers and sisters which we can own as ours? Let&amp;rsquo;s follow the psalmist for an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our fathers, when they were in Egypt, did not consider your wondrous works; they did not remember the abundance of your steadfast love, but rebelled by the sea, at the Red Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus begins another sorry retelling of the shameful failure and ongoing wretchedness of the Israelites as they wandered in the wilderness, both geographically and metaphorically. And equally another wonderful retelling of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness to these reprobates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet he saved them for his name&amp;rsquo;s sake, that he might make known his mighty power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how did his people respond to this unmerited rescue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But they soon forgot his works; they did not wait for his counsel. But they had a wanton craving in the wilderness, and put God to the test in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it just got worse and worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They made a calf in Horeb and worshipped a metal image. They exchanged the glory of God for the image of an ox that eats grass. They forgot God, their Saviour, who had done great things in Egypt, wondrous works in the land of Ham, and awesome deeds by the Red Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:19-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, and then, and then. What a pitiful refrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then they despised the pleasant land, having no faith in his promise. They murmured in their tents, and did not obey the voice of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then they yoked themselves to the Baal of Peor, and ate sacrifices offered to the dead; they provoked the LORD to anger with their deeds, and a plague broke out among them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They did not destroy the peoples, as the LORD commanded them, but they mixed with the nations and learned to do as they did. They served their idols, which became a snare to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:34-36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And was the Lord infinitely patient with his rebellious people? No he was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the anger of the LORD was kindled against his people, and he abhorred his heritage; he gave them into the hand of the nations, so that those who hated them ruled over them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:40-41&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, grieve over this obstinately wayward people, for they are your people. And marvel that the Lord did not finish with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many times he delivered them, but they were rebellious in their purposes and were brought low through their iniquity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:43&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the ongoing cycle, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness towards his ungrateful and unfaithful people, and it remains so today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the context of this sorry retelling of unfaithfulness and wretchedness and shame, marvel that the psalmist continued to stand with his brothers and sisters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Save us, O LORD our God, and gather us from among the nations, that we may give thanks to your holy name and glory in your praise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:47&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Us! The word is us! Save &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;, O Lord! Have mercy on &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified by his grace as a gift, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:23-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And knowing this, there are three things to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is to praise our good and faithful God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Praise the LORD! Oh give thanks to the LORD, for he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is to be overwhelmed by the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power and beauty and goodness and holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who can utter the mighty deeds of the LORD, or declare all his praise?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third is to use these to fuel a life that honours him in every way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are they who observe justice, who do righteousness at all times!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 106:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we must do this together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, stand together with the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people, for they are your people, and worship him together! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Humility before honour</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/humility-before-honour/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/humility-before-honour/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/humility-before-honour/sergio-garcia-peILg94wWd8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Humility before honour" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my Soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you still not enjoying being brushed aside and disregarded? Consider this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before destruction a man&amp;rsquo;s heart is haughty, but humility comes before honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 18:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the original Hebrew the second simply says, humility before honour. How interesting. Humility before honour. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But firstly, before destruction a man&amp;rsquo;s heart is haughty. Haughty is somewhat of an old-fashioned word. What would be a more modern rendition? Conceited. Arrogant. Superior. Full of oneself. Prideful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This then is about the greatest sin of them all: pride. And so the first part of this proverbial couplet is simply pride comes before a fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD preserves the faithful but abundantly repays the one who acts in pride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly did you suppose this repayment to comprise? Did you think it would be less than destruction? Did you think the fall would be anything other than divine judgment? Had you perhaps underestimated the severity of the sin of pride?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Scoffer” is the name of the arrogant, haughty man who acts with arrogant pride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 21:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not suppose that it is a small thing to carry the name of scoffer, nor something easily excused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whoever plans to do evil will be called a schemer. The devising of folly is sin, and the scoffer is an abomination to mankind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 24:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An abomination to mankind no less!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the LORD of hosts has a day against all that is proud and lofty, against all that is lifted up⸺and it shall be brought low;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the haughtiness of man shall be humbled, and the lofty pride of men shall be brought low, and the LORD alone will be exalted in that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 2:12, 17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pride challenges the Lord himself. Do you wonder then that he will not tolerate it? For it displaces the Lord from his throne. It deceives and it defiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [Jesus] said, “What comes out of a person is what defiles him. For from within, out of the heart of man, come evil thoughts, sexual immorality, theft, murder, adultery, coveting, wickedness, deceit, sensuality, envy, slander, pride, foolishness. All these evil things come from within, and they defile a person.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 7:20-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a shocking list, and pride is right there in the thick of it. But what else did Jesus say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are the meek, for they shall inherit the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s return to our proverb in the context of inheriting the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Humility before honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 18:12b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word for honour is &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt;, although this is a word mostly not translated honour. Mostly not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fear of the LORD is instruction in wisdom, and humility comes before honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The reward for humility and fear of the LORD is riches and honour and life.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 22:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One&amp;rsquo;s pride will bring him low, but he who is lowly in spirit will obtain honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 29:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job uses the same word in speaking of what he has received from the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has stripped from me my &lt;em&gt;glory&lt;/em&gt; and taken the crown from my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 19:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As does the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, O LORD, are a shield about me, my &lt;em&gt;glory&lt;/em&gt;, and the lifter of my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at this word &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt;. For far more than honour is it translated glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the LORD said to Moses, “This very thing that you have spoken I will do, for you have found favour in my sight, and I know you by name.” Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.” And Moses quickly bowed his head toward the earth and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:17-18, 34:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at the glory of the Lord and marvel further that this same word &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt; is used for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lift up your heads, O gates! And be lifted up, O ancient doors, that the King of glory may come in. Who is this King of glory? The LORD, strong and mighty, the LORD, mighty in battle! Lift up your heads, O gates! And lift them up, O ancient doors, that the King of glory may come in. Who is this King of glory? The LORD of hosts, he is the King of glory!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 24:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the year that King Uzziah died I saw the Lord sitting upon a throne, high and lifted up; and the train of his robe filled the temple. Above him stood the seraphim. Each had six wings: with two he covered his face, and with two he covered his feet, and with two he flew. And one called to another and said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Holy, holy, holy is the LORD of hosts; the whole earth is full of his glory!”⁠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord will not tolerate the pride that challenges his own exaltation, his own glory, and yet he bestows honour and glory upon the meek and humble⸺glory carried in the same word as his very own!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bestowing of honour is seen so clearly in the echo of the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is high above all nations, and his glory above the heavens! Who is like the LORD our God, who is seated on high, who looks far down on the heavens and the earth? He raises the poor from the dust and lifts the needy from the ash heap, to make them sit with princes, with the princes of his people. He gives the barren woman a home, making her the joyous mother of children. Praise the LORD!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 113:4-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt; which is the glory of the Lord. And the echo is in Hannah&amp;rsquo;s prayer⸺Hannah, that barren woman whose womb was opened by the Lord, making her the joyous mother of Samuel, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s prophet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Hannah prayed and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The LORD makes poor and makes rich; he brings low and he exalts. He raises up the poor from the dust; he lifts the needy from the ash heap to make them sit with princes and inherit a seat of honour. For the pillars of the earth are the LORD&amp;rsquo;s, and on them he has set the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Samuel 2:1a, 7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake. The pillars of the earth are indeed the Lord&amp;rsquo;s. He alone is Creator God, and evermore to be praised. And he alone lifts the needy from the ash heap to make them sit with princes and inherit a seat of honour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be content to live in humility and the fear of the Lord, praising the one who alone is worthy, and know that he alone rewards with honour and glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Locusts</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/locusts/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/locusts/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/locusts/Exodus_10.webp" alt="Featured image of post Locusts" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are those years the locusts have eaten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will restore to you the years that the swarming locust has eaten, the hopper, the destroyer, and the cutter &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:25a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this sound like a wonderful promise of restoration? But what does it mean? To understand those years we must first understand the locusts. So what are the locusts? I have quoted only half a verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will restore to you the years that the swarming locust has eaten, the hopper, the destroyer, and the cutter, my great army, which I sent among you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the words of the Lord, and so these are his own locusts, his great army, which he sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word of the LORD that came to Joel, the son of Pethuel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear this, you elders; give ear, all inhabitants of the land! Has such a thing happened in your days, or in the days of your fathers? Tell your children of it, and let your children tell their children, and their children to another generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the cutting locust left, the swarming locust has eaten. What the swarming locust left, the hopping locust has eaten, and what the hopping locust left, the destroying locust has eaten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 1:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever is going on here clearly was and is of vital importance and must be remembered. Notice the urgent exhortation to pay attention, to tell the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, not to forget even through the generations. We ourselves must not overlook this. It is as relevant today as it was then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn more from Zephaniah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I will utterly sweep away everything from the face of the earth,” declares the LORD. “I will sweep away man and beast; I will sweep away the birds of the heavens and the fish of the sea, and the rubble with the wicked. I will cut off mankind from the face of the earth,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are these wicked ones who have brought down such judgment from the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I will stretch out my hand against Judah and against all the inhabitants of Jerusalem”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the Lord&amp;rsquo;s chosen people, the hitherto recipients of his covenant love. And this is a prophecy of the day of the Lord, that terrible day of judgment and destruction rained down by the Lord on his own people, his beloved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why? Why would this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I will punish the officials and the king&amp;rsquo;s sons and all who array themselves in foreign attire.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s people, his highest and most exalted ones, had become so compromised, so contaminated by the nations. So worldly. So like us in fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“At that time I will search Jerusalem with lamps, and I will punish the men who are complacent, those who say in their hearts, ‘The LORD will not do good, nor will he do ill.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you think this couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen to us? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that thought the very definition of complacency? That the Lord will not do good, nor will he do ill? That everything will just continue to tick along as we all go about our lives? That the extent of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s interest is merely to observe? O my soul, repudiate such thinking. Purge that complacency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then should be done in the face of this day of judgment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be silent before the Lord GOD! For the day of the LORD is near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:7a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you so full of bluster? So full of excuses? So full of self-justification? Be silent! Be silent before the Lord God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seek the LORD, all you humble of the land, who do his just commands; seek righteousness; seek humility; perhaps you may be hidden on the day of the anger of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 2:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must be silent and humble ourselves and seek righteousness and humility. But where may these be found in the midst of all this negligence and self-indulgence and intransigence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John tells us of the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My little children, I am writing these things to you so that you may not sin. But if anyone does sin, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous. He is the propitiation for our sins, and not for ours only but also for the sins of the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 2:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Paul tells us of the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have this mind among yourselves, which is yours in Christ Jesus, who, though he was in the form of God, did not count equality with God a thing to be grasped, but emptied himself, by taking the form of a servant, being born in the likeness of men. And being found in human form, he humbled himself by becoming obedient to the point of death, even death on a cross.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek righteousness and humility. Seek Jesus. Cry out to him for salvation and turn to him so that you may be hidden on that terrible day of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore let us be grateful for receiving a kingdom that cannot be shaken, and thus let us offer to God acceptable worship, with reverence and awe, for our God is a consuming fire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us repent of complacency and brainless triumphalism, and offer to God acceptable worship with reverence and awe, for our God is a consuming fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s something else to notice here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be silent before the Lord GOD! For the day of the LORD is near; the LORD has prepared a sacrifice and consecrated his guests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has indeed prepared a sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Isaac said to his father Abraham, “My father!” And he said, “Here I am, my son.” He said, “Behold, the fire and the wood, but where is the lamb for a burnt offering?” Abraham said, “God will provide for himself the lamb for a burnt offering, my son.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 22:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Christ has entered, not into holy places made with hands, which are copies of the true things, but into heaven itself, now to appear in the presence of God on our behalf. Nor was it to offer himself repeatedly, as the high priest enters the holy places every year with blood not his own, for then he would have had to suffer repeatedly since the foundation of the world. But as it is, he has appeared once for all at the end of the ages to put away sin by the sacrifice of himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 9:24-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only has the Lord prepared the sacrifice of his only Son at such enormous cost, but through him he has also consecrated his guests. O my soul, your own consecration is ongoing, as you are so very aware. Rejoice that it continues and exult with all your heart at the lavish generosity of this restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sing aloud, O daughter of Zion; shout, O Israel! Rejoice and exult with all your heart, O daughter of Jerusalem! The LORD has taken away the judgments against you; he has cleared away your enemies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 3:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And observe how the Lord himself rejoices to see his people returning to him in repentance and humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD your God is in your midst, a mighty one who will save; he will rejoice over you with gladness; he will quiet you by his love; he will exult over you with loud singing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 3:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be quieted by that great Calvary love, rejoice and give thanks to the one who restores those years! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
