<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>expectation on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/expectation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in expectation on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/expectation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>That was yesterday</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/istrfry-marcus-NX0WjgdQl58-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post That was yesterday" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened yesterday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were you hoping for great things? Were you expecting great things? And are you tempted to say, “nothing”? That nothing happened? (You would be so very wrong about that, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that nothing happened yesterday, now what? What will you do now? Where is hope? How can hope survive the passing of yet another day, the unrelenting accumulation of which become inexorable years? How can faith survive this, O my soul? How will this rollercoaster of expectation and disappointment not simply grind you down into the dust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How indeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how. There are three reasons. The first reason is to understand that disappointment is a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointment is a lie because it presupposes failure. But what failure would that be, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Joshua, now old and well advanced in years, passing on some wisdom at the end of his own life to those who would come after him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now I am about to go the way of all the earth, and you know in your hearts and souls, all of you, that not one word has failed of all the good things that the LORD your God promised concerning you. All have come to pass for you; not one of them has failed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not one of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promises had failed, nor has failed, nor will fail. Know that he is faithful and true, O my soul, to all that he has said, and to all that he is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that what you were hoping for yesterday didn&amp;rsquo;t happen, what you were expecting, what you were so committed in faith to receiving, then listen to the Lord himself, speaking through Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me, declaring the end from the beginning and from ancient times things not yet done, saying, ‘My counsel shall stand, and I will accomplish all my purpose,’ calling a bird of prey from the east, the man of my counsel from a far country. I have spoken, and I will bring it to pass; I have purposed, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 46:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sure, there are things not yet done, but there is none like God, declaring the end from the beginning, from ancient times. O my soul, he will do it! He will accomplish all he has purposed! Know that nothing has failed. Trust him still and praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason is because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts. Poured out for you, O my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we have been justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ. Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope, and hope does not put us to shame, because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will have to return another time to rejoicing in our sufferings but for now consider just that final verse, for which the Berean Standard Bible rendition is particularly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And hope does not disappoint us, because God has poured out His love into our hearts through the Holy Spirit, whom He has given us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:5 BSB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope does not disappoint. God himself is both the giver and the one who pours. It is his own great love. He poured out that same love at Calvary, O my soul. Rejoice in hope of the glory of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and final reason is to understand at least something of what did actually happen yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was I hoping for? Isaiah knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Oh that you would rend the heavens and come down, that the mountains might quake at your presence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that the Creator God of the Universe, awesome in power and terrifying in purity but also so very good and kind, would break into this impossible situation, breathing out grace and truth and power into my own life and those around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So did he?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From of old no one has heard or perceived by the ear, no eye has seen a God besides you, who acts for those who wait for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah tells us that the Lord acts. Not that he will act, or even that he did act, but that he acts, in the present tense. He is working right now with great power for those who wait for him. Will you be that, O my soul? Will you continue to be that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is it that he is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habbakuk knows and it cannot be told.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days that you would not believe if told.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonder and be astounded, O my soul, at what the Lord is already doing in your life, and renounce disappointment! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>This is the day!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/robert-lukeman-_RBcxo9AU-U-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post This is the day!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do you expect change will come?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many years spent hoping and trusting, holding on to your promise from the Lord and yet still waiting, are you tempted to give up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you still somehow expect that the Lord will act with great power to fulfil that promise? And when exactly do you expect that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one answer which honours the Lord and that is today. You must continue to expect it and you must expect it today! It is imperative that you do so. Your very faith depends upon it. Your life and health and strength depend upon it. How else could you live a life that honours him, other than in complete trust and dependence upon him, and other than in expectation of the imminent outworking of his great power in your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who promised is indeed faithful. His very name is Faithful and True (Rev 19:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is it quite so important to hold fast to this hope, this expectation of imminent fulfilment, without wavering?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the midst of a spiritual battle and the fighting is fierce. To expect anything other than imminent fulfilment would open the door to doubt ⸺that doubt which is so ready to creep in and steal away hope and joy and expectation. That doubt which would cause all to unravel and expose the tattered remains of a faith which once was. That doubt which must be resisted with all strength. Be steadfast, O my soul! Cry out to the Faithful One, Lord I believe! Help my unbelief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Ahab sent to all the people of Israel and gathered the prophets together at Mount Carmel. And Elijah came near to all the people and said, “How long will you go limping between two different opinions? If the LORD is God, follow him; but if Baal, then follow him.” And the people did not answer him a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they took the bull that was given them, and they prepared it and called upon the name of Baal from morning until noon, saying, “O Baal, answer us!” But there was no voice, and no one answered. And they limped around the altar that they had made. And at noon Elijah mocked them, saying, “Cry aloud, for he is a god. Either he is musing, or he is relieving himself, or he is on a journey, or perhaps he is asleep and must be awakened.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:20-21, 26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you tempted to such thoughts while you wait on the living God, the God of your life? Repudiate them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And at the time of the offering of the oblation, Elijah the prophet came near and said, “O LORD, God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let it be known this day that you are God in Israel, and that I am your servant, and that I have done all these things at your word. Answer me, O LORD, answer me, that this people may know that you, O LORD, are God, and that you have turned their hearts back.” Then the fire of the LORD fell and consumed the burnt offering and the wood and the stones and the dust, and licked up the water that was in the trench. And when all the people saw it, they fell on their faces and said, “The LORD, he is God; the LORD, he is God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:36-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord, he is God! Praise him, O my soul!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s answer to our most earnest praying, the outworking of his mighty strength in our lives to fulfil all that he has promised, is that all may know that the Lord, he is God! And his grace and kindness is that you, O my soul, may know it. Expect it today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our experience of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power being outworked in our lives is limited only by our faith to believe it, our faith to receive it. This is why it is quite so important that we do not hold back in expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And as Jesus passed on from there, two blind men followed him, crying aloud, “Have mercy on us, Son of David.” When he entered the house, the blind men came to him, and Jesus said to them, “Do you believe that I am able to do this?” They said to him, “Yes, Lord.” Then he touched their eyes, saying, “According to your faith be it done to you.” And their eyes were opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 9:27-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you believe that he is able to do this? According to your faith be it done to you. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s yet more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him. Whoever believes in him is not condemned, but whoever does not believe is condemned already, because he has not believed in the name of the only Son of God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you dare to believe, O my soul, of the only Son of God. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the day that the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the day, O my soul! Expect great things in it! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
