<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>trust on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/trust/</link>
        <description>Recent content in trust on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/trust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Through the fire</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/through-the-fire/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/through-the-fire/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/through-the-fire/kilauea-summit-eruption.png" alt="Featured image of post Through the fire" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you understood what “through the fire” means?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am of course referring to that uplifting song, The Goodness of God, which is addressed directly to the Lord. The chorus asserts “all my life you have been faithful”, and verse two, “you have led me through the fire”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have all who cherish this song really understood what this means? Through does not mean out of without first into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would a faithful God lead me into the fire? And since this is just a song we have to ask, does Scripture even support this idea?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the word of the Lord through Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For my name&amp;rsquo;s sake I defer my anger; for the sake of my praise I restrain it for you, that I may not cut you off. Behold, I have refined you, but not as silver; I have tried you in the furnace of affliction. For my own sake, for my own sake, I do it, for how should my name be profaned? My glory I will not give to another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 48:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are these whom the Lord has refined in the furnace of affliction? Isaiah tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hear this, O house of Jacob, who are called by the name of Israel, and who came from the waters of Judah, who swear by the name of the LORD and confess the God of Israel, but not in truth or right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 48:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the Israelites, God&amp;rsquo;s chosen people, who confess his name, but crucially &lt;em&gt;not in truth or right&lt;/em&gt;. They are in fact hypocrites, lacking integrity, lacking honesty, lacking righteousness. And so the Lord refines them in the furnace of affliction. And why? For his own sake and for his own glory. Otherwise how would his name be profaned, dishonoured by these hypocrites professing his name in falsehood?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But notice how the Lord restrains his anger at these hypocrites. He holds it back for the sake of his praise and instead he chooses to refine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was this furnace of affliction? It was the eighteen month siege of Jerusalem by Nebuchadnezzar followed by the exile of Judah to Babylon, truly &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the grimmest of times&lt;/a&gt;. Into the fire indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And was that enough? Was that to be the end of the refining? No it was not. Upon their return to Jerusalem after the Babylonian exile there is a further prophecy from Zechariah, again of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own chosen people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the whole land, declares the LORD, two thirds shall be cut off and perish, and one third shall be left alive. And I will put this third into the fire, and refine them as one refines silver, and test them as gold is tested. They will call upon my name, and I will answer them. I will say, ‘They are my people’; and they will say, ‘The LORD is my God.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zechariah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zechariah 13:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two thirds perished and the remaining one third was to be put into the fire by the hand of the Lord. And then what? The Lord will say, ‘They are my people’; and they will say, ‘The LORD is my God.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we must endeavour to understand the two different kinds of refining, one which is not as silver and one which is. This is certainly difficult to understand and it seems to me to be a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;hard teaching&lt;/a&gt; indeed. But we must not shy away from such verses! The commentaries differ and so this must be approached with humility. And yet surely we must wrestle with these hard teachings with both intellectual integrity and reverence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When silver is refined, the whole of it is purified and all the silver is retained. Dross is removed from throughout and from throughout pure silver is retrieved. Nothing is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then is a refining not as silver? I believe it may be a separation, as of sheep and goats. Not all are accepted. Some are rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people to whom Isaiah prophesied were to be refined but not as silver. Later, after the return from the exile, two thirds perished. Rejected. Discarded. One third remained to be further refined, and this time as silver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my soul, cry out to the Lord lest you be refined but not as silver, for both kinds of refining remain. Listen to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the Son of Man comes in his glory, and all the angels with him, then he will sit on his glorious throne. Before him will be gathered all the nations, and he will separate people one from another as a shepherd separates the sheep from the goats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:31-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, there is to be such a separation. Pray for mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he will place the sheep on his right, but the goats on the left. Then the King will say to those on his right, ‘Come, you who are blessed by my Father, inherit the kingdom prepared for you from the foundation of the world. For I was hungry and you gave me food, I was thirsty and you gave me drink, I was a stranger and you welcomed me, I was naked and you clothed me, I was sick and you visited me, I was in prison and you came to me.’ Then the righteous will answer him, saying, ‘Lord, when did we see you hungry and feed you, or thirsty and give you drink? And when did we see you a stranger and welcome you, or naked and clothe you? And when did we see you sick or in prison and visit you?’ And the King will answer them, ‘Truly, I say to you, as you did it to one of the least of these my brothers, you did it to me.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:33-40&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides praying for mercy you must be sure to love and care for the least. For as you do to each of these you do to Jesus himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he will say to those on his left, ‘Depart from me, you cursed, into the eternal fire prepared for the devil and his angels. For I was hungry and you gave me no food, I was thirsty and you gave me no drink, I was a stranger and you did not welcome me, naked and you did not clothe me, sick and in prison and you did not visit me.’ Then they also will answer, saying, ‘Lord, when did we see you hungry or thirsty or a stranger or naked or sick or in prison, and did not minister to you?’ Then he will answer them, saying, ‘Truly, I say to you, as you did not do it to one of the least of these, you did not do it to me.’ And these will go away into eternal punishment, but the righteous into eternal life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 25:41-46&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; warning in the Sermon on the Mount was both urgent and stark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but the one who does the will of my Father who is in heaven. On that day many will say to me, ‘Lord, Lord, did we not prophesy in your name, and cast out demons in your name, and do many mighty works in your name?’ And then will I declare to them, ‘I never knew you; depart from me, you workers of lawlessness.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cry out to the Lord for mercy, love him with all of your heart, and trust him in everything. And know that just as he leads into the fire, he also leads out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you, O God, have tested us; you have tried us as silver is tried. You brought us into the net; you laid a crushing burden on our backs; you let men ride over our heads; we went through fire and through water; yet you have brought us out to a place of abundance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 66:10-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we see both into and out of. Truly through the fire and out to a place of abundance. Do not forget the words of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 10:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, trust the Lord, knowing that if he leads you into the fire he does indeed know what he is doing, and it is for his praise and his glory. May the name of the Lord be praised! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Blessed in the waiting</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/blessed-in-the-waiting/49820769116_8868b8d012_o.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blessed in the waiting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the hardest thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, what is the hardest thing to endure?  That which leads you to think you have been forgotten by the Lord and he has withdrawn himself? That which is the loneliest path to walk? That which keeps you in sorrow throughout the day? That which makes you cry out with that most earnest and desperate question, how long, O Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it not waiting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How long, O LORD? Will you forget me forever? How long will you hide your face from me? How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day? How long shall my enemy be exalted over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does not that waiting time seem like death or defeat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death, lest my enemy say, “I have prevailed over him,” lest my foes rejoice because I am shaken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That waiting time can be unspeakably awful, seemingly almost too hard to bear. And isn&amp;rsquo;t it all such a terrible waste of time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to notice something. O my soul, you must notice quite how much waiting is done by those in whom and through whom the Lord does great works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses waited for forty years. In the wilderness. Tending sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph waited for more than ten. In prison. Apparently forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus himself waited thirty years. In obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be that somehow the waiting time is when the Lord does his most important work of preparation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what happened at the end of Moses&amp;rsquo; waiting time, his forty years in the wilderness of Midian, that apparently wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said, “I have surely seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt and have heard their cry because of their taskmasters. I know their sufferings, and I have come down to deliver them out of the hand of the Egyptians and to bring them up out of that land to a good and broad land, a land flowing with milk and honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Come, I will send you to Pharaoh that you may bring my people, the children of Israel, out of Egypt.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:7-8, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally Moses was ready to be used by the Lord for this great task. How do we know that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But Moses said to God, “Who am I that I should go to Pharaoh and bring the children of Israel out of Egypt?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 3:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses had become nothing. He had died to self. It had taken forty years, because there had previously been so much pride in his heart. He had previously been so full of Moses, so pleased with himself. And now he regarded himself as nothing at all. But he wasn&amp;rsquo;t. He was finally ready to be used greatly by the Lord. And he was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Joseph? After more than ten years in prison, he had to wait yet another seven before the Lord used him to rescue the people of Israel from famine in the land of Canaan. What was his testimony then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before the year of famine came, two sons were born to Joseph. Asenath, the daughter of Potiphera priest of On, bore them to him. Joseph called the name of the firstborn Manasseh. “For,” he said, “God has made me forget all my hardship and all my father&amp;rsquo;s house.” The name of the second he called Ephraim, “For God has made me fruitful in the land of my affliction.”⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 41:50-52&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, praise the Lord for his faithfulness to Joseph, and rest in that same faithfulness. He knows precisely what he is doing, and all his paths are steadfast love and faithfulness. He takes the years that are required, and those years are not wasted. Rather they are the time of preparation and meticulous restoration and transforming grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know how a diamond is formed? Under intense pressure and heat and a billion years of waiting. Are those wasted years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jesus? Even as a twelve year old he displayed such understanding. Do you not think he would have wanted to heal the sick and the brokenhearted and rescue the lost when he was seventeen? When he was twenty-three? When he was twenty-eight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own waiting time know that Jesus understands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since then we have a great high priest who has passed through the heavens, Jesus, the Son of God, let us hold fast our confession. For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but one who in every respect has been tempted as we are, yet without sin. Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 4:14-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the greatest temptation in the waiting time? Is it not to doubt the goodness and faithfulness and sufficiency of God? Repent of those doubts and trust the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did you notice that question which was asked four times by the psalmist and still not answered? How long O Lord? How long? This is the most unanswered question, and painfully so. But what is the psalmist really asking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider and answer me, O LORD my God; light up my eyes, lest I sleep the sleep of death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not really an answer to his question that the psalmist is seeking. It is the answer which is the presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notice too how this answer is received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have trusted in your steadfast love; my heart shall rejoice in your salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own waiting time you must trust in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love. And here is trust. It is to assert and to dwell in the wisdom and kindness and faithfulness and sufficiency of the Lord &lt;em&gt;right in the middle of that painful longing&lt;/em&gt;. Right there in the middle of the waiting is the only opportunity to trust. So do that, and rejoice in his salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will sing to the LORD, because he has dealt bountifully with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 13:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, sing to the Lord, because he has already dealt bountifully with you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The turning point</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/Fotos_del_Gran_Canaria_2010_PWA_Pozo_Izquierdo_Grand_Prix.Santa_Lucia.Gran_Canaria_%284778010692%29.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The turning point" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long does it take to get from clinging on in the dust despairing of life itself to running in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commandments having had one&amp;rsquo;s heart set free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the answer is seven verses. Seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to the dust; give me life according to your word! When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes! Make me understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your wondrous works. My soul melts away for sorrow; strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me and graciously teach me your law! I have chosen the way of faithfulness; I set your rules before me. I cling to your testimonies, O LORD; let me not be put to shame! I will run in the way of your commandments for you set my heart free!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:25-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth that last verse is in the future tense, and the mainline translation is “when you enlarge my heart”. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is going on here that leads to such a turnaround?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul melts away for sorrow. Do you know what that is like? To live with such vulnerability in that place right on the edge of crumpling into a heap and sobbing uncontrollably? The place of clinging on when all strength is gone? The place of crying out for life itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some heart-cries here for the Lord to act with compassion and great power: Give me life according to your word! Make me understand the way of your precepts! Strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me! But these in and of themselves are not the turning point. The turning point comes next and it is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have chosen the way of faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the turning point. In weakness and in sorrow, clinging on in the dust, with courage and determination the psalmist chooses the way of faithfulness. Everything follows from this. O my soul, choose the way of faithfulness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s be clear about whose faithfulness this is. Recall the Lord&amp;rsquo;s introduction of himself to Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses said to the LORD, “See, you say to me, ‘Bring up this people,’ but you have not let me know whom you will send with me. Yet you have said, ‘I know you by name, and you have also found favour in my sight.’ Now therefore, if I have found favour in your sight, please show me now your ways, that I may know you in order to find favour in your sight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:12-13, 18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Lord, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of faithfulness is the way of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness. So what does it mean to choose this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vindicate me, O LORD, for I have walked in my integrity, and I have trusted in the LORD without wavering. Prove me, O LORD, and try me; test my heart and my mind. For your steadfast love is before my eyes, and I walk in your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 26:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To choose the way of faithfulness and to walk in it is to trust in the Lord without wavering. It is to rely on him whatever else is happening, reminding oneself of his steadfast love. Prove me, O Lord, and try me. Know that I do not doubt you. I do not doubt your goodness and your mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what do you suppose is this proving? This trying? This testing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to see beyond current circumstances with eyes of faith, beyond current suffering, to assert with the psalmist out of the darkest valley, out of the deepest sorrow, out of the most wrenching pain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I know, O LORD, that your rules are righteous, and that in faithfulness you have afflicted me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:75&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to assert confidence in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness and to wait upon him, trusting and not doubting. Beyond the point of understanding, beyond the point of being able to see is where trust is tried, tested, and proven. And in this time of testing, this waiting time, it is to walk in one&amp;rsquo;s integrity, keeping covenant with the Holy One, surrendering all to him as an act of worship, perhaps in tears and bewilderment, but surrendering nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what must one do while walking in this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I set your rules before me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your heart is breaking, set his rules before you and walk in them, and know this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the paths of the LORD are steadfast love and faithfulness, for those who keep his covenant and his testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be sure to keep his covenant and his testimonies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now what about that future tense of the running?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will run in the way of your commandments when you enlarge my heart!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is breaking and I simply lack the capacity for this. How can I endure this waiting time? My strength is almost gone. But the Lord himself enlarges my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These sterile and barren bodies of ours are yearning for full deliverance. That is why waiting does not diminish us, any more than waiting diminishes a pregnant mother. We are enlarged in the waiting. We, of course, don’t see what is enlarging us. But the longer we wait, the larger we become, and the more joyful our expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:23-25 MSG&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will run, O my soul, I will! I will run in the way of his commandments, trusting and not doubting. I choose the way of faithfulness. I choose to trust the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, trust in the Lord with all your heart and choose the way of his steadfast love and faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The trust test</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/guzman-barquin-Qd688l1yDOI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The trust test" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is it to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I say trust, I mean completely depend upon him, fully committed, with no way out and no room for doubt. No wavering. No second guessing. None at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said &amp;hellip; “Do not fear, only believe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 5:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such trust is life and health and strength. Why would anyone not live like this? And yet many do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall with me the sorry saga of the Israelites failing to trust the Lord, their ongoing enslavement to fear and uncertainty and doubt. And recall too the Lord&amp;rsquo;s uncompromising response, his righteous anger burning against them, his chosen people, his beloved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What reason did the Israelites have to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the sight of their fathers he performed wonders in the land of Egypt, in the fields of Zoan. He divided the sea and let them pass through it, and made the waters stand like a heap. In the daytime he led them with a cloud, and all the night with a fiery light. He split rocks in the wilderness and gave them drink abundantly as from the deep. He made streams come out of the rock and caused waters to flow down like rivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:12-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the God who miraculously delivered his people from slavery in Egypt, parting the waters of the Red Sea so they could pass safely. And led them through the desert, miraculously guiding them and remaining with them. And slaked their thirst in the desert, again, miraculously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he fed them with manna from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Moses, “Behold, I am about to rain bread from heaven for you, and the people shall go out and gather a day&amp;rsquo;s portion every day, that I may test them, whether they will walk in my law or not.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 16:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was the test. This is the trust test. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that the Israelites faced time and again. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that we ourselves face time and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how did they do, those Israelites, those chosen people, those beloved ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They forgot his works and the wonders that he had shown them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They forgot all the reasons they had to trust him! Their earlier fear of the Lord and belief in him was so feeble it had simply evaporated like the morning mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet they sinned still more against him, rebelling against the Most High in the desert. They tested God in their heart by demanding the food they craved. They spoke against God, saying, “Can God spread a table in the wilderness? He struck the rock so that water gushed out and streams overflowed. Can he also give bread or provide meat for his people?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:17-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the sneering doubt here, the sheer contempt for their provider, the complete absence of trust? O my soul, be appalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, when the LORD heard, he was full of wrath; a fire was kindled against Jacob; his anger rose against Israel, because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not want you to be unaware, brothers, that our fathers were all under the cloud, and all passed through the sea, and all were baptized into Moses in the cloud and in the sea, and all ate the same spiritual food, and all drank the same spiritual drink. For they drank from the spiritual Rock that followed them, and the Rock was Christ. Nevertheless, with most of them God was not pleased, for they were overthrown in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They drank from the Rock which was Christ no less and yet they failed the trust test. Overthrown means struck down. In judgment for their lack of trust most of them were struck down by the Lord, their hitherto protector and provider, the Faithful One. Most of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The anger of God rose against them, and he killed the strongest of them and laid low the young men of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how important it is to trust, to believe, to depend upon the Lord without wavering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of our own trust test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even when things are very dark indeed you must trust the Lord and depend upon him relentlessly. He is faithful and true. Never doubt that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who among you fears the LORD and obeys the voice of his servant? Let him who walks in darkness and has no light trust in the name of the LORD and rely on his God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 50:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is tested when our lives are at stake, when our hearts are breaking, when things are entirely beyond us and all we can do is depend upon the Lord, upon his faithfulness to all that he has promised and to all that he is, when the way ahead is unseeable. But without the unseeable there can be no faith! O my soul, will you trust him then? Will you trust him now? Will you continue to trust him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now hope that is seen is not hope. For who hopes for what he sees? But if we hope for what we do not see, we wait for it with patience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in this waiting time of unseeing are you tempted to doubt? Are you tempted to despair? Are you tempted to run ahead of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will in your own strength? Resist! You must resist! Hold on to what is true. Hold on to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No temptation has overtaken you that is not common to man. God is faithful, and he will not let you be tempted beyond your ability, but with the temptation he will also provide the way of escape, that you may be able to endure it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can endure this, O my soul. Repudiate doubt and all that drags you down, and trust him. Trust him! You must endure with steadfast faith, believing and not doubting. Trust Jesus, whose name is Faithful and True!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The penalty for failing the truth test is severe, as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen. For standing firm, however, there are two stupendous prizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in him, O my soul, and he will act!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD’s delight is in those who fear him, those who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing this, by walking this path of trust and dependence and unwavering hope in him, waiting with patience, you can delight our Heavenly Father. You can delight him! What more motivation could you have to choose to trust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 15:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, put all your hope in his unfailing love and trust in the faithfulness of your Heavenly Father, and so delight him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
