<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>trust on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/trust/</link>
        <description>Recent content in trust on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/trust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The turning point</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/Fotos_del_Gran_Canaria_2010_PWA_Pozo_Izquierdo_Grand_Prix.Santa_Lucia.Gran_Canaria_%284778010692%29.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The turning point" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long does it take to get from clinging on in the dust despairing of life itself to running in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commandments having had one&amp;rsquo;s heart set free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the answer is seven verses. Seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to the dust; give me life according to your word! When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes! Make me understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your wondrous works. My soul melts away for sorrow; strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me and graciously teach me your law! I have chosen the way of faithfulness; I set your rules before me. I cling to your testimonies, O LORD; let me not be put to shame! I will run in the way of your commandments for you set my heart free!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:25-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth that last verse is in the future tense, and the mainline translation is “when you enlarge my heart”. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is going on here that leads to such a turnaround?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul melts away for sorrow. Do you know what that is like? To live with such vulnerability in that place right on the edge of crumpling into a heap and sobbing uncontrollably? The place of clinging on when all strength is gone? The place of crying out for life itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some heart-cries here for the Lord to act with compassion and great power: Give me life according to your word! Make me understand the way of your precepts! Strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me! But these in and of themselves are not the turning point. The turning point comes next and it is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have chosen the way of faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the turning point. In weakness and in sorrow, clinging on in the dust, with courage and determination the psalmist chooses the way of faithfulness. Everything follows from this. O my soul, choose the way of faithfulness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s be clear about whose faithfulness this is. Recall the Lord&amp;rsquo;s introduction of himself to Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses said to the LORD, “See, you say to me, ‘Bring up this people,’ but you have not let me know whom you will send with me. Yet you have said, ‘I know you by name, and you have also found favour in my sight.’ Now therefore, if I have found favour in your sight, please show me now your ways, that I may know you in order to find favour in your sight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:12-13, 18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Lord, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of faithfulness is the way of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness. So what does it mean to choose this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vindicate me, O LORD, for I have walked in my integrity, and I have trusted in the LORD without wavering. Prove me, O LORD, and try me; test my heart and my mind. For your steadfast love is before my eyes, and I walk in your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 26:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To choose the way of faithfulness and to walk in it is to trust in the Lord without wavering. It is to rely on him whatever else is happening, reminding oneself of his steadfast love. Prove me, O Lord, and try me. Know that I do not doubt you. I do not doubt your goodness and your mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what do you suppose is this proving? This trying? This testing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to see beyond current circumstances with eyes of faith, beyond current suffering, to assert with the psalmist out of the darkest valley, out of the deepest sorrow, out of the most wrenching pain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I know, O LORD, that your rules are righteous, and that in faithfulness you have afflicted me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:75&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to assert confidence in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness and to wait upon him, trusting and not doubting. Beyond the point of understanding, beyond the point of being able to see is where trust is tried, tested, and proven. And in this time of testing, this waiting time, it is to walk in one&amp;rsquo;s integrity, keeping covenant with the Holy One, surrendering all to him as an act of worship, perhaps in tears and bewilderment, but surrendering nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what must one do while walking in this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I set your rules before me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your heart is breaking, set his rules before you and walk in them, and know this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the paths of the LORD are steadfast love and faithfulness, for those who keep his covenant and his testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be sure to keep his covenant and his testimonies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now what about that future tense of the running?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will run in the way of your commandments when you enlarge my heart!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is breaking and I simply lack the capacity for this. How can I endure this waiting time? My strength is almost gone. But the Lord himself enlarges my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These sterile and barren bodies of ours are yearning for full deliverance. That is why waiting does not diminish us, any more than waiting diminishes a pregnant mother. We are enlarged in the waiting. We, of course, don’t see what is enlarging us. But the longer we wait, the larger we become, and the more joyful our expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:23-25 MSG&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will run, O my soul, I will! I will run in the way of his commandments, trusting and not doubting. I choose the way of faithfulness. I choose to trust the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, trust in the Lord with all your heart and choose the way of his steadfast love and faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The trust test</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/guzman-barquin-Qd688l1yDOI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The trust test" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is it to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I say trust, I mean completely depend upon him, fully committed, with no way out and no room for doubt. No wavering. No second guessing. None at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said &amp;hellip; “Do not fear, only believe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 5:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such trust is life and health and strength. Why would anyone not live like this? And yet many do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall with me the sorry saga of the Israelites failing to trust the Lord, their ongoing enslavement to fear and uncertainty and doubt. And recall too the Lord&amp;rsquo;s uncompromising response, his righteous anger burning against them, his chosen people, his beloved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What reason did the Israelites have to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the sight of their fathers he performed wonders in the land of Egypt, in the fields of Zoan. He divided the sea and let them pass through it, and made the waters stand like a heap. In the daytime he led them with a cloud, and all the night with a fiery light. He split rocks in the wilderness and gave them drink abundantly as from the deep. He made streams come out of the rock and caused waters to flow down like rivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:12-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the God who miraculously delivered his people from slavery in Egypt, parting the waters of the Red Sea so they could pass safely. And led them through the desert, miraculously guiding them and remaining with them. And slaked their thirst in the desert, again, miraculously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he fed them with manna from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Moses, “Behold, I am about to rain bread from heaven for you, and the people shall go out and gather a day&amp;rsquo;s portion every day, that I may test them, whether they will walk in my law or not.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 16:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was the test. This is the trust test. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that the Israelites faced time and again. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that we ourselves face time and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how did they do, those Israelites, those chosen people, those beloved ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They forgot his works and the wonders that he had shown them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They forgot all the reasons they had to trust him! Their earlier fear of the Lord and belief in him was so feeble it had simply evaporated like the morning mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet they sinned still more against him, rebelling against the Most High in the desert. They tested God in their heart by demanding the food they craved. They spoke against God, saying, “Can God spread a table in the wilderness? He struck the rock so that water gushed out and streams overflowed. Can he also give bread or provide meat for his people?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:17-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the sneering doubt here, the sheer contempt for their provider, the complete absence of trust? O my soul, be appalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, when the LORD heard, he was full of wrath; a fire was kindled against Jacob; his anger rose against Israel, because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not want you to be unaware, brothers, that our fathers were all under the cloud, and all passed through the sea, and all were baptized into Moses in the cloud and in the sea, and all ate the same spiritual food, and all drank the same spiritual drink. For they drank from the spiritual Rock that followed them, and the Rock was Christ. Nevertheless, with most of them God was not pleased, for they were overthrown in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They drank from the Rock which was Christ no less and yet they failed the trust test. Overthrown means struck down. In judgment for their lack of trust most of them were struck down by the Lord, their hitherto protector and provider, the Faithful One. Most of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The anger of God rose against them, and he killed the strongest of them and laid low the young men of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how important it is to trust, to believe, to depend upon the Lord without wavering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of our own trust test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even when things are very dark indeed you must trust the Lord and depend upon him relentlessly. He is faithful and true. Never doubt that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who among you fears the LORD and obeys the voice of his servant? Let him who walks in darkness and has no light trust in the name of the LORD and rely on his God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 50:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is tested when our lives are at stake, when our hearts are breaking, when things are entirely beyond us and all we can do is depend upon the Lord, upon his faithfulness to all that he has promised and to all that he is, when the way ahead is unseeable. But without the unseeable there can be no faith! O my soul, will you trust him then? Will you trust him now? Will you continue to trust him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now hope that is seen is not hope. For who hopes for what he sees? But if we hope for what we do not see, we wait for it with patience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in this waiting time of unseeing are you tempted to doubt? Are you tempted to despair? Are you tempted to run ahead of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will in your own strength? Resist! You must resist! Hold on to what is true. Hold on to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No temptation has overtaken you that is not common to man. God is faithful, and he will not let you be tempted beyond your ability, but with the temptation he will also provide the way of escape, that you may be able to endure it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can endure this, O my soul. Repudiate doubt and all that drags you down, and trust him. Trust him! You must endure with steadfast faith, believing and not doubting. Trust Jesus, whose name is Faithful and True!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The penalty for failing the truth test is severe, as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen. For standing firm, however, there are two stupendous prizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in him, O my soul, and he will act!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD’s delight is in those who fear him, those who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing this, by walking this path of trust and dependence and unwavering hope in him, waiting with patience, you can delight our Heavenly Father. You can delight him! What more motivation could you have to choose to trust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 15:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, put all your hope in his unfailing love and trust in the faithfulness of your Heavenly Father, and so delight him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
