<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>mystery on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/mystery/</link>
        <description>Recent content in mystery on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/mystery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The things that are revealed</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-things-that-are-revealed/vladimir-soares-3fer5_PzDkM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The things that are revealed" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When is a mystery not a mystery? Why, when it has been revealed of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider just what has been revealed and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically on this Good Friday I want to consider the revelation of the mystery of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will, according to his purpose, from my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/desert-island/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;desert island&lt;/a&gt; chapter of the Bible. And of course it is all and entirely about Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of our trespasses, according to the riches of his grace, which he lavished upon us, in all wisdom and insight making known to us the mystery of his will, according to his purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time, to unite all things in him, things in heaven and things on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s unpack this slowly and carefully, for the words are so familiar we are at risk of progressing past them without really noticing what they&amp;rsquo;re even saying, when in fact we should again be completely overwhelmed by the goodness and kindness and sovereignty and justice of the Father, and by the riches of his grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jesus we have redemption. Thayer defines redemption as a releasing effected by payment of a ransom. So we must remind ourselves from what we have been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you were dead in the trespasses and sins in which you once walked, following the course of this world, following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience⸺among whom we all once lived in the passions of our flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind, and were by nature children of wrath, like the rest of mankind.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was dead in my trespasses and sins, and this was the norm as I merely followed the course of this world along with several billion others. How ironic that those who live in the passions of their flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind thinking they are free to do so are in fact slaves to sin, in bondage, children of wrath by their very nature, like the whole of mankind. We cannot understand the magnitude of this redemption⸺this release⸺without first understanding the sheer wretchedness and utter hopelessness of the previous state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was more wretched and more hopeless even than that. I was obliviously following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience. Satan has such a hold on those sometimes seen merely as worldly, and so many remain in ignorance of this. It is entirely a spiritual battle, and without Christ the battle is hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are not without Christ! And realising this and the magnitude of the rescue, how can humble gratitude not come flooding into our hearts, and love for our wonderful Saviour? And worship and adoration of our Heavenly Father whose purpose this is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was the ransom that was paid to release us from that previous state? It was the blood of the Lamb, the very Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they brought [Jesus] to the place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they crucified him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the sixth hour had come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour. And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, “Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?” which means, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:22,24a,33-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold the only Son of God crying out in anguish, forsaken by the Father who turned his face away from his only and most beloved Son. And you and I both know the reason why, the answer to Jesus&amp;rsquo; most desperate question. We know it only because in all wisdom and insight our Heavenly Father has made known to us the mystery of his will. This is no secret⸺it has been revealed to us according the riches of his grace. Jesus was forsaken on that cross so that we may not be. The debt that he paid was entirely ours. Our redemption is through the blood of the Lamb, poured out at Calvary for the forgiveness of sins, such a costly sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father turned his face away from his beloved Son precisely so that he could turn it towards us, previously miserable, hopeless and helpless sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was all according to God&amp;rsquo;s purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time. So it&amp;rsquo;s worth asking when he did this. When exactly did he set forth this plan? Behold! It was right at the beginning!  Only moments after sin first came into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD God said to the serpent, “Because you have done this, cursed are you above all livestock and above all beasts of the field; on your belly you shall go, and dust you shall eat all the days of your life. I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rescue was planned so far ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In him we have obtained an inheritance, having been predestined according to the purpose of him who works all things according to the counsel of his will, so that we who were the first to hope in Christ might be to the praise of his glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of the fullness of time? Yet more revelation, this time through John the Apostle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw an angel coming down from heaven, holding in his hand the key to the bottomless pit and a great chain. And he seized the dragon, that ancient serpent, who is the devil and Satan, and bound him for a thousand years, and threw him into the pit, and shut it and sealed it over him, so that he might not deceive the nations any longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 20:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But finally, we must remember why it is that these things are revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apostle Paul expands upon this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Heavenly Father chose us in him before the foundation of the world that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this we must do, out of gratitude and adoration for our wonderful Saviour, as an act of worship, and in the power and grace of our risen Lord Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still the real mystery remains. Why would he do this? Why would the Creator God of the Universe set his love upon what is unlovely, those dead in trespasses and sins, at such great cost? We cannot fathom this. We can only thank and praise and worship and adore the one who made it so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, this mystery is revealed and yet remains. Worship and adore its divine author! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The problem with the parables</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-problem-with-the-parables/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-problem-with-the-parables/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-problem-with-the-parables/dev-asangbam-sJipHSttNXo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The problem with the parables" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t the parable of the persistent widow just so very uncomfortable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he told them a parable to the effect that they ought always to pray and not lose heart. He said, “In a certain city there was a judge who neither feared God nor respected man. And there was a widow in that city who kept coming to him and saying, ‘Give me justice against my adversary.’ For a while he refused, but afterward he said to himself, ‘Though I neither fear God nor respect man, yet because this widow keeps bothering me, I will give her justice, so that she will not beat me down by her continual coming.’” And the Lord said, “Hear what the unrighteous judge says. And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? I tell you, he will give justice to them speedily. Nevertheless, when the Son of Man comes, will he find faith on earth?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:1-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was a judge who neither feared God nor respected man, who only gave the widow what she was asking for to stop her bothering him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke tells us precisely why Jesus told this parable, that we should persist in prayer and not lose heart. The parable provides insight into this. The persistent widow is me, crying out to God day and night, and the unrighteous judge is God himself⸺Father, Creator, Lord of All. And here&amp;rsquo;s what is so uncomfortable, so jarring. The character representing God in this parable is an unrighteous judge who cared only that the widow stop bothering him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this how the Lord receives the prayers of his beloved ones, our prayers? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s first see how precious to the Lord are the prayers of his saints, us, our prayers. And for that we must look into the throne room of heaven itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And between the throne and the four living creatures and among the elders I saw a Lamb standing, as though it had been slain, with seven horns and with seven eyes, which are the seven spirits of God sent out into all the earth. And he went and took the scroll from the right hand of him who was seated on the throne. And when he had taken the scroll, the four living creatures and the twenty-four elders fell down before the Lamb, each holding a harp, and golden bowls full of incense, which are the prayers of the saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:6-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the Lamb who was slain, the risen Lord Jesus, with eyes like a flame of fire, feet like burnished bronze, a voice like the roar of many waters, and his face like the sun shining in full strength. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here in the throne room around the Lamb are the twenty-four elders holding those golden bowls full of incense, which are the prayers of the saints⸺our prayers. What next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the Lamb opened the seventh seal, there was silence in heaven for about half an hour. Then I saw the seven angels who stand before God, and seven trumpets were given to them. And another angel came and stood at the altar with a golden censer, and he was given much incense to offer with the prayers of all the saints on the golden altar before the throne, and the smoke of the incense, with the prayers of the saints, rose before God from the hand of the angel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 8:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how precious to the Lord are the prayers of the saints. They are offered on the golden altar before the throne in heaven, and are a pleasing aroma to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it would be a terrible mistake to infer something of the character of God from the unrighteous judge in the parable. That is not what the parable is about and that is not what it means. To make such an inference would be an example of attributing meaning beyond what is intended, and yet people make that mistake all the time. How often have you heard criticism of the father in the parable of the Prodigal Son over how he must have treated the elder son? But the father represents our Heavenly Father! That is not what the parable is about and the criticism is out of place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s a bigger problem with the parables than inferring beyond what they teach and it is this, which Jesus explained to his disciples in the context of the parable of the sower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the disciples came and said to him, “Why do you speak to them in parables?” And he answered them, “To you it has been given to know the secrets of the kingdom of heaven, but to them it has not been given. For to the one who has, more will be given, and he will have an abundance, but from the one who has not, even what he has will be taken away. This is why I speak to them in parables, because seeing they do not see, and hearing they do not hear, nor do they understand.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:10-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can this be right? That the reason Jesus spoke in parables was to inhibit understanding? Didn&amp;rsquo;t he come to seek and save the lost? What could this possibly mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus continued by quoting Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in their case the prophecy of Isaiah is fulfilled that says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You will indeed hear but never understand,
and you will indeed see but never perceive.” For this people&amp;rsquo;s heart has grown dull, and with their ears they can barely hear, and their eyes they have closed, lest they should see with their eyes and hear with their ears and understand with their heart and turn, and I would heal them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/the-elephant-in-the-room/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;I have wrestled with this prophecy of Isaiah before&lt;/a&gt;. But here I have noticed something significant. Read carefully Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s original prophecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [the voice of the Lord] said, “Go, and say to this people: ‘Keep on hearing, but do not understand; keep on seeing, but do not perceive.’ Make the heart of this people dull, and their ears heavy, and blind their eyes; lest they see with their eyes, and hear with their ears, and understand with their hearts, and turn and be healed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice of the Lord is full of imperatives. Make the heart of this people dull, and their ears heavy, and blind their eyes. Something is being done to this people and it is most uncomfortable. But Jesus is Lord of All, God before time, and fully able to clarify this. Notice how he quotes from Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this people&amp;rsquo;s heart has grown dull, and with their ears they can barely hear, and their eyes they have closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:15a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart of those unable to comprehend the parables has grown dull and they have closed their own eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is mystery here and grappling must continue. But in the grappling notice the grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But blessed are your eyes, for they see, and your ears, for they hear. For truly, I say to you, many prophets and righteous people longed to see what you see, and did not see it, and to hear what you hear, and did not hear it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, many have longed for what you have, for what you have received and seen and heard and understood. Are you sufficiently grateful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To you it has been given to know the secrets of the kingdom of heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice too that the prophecy of Isaiah is not universal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is why I speak to them in parables, because seeing they do not see, and hearing they do not hear, nor do they understand. Indeed, in their case the prophecy of Isaiah is fulfilled &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 13:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold on therefore to what you have, guard it jealously, and be grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;See what kind of love the Father has given to us, that we should be called children of God; and so we are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 3:1a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally notice how Jesus finished his parable of the persistent widow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, when the Son of Man comes, will he find faith on earth?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 18:8b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Lord receives your prayers into his golden bowls in the throne room of heaven, will he find faith on earth? Will you pray in faith? And will you keep praying, believing and not doubting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, always pray and do not lose heart, and be grateful for the love of the Father, that we should be called children of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
