<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The answer</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-answer/neil-mark-thomas-hgIJfyEaQQQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The answer" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this answer that the psalmist received when he told the Lord of his ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And why is this followed by an immediate and urgent plea to be taught his statutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what even was the question that demanded an answer? Do you see a question here from the psalmist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s answer is not so much an answer to a question but something far deeper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find something similar in the previous psalm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Out of my distress I called on the LORD; the LORD answered me and set me free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling on the Lord is no sort of question. This is a cry for help. So what is the answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joel tells of an answer of a similar kind. In the context of the day of the Lord, that fearful day of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s righteous judgment of his own wayward people, that day of destruction, that day of reckoning, we find this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD became jealous for his land and had pity on his people. The LORD answered and said to his people, “Behold, I am sending to you grain, wine, and oil, and you will be satisfied; and I will no more make you a reproach among the nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one question in sight here, and it is found in the prayer of the ministers of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spare your people, O LORD, and make not your heritage a reproach, a byword among the nations. Why should they say among the peoples, “Where is their God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where indeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s first understand what it means for the Lord to become jealous for his land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the LORD said to Abram, “Go from your country and your kindred and your father&amp;rsquo;s house to the land that I will show you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To your offspring I will give this land.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 12:1, 7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land was hugely symbolic of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s covenant promise to his chosen people. The Lord is faithful even when his people are not. He never once forgot that covenant promise. He never once forgot that covenant love poured out at Calvary and he never will. He is faithful in covenant love to his people even when they are not. O my soul, praise the God of your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what was his answer for his chosen people in the midst of that divine and righteous judgment of the day of the Lord? It was presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LORD answered and said to his people,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be glad, O children of Zion, and rejoice in the LORD your God, for he has given the early rain for your vindication; he has poured down for you abundant rain, the early and the latter rain, as before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall eat in plenty and be satisfied, and praise the name of the LORD your God, who has dealt wondrously with you. And my people shall never again be put to shame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And it shall come to pass that everyone who calls on the name of the LORD shall be saved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:19, 23, 26, 32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compassion and kindness rain down from heaven on undeserving sinners. Praise the Lord, who has dealt wondrously with us all! And everyone who calls on the name of the Lord shall be saved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is where we started. Let&amp;rsquo;s examine the context of our opening verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to the dust; give me life according to your word! When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes! Make me understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your wondrous works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:25-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context is one in need of rescue, clinging to the dust, despairing of life itself. When I told of my ways⸺when I gave an account to the Lord of my own ruined life, when I acknowledged before him my own complete and utter inadequacy⸺he answered me, and his answer is presence and compassion and adequacy and rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice in this answer! Rejoice in the God of your salvation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these statutes? Why does my heart cry out to the Lord, teach me your statutes? Because the only possible response from the one who understands the magnitude of the rescue is this: to live a right life, a noble life, a life that honours the Lord in every way and in every thought and in every deed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the desire we see in the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Teach me your statutes! &amp;hellip;  Make me understand the way of your precepts &amp;hellip; Put false ways far from me
and graciously teach me your law! &amp;hellip; I set your rules before me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:26, 27, 29, 30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been rescued by the God of my salvation, the Creator of the Universe, and my life now belongs to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, praise the God of your salvation for this answer in Christ, and live for him alone! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The turning point</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-turning-point/Fotos_del_Gran_Canaria_2010_PWA_Pozo_Izquierdo_Grand_Prix.Santa_Lucia.Gran_Canaria_%284778010692%29.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The turning point" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long does it take to get from clinging on in the dust despairing of life itself to running in the path of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s commandments having had one&amp;rsquo;s heart set free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the answer is seven verses. Seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul clings to the dust; give me life according to your word! When I told of my ways, you answered me; teach me your statutes! Make me understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your wondrous works. My soul melts away for sorrow; strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me and graciously teach me your law! I have chosen the way of faithfulness; I set your rules before me. I cling to your testimonies, O LORD; let me not be put to shame! I will run in the way of your commandments for you set my heart free!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:25-32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth that last verse is in the future tense, and the mainline translation is “when you enlarge my heart”. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is going on here that leads to such a turnaround?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul melts away for sorrow. Do you know what that is like? To live with such vulnerability in that place right on the edge of crumpling into a heap and sobbing uncontrollably? The place of clinging on when all strength is gone? The place of crying out for life itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some heart-cries here for the Lord to act with compassion and great power: Give me life according to your word! Make me understand the way of your precepts! Strengthen me according to your word! Put false ways far from me! But these in and of themselves are not the turning point. The turning point comes next and it is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have chosen the way of faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the turning point. In weakness and in sorrow, clinging on in the dust, with courage and determination the psalmist chooses the way of faithfulness. Everything follows from this. O my soul, choose the way of faithfulness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s be clear about whose faithfulness this is. Recall the Lord&amp;rsquo;s introduction of himself to Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses said to the LORD, “See, you say to me, ‘Bring up this people,’ but you have not let me know whom you will send with me. Yet you have said, ‘I know you by name, and you have also found favour in my sight.’ Now therefore, if I have found favour in your sight, please show me now your ways, that I may know you in order to find favour in your sight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:12-13, 18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Lord, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of faithfulness is the way of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own faithfulness. So what does it mean to choose this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vindicate me, O LORD, for I have walked in my integrity, and I have trusted in the LORD without wavering. Prove me, O LORD, and try me; test my heart and my mind. For your steadfast love is before my eyes, and I walk in your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 26:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To choose the way of faithfulness and to walk in it is to trust in the Lord without wavering. It is to rely on him whatever else is happening, reminding oneself of his steadfast love. Prove me, O Lord, and try me. Know that I do not doubt you. I do not doubt your goodness and your mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what do you suppose is this proving? This trying? This testing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to see beyond current circumstances with eyes of faith, beyond current suffering, to assert with the psalmist out of the darkest valley, out of the deepest sorrow, out of the most wrenching pain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I know, O LORD, that your rules are righteous, and that in faithfulness you have afflicted me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:75&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to assert confidence in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness and to wait upon him, trusting and not doubting. Beyond the point of understanding, beyond the point of being able to see is where trust is tried, tested, and proven. And in this time of testing, this waiting time, it is to walk in one&amp;rsquo;s integrity, keeping covenant with the Holy One, surrendering all to him as an act of worship, perhaps in tears and bewilderment, but surrendering nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what must one do while walking in this way of faithfulness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I set your rules before me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:30b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your heart is breaking, set his rules before you and walk in them, and know this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All the paths of the LORD are steadfast love and faithfulness, for those who keep his covenant and his testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be sure to keep his covenant and his testimonies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now what about that future tense of the running?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will run in the way of your commandments when you enlarge my heart!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is breaking and I simply lack the capacity for this. How can I endure this waiting time? My strength is almost gone. But the Lord himself enlarges my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These sterile and barren bodies of ours are yearning for full deliverance. That is why waiting does not diminish us, any more than waiting diminishes a pregnant mother. We are enlarged in the waiting. We, of course, don’t see what is enlarging us. But the longer we wait, the larger we become, and the more joyful our expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:23-25 MSG&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will run, O my soul, I will! I will run in the way of his commandments, trusting and not doubting. I choose the way of faithfulness. I choose to trust the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, trust in the Lord with all your heart and choose the way of his steadfast love and faithfulness! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A pure heart</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/bas-glaap-DEQS0GFk4AM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A pure heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you given much thought to what is pure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honourable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is pure then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The words of the LORD are pure words, like silver refined in a furnace on the ground, purified seven times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 12:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This psalm underlines the striking contrast between the purity of the Lord and his words and the double-mindedness of humankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everyone utters lies to his neighbour; with flattering lips and a double heart they speak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words of the Lord then are pure, but what else? Is the catalogue of what is pure in fact a very short list indeed? Could we add to that list? What else could be pure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this one beatitude stand out from among the others as utterly intimidating? Being poor in spirit, mourning, meekness, hunger and thirsting for righteousness, being merciful⸺isn&amp;rsquo;t our response to those others, yes Lord? But being pure in heart? Isn&amp;rsquo;t our response to this, O Lord have mercy on me, a sinner? Yes of course it is, at least it is if we have any honesty in our own self-evaluation. And that is because it seems to be utterly beyond us. But is it? Is it really? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this, and as we do, give thought to the prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you want to see God? Then resolve to do this, to be pure in heart. But how? How can we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job&amp;rsquo;s friend Eliphaz uttered much foolishness in his earnest desire to help Job. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can mortal man be in the right before God? Can a man be pure before his Maker?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 4:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He followed up with two rhetorical questions, revealing the limitations of his own understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is man, that he can be pure? Or he who is born of a woman, that he can be righteous?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 15:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was wrong, O my soul. Rejoice that he was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Eliphaz the Temanite: “My anger burns against you and against your two friends, for you have not spoken of me what is right, as my servant Job has.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:7b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s try to answer the question by understanding how. How is it possible to be pure before the Lord? There are three elements which must come together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleanse means purify. Jesus came and died for you and for me and for all of humankind, that we may be forgiven our sin, that we may be justified and redeemed, and that we may be purified from all unrighteousness. The justification and redemption were an immediate and once-and-for-all-time thing. The purification is a rest-of-our-life thing and is the ongoing work of the Holy Spirit. Without the body and blood of Jesus there can be no meaningful purification, so perhaps Eliphaz was not entirely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first and most fundamental element of purification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist points us to the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man keep his way pure? By guarding it according to your word. With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments! I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this. I am that young man, so desiring to keep my way pure and yet so aware of the challenge in that, and so aware of my own propensity to sin⸺so aware of how I fall short, and therefore so resolute in guarding my heart according to the revealed word of God. And seeking him will take my whole heart, but it will be so worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you, declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all my heart I will seek the Lord, ruthlessly and unrelentingly. No holding back. No compromise. No distractions. My heart-cry is, let me not wander from your commandments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you understand what it means to store up his word in your heart? Immerse yourself in the Bible. It is his precious gift to us. Read it. Savour it. Chew on it. Digest it. Commit it to memory. And do it. It will guard your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second element of purification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third? The third element is surprising and inclined to be overlooked in this regard, but it is in fact the game-changer, the red pill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third element is the extraordinary power of love, both the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great love which came first, and our love response to his rescue⸺our love for the Lord and our love for one another. Isn&amp;rsquo;t this simply astonishing? That the outworking of authentic and abounding love could be a pure heart? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fruit of righteousness comes through Jesus Christ, and is to the glory and praise of God. It is his own work in us, and it is all of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We love because he first loved us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 4:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is love from a grateful heart. But how can purity be the result of this love? Didn&amp;rsquo;t the Pharisees expend so much energy dotting every &lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt; and crossing every &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; in order to become pure? And there are so many commandments to keep. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it all utterly wearying, completely beyond us? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Owe no one anything, except to love each other, for the one who loves another has fulfilled the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:8, 10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law, and surely this is purity before the Lord. A pure heart then is the outworking of authentic and abounding love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who can say, “I have made my heart pure; I am clean from my sin?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 20:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will for you, so receive it and embrace it and pursue it with your whole heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What to think about</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/what-to-think-about/redd-f-LP3PabHuyiE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What to think about" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you thinking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking again about those insolent ones? And if so, why? Why would you continue to think about them? Thinking about them is not blessing you. Be assured that they are not thinking about you! Or are you dwelling on other things which drag you down? Why would you continue to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Like a dog that returns to his vomit is a fool who repeats his folly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 26:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what are you doing? Would you be building that dam on the river of life? Stop! Stop thinking about those things which drag you down. Stop dwelling on them. Stop living in them. Think instead about something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then? What must you think about? Paul tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honourable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about these things and be lifted up and encouraged. So what are they, these things that we must think about? Rejoice that they are many and varied, and fill your mind with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw heaven opened, and behold, a white horse! The one sitting on it is called Faithful and True, and in righteousness he judges and makes war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 19:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Here is Jesus in all of his resurrection power and splendour, whose very name is Faithful and True. In righteousness he judges and makes war on all that is unholy. And he is victorious. Think about him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now, O Lord GOD, you are God, and your words are true, and you have promised this good thing to your servant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Samuel 7:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words of the Lord are true. What he has promised is true. His name is Faithful and True. Think about this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about whatever is just.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, think about this. Christ died on the cross, paying the price for my sin and yours in full. If we confess our sins and cry out to God for mercy it is his justice that demands we be forgiven. The price is paid. He will not take a second payment precisely because he is just. Hallelujah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon me, because the LORD has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I the LORD love justice; I hate robbery and wrong; I will faithfully give them their recompense, and I will make an everlasting covenant with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 61:1,8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that the Lord loves justice. In power and compassion Jesus came to do justice for the poor and the oppressed. Think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn to do good; seek justice, correct oppression; bring justice to the fatherless, plead the widow&amp;rsquo;s cause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 1:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about how to do justice⸺the Lord&amp;rsquo;s own justice which binds up the brokenhearted and proclaims liberty to the captives and the opening of the prison to those who are bound. Think about how to do this in his Spirit and by his power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about what is worthy of praise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I looked, and I heard around the throne and the living creatures and the elders the voice of many angels, numbering myriads of myriads and thousands of thousands, saying with a loud voice, “Worthy is the Lamb who was slain, to receive power and wealth and wisdom and might and honour and glory and blessing!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 5:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the sound of a hundred million angels singing praise to the risen Lord Jesus in his resurrection power and splendour. And hear his own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I turned to see the voice that was speaking to me, and on turning I saw seven golden lampstands, and in the midst of the lampstands one like a son of man, clothed with a long robe and with a golden sash around his chest. The hairs of his head were white, like white wool, like snow. His eyes were like a flame of fire, his feet were like burnished bronze, refined in a furnace, and his voice was like the roar of many waters. In his right hand he held seven stars, from his mouth came a sharp two-edged sword, and his face was like the sun shining in full strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw him, I fell at his feet as though dead. But he laid his right hand on me, saying, “Fear not, I am the first and the last, and the living one. I died, and behold I am alive forevermore, and I have the keys of Death and Hades.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 1:12-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear not, O my soul, and think about this. He is the first and the last and the living one, who died and rose again to life, and he is alive forevermore. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, why finally? Why does Paul say finally? We need to look at what came before. And what came before is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not be anxious about those insolent ones or about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about these true, just, praiseworthy things, O my soul, and pray with thanksgiving, and know that the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your heart and your mind in Christ Jesus! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Plan B</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/senjuti-kundu-JfolIjRnveY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Plan B" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life as God had intended?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was hated by his brothers to the extent that they wanted to murder him. Narrowly escaping death at their hands he was sold into slavery at the age of seventeen and then thrown into prison in Egypt for a crime he didn&amp;rsquo;t commit, where he was incarcerated for more than ten years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this what God had intended for him? Why had this all happened? Is this what the Lord&amp;rsquo;s perfect plans and purposes look like for those he loves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means! We simply must account for human folly and foolishness. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s own life and his whole family were dominated by these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Israel loved Joseph more than any other of his sons, because he was the son of his old age. And he made him a robe of many colours. But when his brothers saw that their father loved him more than all his brothers, they hated him and could not speak peacefully to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacob, now called Israel, fathered Joseph in his old age and doted upon him, unwisely favouring him above his brothers whose subsequent envy grew to become hatred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Joseph demonstrated that he was his father&amp;rsquo;s son through his own lack of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Joseph, being seventeen years old, was pasturing the flock with his brothers. He was a boy with the sons of Bilhah and Zilpah, his father&amp;rsquo;s wives. And Joseph brought a bad report of them to their father.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At seventeen shouldn&amp;rsquo;t he have known better how to get on with his brothers than telling tales about them to their own father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Joseph had a dream, and when he told it to his brothers they hated him even more. He said to them, “Hear this dream that I have dreamed: Behold, we were binding sheaves in the field, and behold, my sheaf arose and stood upright. And behold, your sheaves gathered around it and bowed down to my sheaf.” His brothers said to him, “Are you indeed to reign over us? Or are you indeed to rule over us?” So they hated him even more for his dreams and for his words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph&amp;rsquo;s dream was from the Lord and revealed a glorious future. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that. But this revelation caused his brothers to hate him even more. They hated him even more because he was unwise enough to tell them of that prophecy which did indeed come to pass, eventually. Nevertheless, sharing it with his brothers as he did was both foolish and inflammatory. He was his father&amp;rsquo;s son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was a mistake he repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he dreamed another dream and told it to his brothers and said, “Behold, I have dreamed another dream. Behold, the sun, the moon, and eleven stars were bowing down to me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps such things are better kept to one&amp;rsquo;s self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later when he arrived in Egypt as a slave he was equally naive. Let&amp;rsquo;s first notice how this foreign slave without credentials or experience became the trusted overseer of the household of Potiphar, the captain of the guard of the Pharaoh of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD was with Joseph, and he became a successful man, and he was in the house of his Egyptian master. His master saw that the LORD was with him and that the LORD caused all that he did to succeed in his hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t this blessing from the Lord all entirely undeserved? Grace and favour were raining down from heaven on this naive young man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then he was accused by Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife of attempted rape. But notice again the pattern here. Just as Joseph had been unwise to share that dream with his brothers, so also he was unwise to be in the house alone with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now Joseph was handsome in form and appearance. And after a time his master&amp;rsquo;s wife cast her eyes on Joseph and said, “Lie with me.” But he refused &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as she spoke to Joseph day after day, he would not listen to her, to lie beside her or to be with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:6-8, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it continued day after day. His woeful encounter with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife was not an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As soon as his master heard the words that his wife spoke to him, “This is the way your servant treated me,” his anger was kindled. And Joseph&amp;rsquo;s master took him and put him into the prison, the place where the king&amp;rsquo;s prisoners were confined, and he was there in prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph again got what he deserved for his own foolishness, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? But what do we find, again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But the LORD was with Joseph and showed him steadfast love and gave him favour in the sight of the keeper of the prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The undeserved steadfast love of the Lord continued to rain down upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And whatever he did, the LORD made it succeed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually⸺and never was a word so appropriate as here in Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life⸺eventually, Joseph came before Pharaoh himself, in a way which was indeed by the hand of the Lord, interpreted his dream, and was freed to a great and glorious future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Pharaoh said to Joseph, “Since God has shown you all this, there is none so discerning and wise as you are. You shall be over my house, and all my people shall order themselves as you command. Only as regards the throne will I be greater than you.” And Pharaoh said to Joseph, “See, I have set you over all the land of Egypt.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 41:39-41&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ironic. Through those long years of incarceration God had transformed that foolish youth into a man so discerning and wise. What a miracle of grace. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you know the rest. Famine in Canaan caused Jacob to send his sons to Egypt to buy food. After some scheming by Joseph which we could see as teaching his brothers a lesson (and who could blame him for that?) there was an emotional reconciliation. And then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus Israel settled in the land of Egypt, in the land of Goshen. And they gained possessions in it, and were fruitful and multiplied greatly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 47:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this story all about then? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s incredible rescue of Joseph&amp;rsquo;s family from famine in their own land? Yes, certainly it is that. A family reconciliation after separation caused by hatred and betrayal? Yes, that too. Rescue and restoration of a naive young man from the consequences of his own foolishness? Indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ultimately isn&amp;rsquo;t this in fact all about the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for undeserving sinners? A Plan B so good and full of grace it seems to improve upon that hypothetical Plan A which never transpired. This Plan B which was wrought out of folly and foolishness and disappointment and shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much had gone wrong, but none of this pain and heartbreak and suffering was intended by the Lord nor attributable to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with us. He is the great rescuer, fully able to pick up the pieces of ruined lives and work all things together for good. His plans and purposes are not thwarted by our mistakes nor by our foolishness. Praise the Lord! And throughout Joseph&amp;rsquo;s story never once did God&amp;rsquo;s grace and steadfast love and faithfulness reach its limit. His grace is sufficient. Yes, the rescue took its time, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t it so well worth the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for your own ruined life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The dam on the river</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/vlad-d-5j6tOZ4LdN4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The dam on the river" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you build a dam across the river of living water? Would you reduce to a trickle that which has been flowing so abundantly? Would you be a busy little beaver, hoarding and assembling your pain and disappointment and cementing it all in place with  unforgiveness and resentment? Would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that I do understand why you would want to build your dam. I acknowledge that you have been treated heinously and that you have been brushed aside and disregarded. And I know that you&amp;rsquo;re hurting, really hurting, and from time to time you want to assert that nobody cares. You want to shout it out across the rooftops at the top of your voice: nobody cares. It&amp;rsquo;s a lie, by the way, that nobody cares. For sure, there are some who don&amp;rsquo;t, perhaps several, and others who are only pretending. But there remain those who are loving and kind and faithful and true. Be grateful for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those insolent ones whose behaviour has been so heinous⸺those who should care and yet do not? Beware, my soul, of how you regard them in return. This is perilous ground indeed upon which you stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul. This means that you must forgive and you must let go of all resentment. You must do these things! And you must not build that dam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me remind you just what is at stake here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, ‘Out of his heart will flow rivers of living water.’” Now this he said about the Spirit, whom those who believed in him were to receive, for as yet the Spirit had not been given, because Jesus was not yet glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 7:37-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you thirst? Do you thirst for love and wholeness and relational authenticity? Come to Jesus and drink. Believe in him and listen to him. Listen to him in your sorrow and pain and dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But I say to you, Do not resist the one who is evil. But if anyone slaps you on the right cheek, turn to him the other also.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Judge not, and you will not be judged; condemn not, and you will not be condemned; forgive, and you will be forgiven; give, and it will be given to you. Good measure, pressed down, shaken together, running over, will be put into your lap. For with the measure you use it will be measured back to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive and you will be forgiven. Extend love and kindness to those who do not, and it will be measured back to you, O my soul, how it will! And rivers of living water will flow out of your heart and you will be a blessing to many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t the way these insolent ones carry on simply egregious? Yes of course it is, and appallingly so. What&amp;rsquo;s to be done then about their heinous behaviour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin; ponder in your own hearts on your beds, and be silent. Offer right sacrifices, and put your trust in the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry, O my soul. Be angry and do not sin. Notice it is “and” not “but”. Interesting! The dam on the river is not made of anger. Was Jesus angry when he cleared the temple? Yes of course he was and rightly so. There is a righteous anger and it is of the Lord. Be angry and do not sin. The behaviour is egregious and it cannot be excused. It can only be forgiven, and this you must do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And listen to the heart-cry of the Psalmist to the Lord. Make it your own as you put your trust in the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal bountifully with your servant, that I may live and keep your word. Open my eyes, that I may behold
wondrous things out of your law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You rebuke the insolent, accursed ones, who wander from your commandments. Take away from me scorn and contempt, for I have kept your testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:17-18, 21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the one who rebukes these insolent ones. And there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word of the LORD came to me: “Son of man, prophesy against the shepherds of Israel; prophesy, and say to them, even to the shepherds, Thus says the Lord GOD: Ah, shepherds of Israel who have been feeding yourselves! Should not shepherds feed the sheep? You eat the fat, you clothe yourselves with the wool, you slaughter the fat ones, but you do not feed the sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says the Lord GOD, Behold, I am against the shepherds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:1-3,10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is good news indeed for these poor sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I myself will be the shepherd of my sheep, and I myself will make them lie down, declares the Lord GOD. I will seek the lost, and I will bring back the strayed, and I will bind up the injured, and I will strengthen the weak, and the fat and the strong I will destroy. I will feed them in justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beware, O my soul, there is a warning also to these very same sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it not enough for you to feed on the good pasture, that you must tread down with your feet the rest of your pasture; and to drink of clear water, that you must muddy the rest of the water with your feet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will rescue my flock; they shall no longer be a prey. And I will judge between sheep and sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:18,22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then are we to do? Two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Forgive, and you will be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you pour yourself out for the hungry and satisfy the desire of the afflicted, then shall your light rise in the darkness and your gloom be as the noonday. And the LORD will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must do what those insolent ones will not, and then you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water. You must forgive, and love and care for the hungry and the afflicted, and pursue humility and hope and joy in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The trust test</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/guzman-barquin-Qd688l1yDOI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The trust test" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is it to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I say trust, I mean completely depend upon him, fully committed, with no way out and no room for doubt. No wavering. No second guessing. None at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said &amp;hellip; “Do not fear, only believe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 5:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such trust is life and health and strength. Why would anyone not live like this? And yet many do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall with me the sorry saga of the Israelites failing to trust the Lord, their ongoing enslavement to fear and uncertainty and doubt. And recall too the Lord&amp;rsquo;s uncompromising response, his righteous anger burning against them, his chosen people, his beloved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What reason did the Israelites have to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the sight of their fathers he performed wonders in the land of Egypt, in the fields of Zoan. He divided the sea and let them pass through it, and made the waters stand like a heap. In the daytime he led them with a cloud, and all the night with a fiery light. He split rocks in the wilderness and gave them drink abundantly as from the deep. He made streams come out of the rock and caused waters to flow down like rivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:12-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the God who miraculously delivered his people from slavery in Egypt, parting the waters of the Red Sea so they could pass safely. And led them through the desert, miraculously guiding them and remaining with them. And slaked their thirst in the desert, again, miraculously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he fed them with manna from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Moses, “Behold, I am about to rain bread from heaven for you, and the people shall go out and gather a day&amp;rsquo;s portion every day, that I may test them, whether they will walk in my law or not.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 16:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was the test. This is the trust test. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that the Israelites faced time and again. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that we ourselves face time and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how did they do, those Israelites, those chosen people, those beloved ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They forgot his works and the wonders that he had shown them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They forgot all the reasons they had to trust him! Their earlier fear of the Lord and belief in him was so feeble it had simply evaporated like the morning mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet they sinned still more against him, rebelling against the Most High in the desert. They tested God in their heart by demanding the food they craved. They spoke against God, saying, “Can God spread a table in the wilderness? He struck the rock so that water gushed out and streams overflowed. Can he also give bread or provide meat for his people?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:17-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the sneering doubt here, the sheer contempt for their provider, the complete absence of trust? O my soul, be appalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, when the LORD heard, he was full of wrath; a fire was kindled against Jacob; his anger rose against Israel, because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not want you to be unaware, brothers, that our fathers were all under the cloud, and all passed through the sea, and all were baptized into Moses in the cloud and in the sea, and all ate the same spiritual food, and all drank the same spiritual drink. For they drank from the spiritual Rock that followed them, and the Rock was Christ. Nevertheless, with most of them God was not pleased, for they were overthrown in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They drank from the Rock which was Christ no less and yet they failed the trust test. Overthrown means struck down. In judgment for their lack of trust most of them were struck down by the Lord, their hitherto protector and provider, the Faithful One. Most of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The anger of God rose against them, and he killed the strongest of them and laid low the young men of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how important it is to trust, to believe, to depend upon the Lord without wavering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of our own trust test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even when things are very dark indeed you must trust the Lord and depend upon him relentlessly. He is faithful and true. Never doubt that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who among you fears the LORD and obeys the voice of his servant? Let him who walks in darkness and has no light trust in the name of the LORD and rely on his God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 50:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is tested when our lives are at stake, when our hearts are breaking, when things are entirely beyond us and all we can do is depend upon the Lord, upon his faithfulness to all that he has promised and to all that he is, when the way ahead is unseeable. But without the unseeable there can be no faith! O my soul, will you trust him then? Will you trust him now? Will you continue to trust him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now hope that is seen is not hope. For who hopes for what he sees? But if we hope for what we do not see, we wait for it with patience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in this waiting time of unseeing are you tempted to doubt? Are you tempted to despair? Are you tempted to run ahead of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will in your own strength? Resist! You must resist! Hold on to what is true. Hold on to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No temptation has overtaken you that is not common to man. God is faithful, and he will not let you be tempted beyond your ability, but with the temptation he will also provide the way of escape, that you may be able to endure it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can endure this, O my soul. Repudiate doubt and all that drags you down, and trust him. Trust him! You must endure with steadfast faith, believing and not doubting. Trust Jesus, whose name is Faithful and True!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The penalty for failing the truth test is severe, as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen. For standing firm, however, there are two stupendous prizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in him, O my soul, and he will act!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD’s delight is in those who fear him, those who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing this, by walking this path of trust and dependence and unwavering hope in him, waiting with patience, you can delight our Heavenly Father. You can delight him! What more motivation could you have to choose to trust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 15:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, put all your hope in his unfailing love and trust in the faithfulness of your Heavenly Father, and so delight him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Created for his glory</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/mohamed-nohassi-odxB5oIG_iA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Created for his glory" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, why do you exist? What were you created for? You must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading in Isaiah, and I am overwhelmed by what I read. Before we come to my question though, let&amp;rsquo;s consider how the Lord regards us, his beloved ones. Let&amp;rsquo;s lose ourselves in the love letter which is Isaiah Chapter 43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD, he who created you, O Jacob, he who formed you, O Israel: “Fear not, for I have redeemed you; I have called you by name, you are mine.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember Jacob? He was that despicable little man, that man entirely without honour, a liar and a cheat. The man who wrestled with God, all night. The man to whom God gave a new name, Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So these words addressed to Jacob, who are they for? Their setting was the Babylonian exile. Jacob had been dead for perhaps a thousand years. Not for him then! These words are for his descendants⸺not his physical descendants, but the children of the promise⸺and that includes us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, these words are spoken to you by the God who created you, who formed you, who continues to form you⸺and he is not done with the forming by any means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that you may be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness. Fear not, O my soul. You have been redeemed by the Creator God of the universe. Called by him. Known by him. Belonging to him. Rejoice in that ineffable truth and embrace the forming of purity and blamelessness in your own life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this: you are called by name. Your name is who you are. It is your character. You are fully known by the one who calls. There is nothing that the Lord could subsequently learn about you which would change how he regards you. You are called and you are known and you are his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember God&amp;rsquo;s question to Jacob after the wrestling?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said to him, “What is your name?” And he said, “Jacob.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is God asking here? He is the omniscient and all powerful Creator God of the universe and he asks, “What is your name?” He is not seeking information! The question to Jacob is, what kind of man are you? And Jacob confesses his name⸺the cheat, the deceiver, vile and despicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he said, “Your name shall no longer be called Jacob, but Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold! God is the one who makes all things new! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And marvel at the extent to which the Lord will go to do this. Isaiah continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am the LORD your God, the Holy One of Israel, your Saviour. I give Egypt as your ransom, Cush and Seba in exchange for you. Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is my saviour. He is your saviour. The ransom is costly and there is no limit to where he will go for the rescue, because I am precious in his eyes, and honoured. Because you are precious, and he loves you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, he gave one man in particular in return for you: Jesus Christ, the only Son of God, in exchange for your life. In exchange for mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ransom is costly. But fear not, O my soul, he has redeemed you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are you here? Why do you exist? What were you created for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; bring my sons from afar and my daughters from the end of the earth, everyone who is called by my name, whom I created for my glory, whom I formed and made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1, 4, 6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You were created for the glory of God. He set his love upon you, called you by name, poured out that great love at Calvary, and redeemed you. There is no higher calling than for the glory of God. It is why I am here. It is why you are here. And as we receive that great Calvary love may all see it for what it is and give God the glory due his name. Be filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wrestling is done, O my soul. It&amp;rsquo;s time for that to end. You have been bought at a price⸺an unfathomable price. But that price has been paid, and in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now may your love abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, to know the magnitude of the reason why you are here. It is for the glory of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My strength is almost gone</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/todd-trapani-v2Jf_jpNamc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My strength is almost gone" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you weary? So very weary? So weary in fact that you wonder whether you can carry on at all, even not quite knowing what that would mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is it that we are commanded to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be patient in tribulation. And go on being patient. And on. And on. Being patient. In tribulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when will it all end? Will it ever end? How can you continue to endure this, O my soul? Isn&amp;rsquo;t the prolonged nature of it all simply wearing you down?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you made Job&amp;rsquo;s heart-cry your very own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I don’t have the strength to endure. I have nothing to live for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 6:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will it ever end? What is there to live for? Does anything even matter any more?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my Soul, listen to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By your endurance you will gain your lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 21:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is speaking of the great tribulation, but it makes no difference. By your endurance you will gain your life, O my soul. Your endurance matters then, O how it matters! Your life depends upon it. But what is it exactly? What is this endurance by which you will gain your life, beyond simply managing to exist through the trial? What indeed? And where will this endurance come from, that you may live?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s first consider the why, and through that understand the what and the how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have need of endurance, so that when you have done the will of God you may receive what is promised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you want to receive what is promised? Do you want to receive what has been promised from the one whose name is Faithful and True? Then you have need of endurance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This endurance is what will enable you to do the will of God, and to keep on doing it. So now we must ask, what is the will of God here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then they said to him, “What must we do, to be doing the works of God?” Jesus answered them, “This is the work of God, that you believe in him whom he has sent.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 6:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is it. This is what it means to endure. Believe in Jesus, the one whom the Lord has sent! Above all else this means trust him. Trust him, absolutely and completely, and depend upon him, and on him alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Trust in the LORD with all your heart, and do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make straight your paths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 3:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own understanding is quite simply not up to the task. This is entirely beyond me. O my soul, at that point beyond which you cannot understand what or why or how, you must surrender your need to understand, and simply trust the one who does⸺the one whose name is Faithful and True. Trust Jesus! And depend on him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be mindful that straight does not mean easy, but it does mean that there is a way. There is a way ahead, and by taking one step after another on this straight path, trusting and not doubting, you can continue. You can continue, O my soul, so do that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as you resolve to continue to take this path ahead, wondering whether you have the strength even for that, you must understand where strength comes from. It comes from hope. Hold on to hope. The one who promised is Faithful and True. Rejoice in that hope!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength comes from hope. It comes from trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who trust in the LORD will find new strength. They will soar high on wings like eagles. They will run and not grow weary. They will walk and not faint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:31 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my Soul, I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to soaring on wings like an eagle, as that may be inconceivable for now. But know this. The word used for trust is the Hebrew &lt;em&gt;qâvâh&lt;/em&gt;, which could be translated wait for, or hope in, or expect. Yes, more waiting. More waiting, O my soul, but waiting in hope. And rejoicing in that hope. Paul and Isaiah are perfectly aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope. Trust in and depend on Jesus, that he may be the one to lift you up. Oh, and be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in the Lord, O my soul, and find there new strength to carry on! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>That was yesterday</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/istrfry-marcus-NX0WjgdQl58-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post That was yesterday" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened yesterday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were you hoping for great things? Were you expecting great things? And are you tempted to say, “nothing”? That nothing happened? (You would be so very wrong about that, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that nothing happened yesterday, now what? What will you do now? Where is hope? How can hope survive the passing of yet another day, the unrelenting accumulation of which become inexorable years? How can faith survive this, O my soul? How will this rollercoaster of expectation and disappointment not simply grind you down into the dust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How indeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how. There are three reasons. The first reason is to understand that disappointment is a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointment is a lie because it presupposes failure. But what failure would that be, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Joshua, now old and well advanced in years, passing on some wisdom at the end of his own life to those who would come after him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now I am about to go the way of all the earth, and you know in your hearts and souls, all of you, that not one word has failed of all the good things that the LORD your God promised concerning you. All have come to pass for you; not one of them has failed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not one of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promises had failed, nor has failed, nor will fail. Know that he is faithful and true, O my soul, to all that he has said, and to all that he is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that what you were hoping for yesterday didn&amp;rsquo;t happen, what you were expecting, what you were so committed in faith to receiving, then listen to the Lord himself, speaking through Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me, declaring the end from the beginning and from ancient times things not yet done, saying, ‘My counsel shall stand, and I will accomplish all my purpose,’ calling a bird of prey from the east, the man of my counsel from a far country. I have spoken, and I will bring it to pass; I have purposed, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 46:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sure, there are things not yet done, but there is none like God, declaring the end from the beginning, from ancient times. O my soul, he will do it! He will accomplish all he has purposed! Know that nothing has failed. Trust him still and praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason is because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts. Poured out for you, O my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we have been justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ. Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope, and hope does not put us to shame, because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will have to return another time to rejoicing in our sufferings but for now consider just that final verse, for which the Berean Standard Bible rendition is particularly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And hope does not disappoint us, because God has poured out His love into our hearts through the Holy Spirit, whom He has given us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:5 BSB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope does not disappoint. God himself is both the giver and the one who pours. It is his own great love. He poured out that same love at Calvary, O my soul. Rejoice in hope of the glory of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and final reason is to understand at least something of what did actually happen yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was I hoping for? Isaiah knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Oh that you would rend the heavens and come down, that the mountains might quake at your presence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that the Creator God of the Universe, awesome in power and terrifying in purity but also so very good and kind, would break into this impossible situation, breathing out grace and truth and power into my own life and those around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So did he?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From of old no one has heard or perceived by the ear, no eye has seen a God besides you, who acts for those who wait for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah tells us that the Lord acts. Not that he will act, or even that he did act, but that he acts, in the present tense. He is working right now with great power for those who wait for him. Will you be that, O my soul? Will you continue to be that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is it that he is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habbakuk knows and it cannot be told. The Lord himself declares it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days that you would not believe if told.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonder and be astounded, O my soul, at what the Lord is already doing in your life, and renounce disappointment! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>This is the day!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/robert-lukeman-_RBcxo9AU-U-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post This is the day!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do you expect change will come?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many years spent hoping and trusting, holding on to your promise from the Lord and yet still waiting, are you tempted to give up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you still somehow expect that the Lord will act with great power to fulfil that promise? And when exactly do you expect that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one answer which honours the Lord and that is today. You must continue to expect it and you must expect it today! It is imperative that you do so. Your very faith depends upon it. Your life and health and strength depend upon it. How else could you live a life that honours him, other than in complete trust and dependence upon him, and other than in expectation of the imminent outworking of his great power in your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who promised is indeed faithful. His very name is Faithful and True (Rev 19:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is it quite so important to hold fast to this hope, this expectation of imminent fulfilment, without wavering?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the midst of a spiritual battle and the fighting is fierce. To expect anything other than imminent fulfilment would open the door to doubt ⸺that doubt which is so ready to creep in and steal away hope and joy and expectation. That doubt which would cause all to unravel and expose the tattered remains of a faith which once was. That doubt which must be resisted with all strength. Be steadfast, O my soul! Cry out to the Faithful One, Lord I believe! Help my unbelief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Ahab sent to all the people of Israel and gathered the prophets together at Mount Carmel. And Elijah came near to all the people and said, “How long will you go limping between two different opinions? If the LORD is God, follow him; but if Baal, then follow him.” And the people did not answer him a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they took the bull that was given them, and they prepared it and called upon the name of Baal from morning until noon, saying, “O Baal, answer us!” But there was no voice, and no one answered. And they limped around the altar that they had made. And at noon Elijah mocked them, saying, “Cry aloud, for he is a god. Either he is musing, or he is relieving himself, or he is on a journey, or perhaps he is asleep and must be awakened.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:20-21, 26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you tempted to such thoughts while you wait on the living God, the God of your life? Repudiate them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And at the time of the offering of the oblation, Elijah the prophet came near and said, “O LORD, God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let it be known this day that you are God in Israel, and that I am your servant, and that I have done all these things at your word. Answer me, O LORD, answer me, that this people may know that you, O LORD, are God, and that you have turned their hearts back.” Then the fire of the LORD fell and consumed the burnt offering and the wood and the stones and the dust, and licked up the water that was in the trench. And when all the people saw it, they fell on their faces and said, “The LORD, he is God; the LORD, he is God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:36-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord, he is God! Praise him, O my soul!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s answer to our most earnest praying, the outworking of his mighty strength in our lives to fulfil all that he has promised, is that all may know that the Lord, he is God! And his grace and kindness is that you, O my soul, may know it. Expect it today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our experience of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power being outworked in our lives is limited only by our faith to believe it, our faith to receive it. This is why it is quite so important that we do not hold back in expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And as Jesus passed on from there, two blind men followed him, crying aloud, “Have mercy on us, Son of David.” When he entered the house, the blind men came to him, and Jesus said to them, “Do you believe that I am able to do this?” They said to him, “Yes, Lord.” Then he touched their eyes, saying, “According to your faith be it done to you.” And their eyes were opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 9:27-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you believe that he is able to do this? According to your faith be it done to you. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s yet more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him. Whoever believes in him is not condemned, but whoever does not believe is condemned already, because he has not believed in the name of the only Son of God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you dare to believe, O my soul, of the only Son of God. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the day that the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the day, O my soul! Expect great things in it! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hope in God</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/jeremy-bishop-DLICfSD33as-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hope in God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you downcast?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your life not as it once was? Are you grieving for things that once were and are no longer?  So was the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These things I remember, as I pour out my soul: how I would go with the throng and lead them in procession to the house of God with glad shouts and songs of praise, a multitude keeping festival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a man who used to live a life of affirmation and exaltation. But things changed and he became a pariah, even in his own church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As with a deadly wound in my bones, my adversaries taunt me, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, O my soul, does the Lord seem to have withdrawn? Are you no longer enjoying that intimacy, the sweetness of his felt presence in your life? Nor was the psalmist. But the desire for that had not left him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul thirsts for God, for the living God. When shall I come and appear before God? My tears have been my food day and night, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multitude keeping festival, those privileged and self-satisfied ones, had closed ranks, and he was no longer among them. And it seemed to him that God himself had passed him by, forgotten him, rejected him. He was oppressed, scorned, and despised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any hope? Is anything to be done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why are you cast down, O my soul, and why are you in turmoil within me? Hope in God; for I shall again praise him, my salvation and my God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:5-6, also v11 and Psalm 43:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you cast down, O my soul? This is not a question in search of an answer. This is a rebuke. It is a rebuke delivered to one who has taken their eyes off the Lord, and has become overwhelmed by their own difficulties and disappointments, defeated by them and yet dwelling in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in God, O my soul! Hope in the only one in whom you really can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul does indeed thirst for God. But where is hope?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By day the LORD commands his steadfast love, and at night his song is with me, a prayer to the God of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His love is steadfast. All his paths are steadfast love and faithfulness (Psalm 25:10). And he is the God of my life⸺the God of my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is not ignorant of nor indifferent to what is happening in my life. He has plans and purposes for me that are beyond my understanding. He is ambitious for me in ways that would blow my mind if I only knew. He is transforming me into the likeness of Christ, and he knows how to do it, O how he knows! He is the God of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What must I do then? I must trust. I must trust the God of my life, who knows his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is this song that is with me through the night, when tears are my only food? The psalmist knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is my strength and my song; he has become my salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Behold, God is my salvation; I will trust, and will not be afraid; for the LORD GOD is my strength and my song, and he has become my salvation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these are borrowed words. They are Moses&amp;rsquo; words. This is Moses&amp;rsquo; song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is my strength and my song, and he has become my salvation; this is my God, and I will praise him, my father&amp;rsquo;s God, and I will exalt him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 15:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is the context of Moses&amp;rsquo; song?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Moses stretched out his hand over the sea, and the LORD drove the sea back by a strong east wind all night and made the sea dry land, and the waters were divided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the LORD saved Israel that day from the hand of the Egyptians, and Israel saw the Egyptians dead on the seashore. Israel saw the great power that the LORD used against the Egyptians, so the people feared the LORD, and they believed in the LORD and in his servant Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 14:21, 30-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song must be the refrain of your life: the habit of remembering who the Lord is and what he has done. It is the habit of remembering as you do the dishes, as you drive to work, as you grapple with the challenges of life. It is the habit of remembering the God of your life and the great power that he uses to rescue those he loves. Dwell in that, my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not underestimate the discipline and determination required to sing this song, to make it the habit of your life, but this you must do, single-mindedly, doggedly, courageously.  It is a matter of life and death. Take your eyes off yourself, look to the Lord and hope in him.  There is no other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in the Lord, O my soul, for there is no other! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
