<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>complacency on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/complacency/</link>
        <description>Recent content in complacency on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/complacency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Fooled by our own reputation</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/fooled-by-our-own-reputation/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/fooled-by-our-own-reputation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/fooled-by-our-own-reputation/julio-rionaldo-CmuCyTRBDGg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fooled by our own reputation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is reputed to be alive but is in fact dead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One answer of course is the church in Sardis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Sardis write: ‘The words of him who has the seven spirits of God and the seven stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works. You have the reputation of being alive, but you are dead.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(But we would be fools to think this is the only answer.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can understand about Jesus&amp;rsquo; diagnosis of this dead church. Firstly and quite surprisingly, given the severity of the indictment, doesn&amp;rsquo;t his judgment seem to be rather non-specific?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wake up, and strengthen what remains and is about to die, for I have not found your works complete in the sight of my God. Remember, then, what you received and heard. Keep it, and repent. If you will not wake up, I will come like a thief, and you will not know at what hour I will come against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has been going on here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are works but they are not complete. What was received and heard has been forgotten. Repentance is required. And they are asleep. Jesus&amp;rsquo; verdict is that the net effect of these apparently innocuous elements is that the church is dead. Dead, no less!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can understand how that could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word used to describe those works which were not complete is the Greek verb &lt;em&gt;plēroō&lt;/em&gt;, which mostly gets translated fulfilled or fulfil. Their works were not fulfilled. So we should ask, what would be works that were fulfilled? Paul tells us, using the parallel Greek noun &lt;em&gt;plērōma&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there was a deficit of love in Sardis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s consider what could have been received and heard and subsequently forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More than that, we also rejoice in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we have now received reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For if, because of one man&amp;rsquo;s trespass, death reigned through that one man, much more will those who receive the abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness reign in life through the one man Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you did not receive the spirit of slavery to fall back into fear, but you have received the Spirit of adoption as sons, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What had been received was reconciliation, abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness, and the Spirit of adoption as sons and daughters, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, grieve with Jesus that this could have been forgotten. How could this be? What could possibly happen that such things be forgotten? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. What happens is that pride enters the human heart, and self-satisfaction displaces gratitude such that one&amp;rsquo;s own status as one who has been rescued is no longer foremost in the mind. It is pride and self-satisfaction that kill humble gratitude and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So if there is any encouragement in Christ, any comfort from love, any participation in the Spirit, any affection and sympathy, complete my joy by being of the same mind, having the same love, being in full accord and of one mind. Do nothing from selfish ambition or conceit, but in humility count others more significant than yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as in the church in Thyatira so too in Sardis there was a call to repent. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it complacency which deafens ears to such a call?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jesus urges them to wake up lest he come like a thief in the night, unexpected and frankly unwelcome. Does this not remind us of Jesus&amp;rsquo; warning to his own disciples, concerning his return in glory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But concerning that day or that hour, no one knows, not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father. Be on guard, keep awake. For you do not know when the time will come. It is like a man going on a journey, when he leaves home and puts his servants in charge, each with his work, and commands the doorkeeper to stay awake. Therefore stay awake⸺for you do not know when the master of the house will come, in the evening, or at midnight, or when the rooster crows, or in the morning⸺lest he come suddenly and find you asleep. And what I say to you I say to all: Stay awake.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 13:32-37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, stay awake!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And tremble also because of Jesus&amp;rsquo; words to the church in Sardis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you will not wake up, I will come like a thief, and you will not know at what hour I will come against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against you! Against the ones who had received reconciliation, abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness, and the Spirit of adoption as sons and daughters. These ones who were now found by Jesus to be on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, was there ever such complacency? But wake up. It is in fact all around us. All. Around. Us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite this we must notice something vital. While it may have been endemic, this spirit of complacency had not vanquished all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet you have still a few names in Sardis, people who have not soiled their garments, and they will walk with me in white, for they are worthy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not despair. There was a faithful remnant, even here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is to be done? Two things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, be appalled at those who have soiled their garments. Those complacent ones. Those who have a reputation of being alive but are in fact dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, put aside your own complacency and smug self-satisfaction, choose the path of humility, and walk with Jesus in white. And you must be careful to understand what that means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After this I looked, and behold, a great multitude that no one could number, from every nation, from all tribes and peoples and languages, standing before the throne and before the Lamb, clothed in white robes, with palm branches in their hands, and crying out with a loud voice, “Salvation belongs to our God who sits on the throne, and to the Lamb!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one of the elders addressed me, saying, “Who are these, clothed in white robes, and from where have they come?” I said to him, “Sir, you know.” And he said to me, “These are the ones coming out of the great tribulation. They have washed their robes and made them white in the blood of the Lamb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 7:9-10, 13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no other way to walk with Jesus in white other than by being washed in the blood of the Lamb, other than by receiving reconciliation, abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness, and the Spirit of adoption as sons and daughters. And holding on to these with humble gratitude! O my soul, hold on to these precious gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God, being rich in mercy, because of the great love with which he loved us, even when we were dead in our trespasses, made us alive together with Christ⸺by grace you have been saved⸺and raised us up with him and seated us with him in the heavenly places in Christ Jesus, so that in the coming ages he might show the immeasurable riches of his grace in kindness toward us in Christ Jesus. For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:4-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So walk with a grateful heart in humility, as one rescued, as one whose life now belongs to another. For it is so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, wash your robes in the blood of the Lamb and walk worthy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Repent!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/repent/cj-botha-PTztNC4yKY0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Repent!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent call to repent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This call to repent went out long ago to the church in Thyatira and it remains today. But let&amp;rsquo;s first marvel at Jesus&amp;rsquo; generous assessment of that church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Thyatira write: ‘The words of the Son of God, who has eyes like a flame of fire, and whose feet are like burnished bronze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works, your love and faith and service and patient endurance, and that your latter works exceed the first.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the church in Thyatira were these commended by Jesus for their love and faith and service and patient endurance. O my soul, how are your own love and faith and service and patient endurance? Jesus knows! His eyes are like a flame of fire and nothing is hidden from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did you notice the generosity in his assessment? Their latter works exceeded the first⸺some were slow starters. Jesus did not dwell on what came before. He commended them for how they were now. O my soul, leave the past behind! Jesus does not dwell on what came before and nor must you. Know that he is generous in his assessment also of you, desiring for you only what is good. He loves you and is committed to you and demands reciprocity in these. Rejoice that it is so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was not all good news in Thyatira.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have this against you, that you tolerate that woman Jezebel, who calls herself a prophetess and is teaching and seducing my servants to practice sexual immorality and to eat food sacrificed to idols. I gave her time to repent, but she refuses to repent of her sexual immorality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we come specifically to the seduction and the sexual immorality, let&amp;rsquo;s notice something significant here⸺a similarity and a difference with what we read in Jesus&amp;rsquo; letter to the church in Ephesus. Here we have a woman calling herself a prophetess and leading the church astray. In the church in Ephesus there were false apostles also leading the church astray. If that is the similarity what is the difference? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it that she was given time to repent and they were not? Recall that there was no call to repentance for those false apostles in Ephesus. They were simply excluded by Jesus and rejected. Tremble at that judgment and that rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now our instinct may be to characterise Jezebel&amp;rsquo;s sin as utterly heinous, far worse than what was happening in Ephesus, but pause to consider that Jesus did in fact give her that time to repent. This is not something we can understand in its entirety but surely warns us off ranking sins and ranking sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those she was leading astray?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I will throw her onto a sickbed, and those who commit adultery with her I will throw into great tribulation, unless they repent of her works, and I will strike her children dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:22-23a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repent! O my soul, notice the urgency to repent. Jesus came to break the chains of bondage to sin and death and to give life in all its abundance, and repentance and faith are the means to receive this precious and lavish gift. But her children, her spiritual offspring who refuse this gift will be struck dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is this death? Is it not that final, second death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. The one who conquers will not be hurt by the second death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then of the specifics of the sin⸺sexual immorality and eating of food sacrificed to idols. Of the former we can say one thing immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you not know that your bodies are members of Christ? Shall I then take the members of Christ and make them members of a prostitute? Never!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flee from sexual immorality. Every other sin a person commits is outside the body, but the sexually immoral person sins against his own body. Or do you not know that your body is a temple of the Holy Spirit within you, whom you have from God? You are not your own, for you were bought with a price. So glorify God in your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 6:15, 18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How different this is from how our own world views such things. Sexual immorality deeply grieves the Lord, for it is a corruption and a debasement of his wonderful gift to those he made in his own image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is something wider going on here. The pagan worship of the day was centred around ritual sexual acts with temple prostitutes and eating of food sacrificed to idols, and this had come in to the church. How this dishonoured the Lord! It was the worldliness of the day invading his church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of worldliness invading the church in our own time? How this dishonours the Lord! And lest you be thinking that what was being rebuked in Thyatira was merely outward behaviour, think again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And all the churches will know that I am he who searches mind and heart, and I will give to each of you according to your works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:23b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the one who searches mind and heart. Mind and heart are where the Lord is first honoured or dishonoured. As Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What comes out of a person is what defiles him. For from within, out of the heart of man, come evil thoughts, sexual immorality, theft, murder, adultery, coveting, wickedness, deceit, sensuality, envy, slander, pride, foolishness. All these evil things come from within, and they defile a person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 7:20-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what must &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; repent of? O my soul, do not brush this question aside in complacency. Jesus searches mind and heart, and so must you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hear again Jesus&amp;rsquo; own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Just so, I tell you, there is joy before the angels of God over one sinner who repents.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 15:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, repent, leave the past behind, and bring joy before the angels of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Locusts</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/locusts/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/locusts/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/locusts/Exodus_10.webp" alt="Featured image of post Locusts" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are those years the locusts have eaten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will restore to you the years that the swarming locust has eaten, the hopper, the destroyer, and the cutter &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:25a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this sound like a wonderful promise of restoration? But what does it mean? To understand those years we must first understand the locusts. So what are the locusts? I have quoted only half a verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will restore to you the years that the swarming locust has eaten, the hopper, the destroyer, and the cutter, my great army, which I sent among you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the words of the Lord, and so these are his own locusts, his great army, which he sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word of the LORD that came to Joel, the son of Pethuel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear this, you elders; give ear, all inhabitants of the land! Has such a thing happened in your days, or in the days of your fathers? Tell your children of it, and let your children tell their children, and their children to another generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the cutting locust left, the swarming locust has eaten. What the swarming locust left, the hopping locust has eaten, and what the hopping locust left, the destroying locust has eaten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joel 1:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever is going on here clearly was and is of vital importance and must be remembered. Notice the urgent exhortation to pay attention, to tell the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, not to forget even through the generations. We ourselves must not overlook this. It is as relevant today as it was then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn more from Zephaniah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I will utterly sweep away everything from the face of the earth,” declares the LORD. “I will sweep away man and beast; I will sweep away the birds of the heavens and the fish of the sea, and the rubble with the wicked. I will cut off mankind from the face of the earth,” declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are these wicked ones who have brought down such judgment from the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I will stretch out my hand against Judah and against all the inhabitants of Jerusalem”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the Lord&amp;rsquo;s chosen people, the hitherto recipients of his covenant love. And this is a prophecy of the day of the Lord, that terrible day of judgment and destruction rained down by the Lord on his own people, his beloved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why? Why would this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I will punish the officials and the king&amp;rsquo;s sons and all who array themselves in foreign attire.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s people, his highest and most exalted ones, had become so compromised, so contaminated by the nations. So worldly. So like us in fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“At that time I will search Jerusalem with lamps, and I will punish the men who are complacent, those who say in their hearts, ‘The LORD will not do good, nor will he do ill.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you think this couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen to us? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that thought the very definition of complacency? That the Lord will not do good, nor will he do ill? That everything will just continue to tick along as we all go about our lives? That the extent of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s interest is merely to observe? O my soul, repudiate such thinking. Purge that complacency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then should be done in the face of this day of judgment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be silent before the Lord GOD! For the day of the LORD is near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:7a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you so full of bluster? So full of excuses? So full of self-justification? Be silent! Be silent before the Lord God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seek the LORD, all you humble of the land, who do his just commands; seek righteousness; seek humility; perhaps you may be hidden on the day of the anger of the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 2:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must be silent and humble ourselves and seek righteousness and humility. But where may these be found in the midst of all this negligence and self-indulgence and intransigence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John tells us of the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My little children, I am writing these things to you so that you may not sin. But if anyone does sin, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous. He is the propitiation for our sins, and not for ours only but also for the sins of the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 2:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Paul tells us of the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have this mind among yourselves, which is yours in Christ Jesus, who, though he was in the form of God, did not count equality with God a thing to be grasped, but emptied himself, by taking the form of a servant, being born in the likeness of men. And being found in human form, he humbled himself by becoming obedient to the point of death, even death on a cross.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek righteousness and humility. Seek Jesus. Cry out to him for salvation and turn to him so that you may be hidden on that terrible day of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore let us be grateful for receiving a kingdom that cannot be shaken, and thus let us offer to God acceptable worship, with reverence and awe, for our God is a consuming fire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us repent of complacency and brainless triumphalism, and offer to God acceptable worship with reverence and awe, for our God is a consuming fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s something else to notice here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be silent before the Lord GOD! For the day of the LORD is near; the LORD has prepared a sacrifice and consecrated his guests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 1:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has indeed prepared a sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Isaac said to his father Abraham, “My father!” And he said, “Here I am, my son.” He said, “Behold, the fire and the wood, but where is the lamb for a burnt offering?” Abraham said, “God will provide for himself the lamb for a burnt offering, my son.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 22:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Christ has entered, not into holy places made with hands, which are copies of the true things, but into heaven itself, now to appear in the presence of God on our behalf. Nor was it to offer himself repeatedly, as the high priest enters the holy places every year with blood not his own, for then he would have had to suffer repeatedly since the foundation of the world. But as it is, he has appeared once for all at the end of the ages to put away sin by the sacrifice of himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 9:24-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only has the Lord prepared the sacrifice of his only Son at such enormous cost, but through him he has also consecrated his guests. O my soul, your own consecration is ongoing, as you are so very aware. Rejoice that it continues and exult with all your heart at the lavish generosity of this restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sing aloud, O daughter of Zion; shout, O Israel! Rejoice and exult with all your heart, O daughter of Jerusalem! The LORD has taken away the judgments against you; he has cleared away your enemies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 3:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And observe how the Lord himself rejoices to see his people returning to him in repentance and humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD your God is in your midst, a mighty one who will save; he will rejoice over you with gladness; he will quiet you by his love; he will exult over you with loud singing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/zephaniah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zephaniah 3:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be quieted by that great Calvary love, rejoice and give thanks to the one who restores those years! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
