<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>self-interest on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/self-interest/</link>
        <description>Recent content in self-interest on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/self-interest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The entitlement trap</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-entitlement-trap/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-entitlement-trap/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-entitlement-trap/malcolm-lightbody-TQfV8lVw7jQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The entitlement trap" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else did Jesus say about that treasure in heaven?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, what is the very next thing he said? Let&amp;rsquo;s pick up where we left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“And everyone who has left houses or brothers or sisters or father or mother or children or lands, for my name&amp;rsquo;s sake, will receive a hundredfold and will inherit eternal life. But many who are first will be last, and the last first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For the kingdom of heaven is like a master of a house who went out early in the morning to hire labourers for his vineyard. After agreeing with the labourers for a denarius a day, he sent them into his vineyard.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:29-30, 20:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you remember this being the introduction to the parable of the labourers in the vineyard? We&amp;rsquo;d better reacquaint ourselves with that parable then!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it starts with an agreement of a denarius a day for working in the vineyard. That was a right and true payment for a day&amp;rsquo;s work. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t riches, but it was enough to live on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the crux of the parable is what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And going out about the third hour he saw others standing idle in the marketplace, and to them he said, ‘You go into the vineyard too, and whatever is right I will give you.’ So they went.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 20:3-5a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever known an employment contract like this? How many try to nail down every last aspect of an agreement before entering into it? But here we see something else. Here we see trust. We see the new hires trusting the master of the house to do what was right and true. And as we shall see, they were not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Going out again about the sixth hour and the ninth hour, he did the same. And about the eleventh hour he went out and found others standing. And he said to them, ‘Why do you stand here idle all day?’ They said to him, ‘Because no one has hired us.’ He said to them, ‘You go into the vineyard too.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 20:5b-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look how the character of God is already shining through in this story of the master hiring labourers for his vineyard. Not only do we see one who is trustworthy and true, but we see generosity towards those in need. Did it make any difference to him whether those left idle came to join his workers, given there was so little time left to be about his work? Not in the slightest! But it made a difference to them, such a difference. So the master says, more! Let more come in to my vineyard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in particular with regard to employment, doesn&amp;rsquo;t this often seem to be unreasonably hard? Ought it not be straightforward to find honest and appropriate work? But it so rarely is. And there is a reason for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And to Adam [the Lord] said, “Because you have listened to the voice of your wife and have eaten of the tree of which I commanded you, ‘You shall not eat of it,’ cursed is the ground because of you; in pain you shall eat of it all the days of your life; thorns and thistles it shall bring forth for you; and you shall eat the plants of the field. By the sweat of your face you shall eat bread, till you return to the ground, for out of it you were taken; for you are dust, and to dust you shall return.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:17-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we should expect work to remain hard until the end of our lives, and we have no-one but ourselves to blame for that. But notice in our parable the grace extended by the master of the house, welcoming into his employ those whom others had rejected. Such is the Father heart of God⸺a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so now we come to the crunch, the reason for the parable, and it is not pretty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when evening came, the owner of the vineyard said to his foreman, ‘Call the labourers and pay them their wages, beginning with the last, up to the first.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 20:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning with the last. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this seem to be a constant refrain throughout Jesus&amp;rsquo; teaching? The last will be first and the first last. We heard it twice even in these few verses. So why are so many striving to be first? Do they simply not believe Jesus?⸺the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when those hired about the eleventh hour came, each of them received a denarius. Now when those hired first came, they thought they would receive more, but each of them also received a denarius. And on receiving it they grumbled at the master of the house, saying, ‘These last worked only one hour, and you have made them equal to us who have borne the burden of the day and the scorching heat.’ But he replied to one of them, ‘Friend, I am doing you no wrong. Did you not agree with me for a denarius? Take what belongs to you and go. I choose to give to this last worker as I give to you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 20:9-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something ugly here, and it afflicts many in the Kingdom. The ugliness is called entitlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is the source of this entitlement? Is it not in comparison and envy? Is it not in that misguided and deeply held belief, I deserve more than this, because I am better than them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must notice that self-centred tendency in your own heart so you may repudiate it. Replace it with rejoicing in the goodness and generosity of the Father to all⸺each one made in the image of God, and each one deeply loved.  The Father cares for each one, because each one matters to him. Each one was bought for a high price, and each one has a part to play in the Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Am I not allowed to do what I choose with what belongs to me? Or do you begrudge my generosity?’ So the last will be first, and the first last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 20:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you begrudge the generosity of the Lord to those whom you look down upon? To those whom you count as less? To those to whom you yourself are entirely indifferent? May it not be so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because there is such a strong word of warning here for the begrudgers, and that word is so. Such a little word, but of such profound importance. So the last will be first, and the first last. This is the reason. This is how it happens. This is how those already richly blessed in the Kingdom find themselves with so much less than they were expecting. So much less than they thought they were entitled to. Because of that entitlement. Because of that begrudging. Because of that self-centredness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how is it that the last may be first? Simply by responding to the unmerited favour of the Lord with grateful and obedient hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, repudiate that entitlement, rejoice in the generosity of the Father to all, and be grateful! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Self-satisfied and delusional</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/nick-fewings-XpG9JaN_SXQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Self-satisfied and delusional" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a church completely and comprehensively lose its way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Laodicea write: ‘The words of the Amen, the faithful and true witness, the beginning of God&amp;rsquo;s creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works: you are neither cold nor hot. Would that you were either cold or hot! So, because you are lukewarm, and neither hot nor cold, I will spit you out of my mouth. For you say, I am rich, I have prospered, and I need nothing, not realizing that you are wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:14-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, grieve with Jesus over this self-satisfied and delusional church. And grieve further over their complete and unmitigated failure and shame. Recall that even in that dead church in Sardis there were some who had not soiled their garments, who being worthy would walk with Jesus in white. In Laodicea no such are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could there have been such a gulf between how Jesus saw the church and how they saw themselves? Laodicea was a wealthy city and we may deduce that its church also was affluent and middle-class, seeing itself as rich in every way, lacking nothing. But how self-satisfied they were!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They thought they were rich, but they had failed to understand the currency of eternity. In reality they were paupers. And if they saw themselves as discerning, in reality they were blind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laodicea was entirely deception and delusion, but Jesus knew, and he knew they were wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked. How had this happened? How does this happen to any church which seems to be richly blessed, which maybe even gives the appearance of delighting in the Lord? Perhaps they had simply made their lives all about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah prophecies against just such. Note well the nature of the offence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cry aloud; do not hold back; lift up your voice like a trumpet; declare to my people their transgression, to the house of Jacob their sins. Yet they seek me daily and delight to know my ways, as if they were a nation that did righteousness and did not forsake the judgment of their God; they ask of me righteous judgments; they delight to draw near to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how the house of Jacob delighted to draw near to God. Everything was simply magnificent, wasn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. No it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. O my soul, be appalled at their pride and listen to their self-justification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why have we fasted, and you see it not? Why have we humbled ourselves, and you take no knowledge of it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord thought otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, in the day of your fast you seek your own pleasure, and oppress all your workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how they were rebuked for their self-interest and lack of concern for others, and be dismayed with quite how much this contradicted what the Lord required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is not this the fast that I choose: to loose the bonds of wickedness, to undo the straps of the yoke, to let the oppressed go free, and to break every yoke? Is it not to share your bread with the hungry and bring the homeless poor into your house; when you see the naked, to cover him, and not to hide yourself from your own flesh?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus say later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A new commandment I give to you, that you love one another: just as I have loved you, you also are to love one another. By this all people will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? Loving one another is the barometer of discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And humility? In their pride and self-satisfaction, how many Laodiceans would have been able to identify with Paul in saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 1:15b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the answer would have been none. Certainly none are mentioned by Jesus in his letter. In all six of the other churches, Jesus found at least something to commend⸺even in Sardis. But here, nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, wake up to this reality! Jesus&amp;rsquo; warning is as urgent as it is vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but the one who does the will of my Father who is in heaven. On that day many will say to me, ‘Lord, Lord, did we not prophesy in your name, and cast out demons in your name, and do many mighty works in your name?’ And then will I declare to them, ‘I never knew you; depart from me, you workers of lawlessness.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now recall that those Philadelphians, with such little power, were commended by Jesus without reservation. Do we see in Laodicea a church condemned without reservation? No we don&amp;rsquo;t⸺at least not that terrible and final condemnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, marvel over the grace and generosity in Jesus&amp;rsquo; lavish invitation to this prideful and delusional church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I counsel you to buy from me gold refined by fire, so that you may be rich, and white garments so that you may clothe yourself and the shame of your nakedness may not be seen, and salve to anoint your eyes, so that you may see. Those whom I love, I reprove and discipline, so be zealous and repent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus had not given up on this smug and self-satisfied church, and neither must you. They were wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked, and yet look what Jesus was offering. Was it not exactly what they needed? What they really needed? And all they had to do to receive these things was to repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite unlike that open door in Philadelphia, the Laodiceans had firmly closed their own door. But listen again to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent invitation to prideful ones who have completely and comprehensively lost their way. Astonishingly, final condemnation is held back, and what is offered in its place is an invitation to repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who conquers, I will grant him to sit with me on my throne, as I also conquered and sat down with my Father on his throne. He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, listen to what Jesus is saying, repent of self-interest and self-satisfaction, humble yourself, and reach out with love for others! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
