<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>eternity on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/eternity/</link>
        <description>Recent content in eternity on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/eternity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The river of life</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-river-of-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-river-of-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-river-of-life/ignacio-aguilar-PK32VXa8LGM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The river of life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What keeps you going?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God is our refuge and strength, a very present help in trouble. Therefore we will not fear though the earth gives way, though the mountains be moved into the heart of the sea, though its waters roar and foam, though the mountains tremble at its swelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 46:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is indeed our refuge and strength, a very present help in trouble. So very present. The ESV footnote reveals that this may also mean well proven. A well proven help in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you familiar with the reality of this? A well proven help in trouble is not theoretical. It is physical and actual and real, and there is track record. Remember back to a time you knew the very present help of God⸺his character being revealed, his faithfulness to his beloved ones⸺his faithfulness to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As faithful as the Lord has been, so he remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I the LORD do not change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/malachi&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we need his faithfulness, for as we look around this broken world we do indeed see the earth give way and mountains fall into the heart of the sea. What turbulent times are these!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in these turbulent times we must take comfort from the entirety of the psalm, so notice what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is a river whose streams make glad the city of God, the holy habitation of the Most High.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 46:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this river, and what can we know about it? And what is the city of God, and how can it be glad? All of this was revealed to the Apostle John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the angel showed me the river of the water of life, bright as crystal, flowing from the throne of God and of the Lamb through the middle of the street of the city; also, on either side of the river, the tree of life with its twelve kinds of fruit, yielding its fruit each month. The leaves of the tree were for the healing of the nations. No longer will there be anything accursed, but the throne of God and of the Lamb will be in it, and his servants will worship him. They will see his face, and his name will be on their foreheads. And night will be no more. They will need no light of lamp or sun, for the Lord God will be their light, and they will reign forever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 22:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river is the water of life. O my soul, drink deeply of this water of life and slake your thirst. Come to Jesus and drink!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, ‘Out of his heart will flow rivers of living water.’” Now this he said about the Spirit, whom those who believed in him were to receive, for as yet the Spirit had not been given, because Jesus was not yet glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 7:37-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the city?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a new heaven and a new earth, for the first heaven and the first earth had passed away, and the sea was no more. And I saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband. And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man. He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holy city is the bride of Christ, his church for whom he died for the joy which was set before him. The joy of saving hopeless and helpless sinners. His joy in saving me and his joy in saving you. The joy that enabled him to endure the cross, scorning its shame (Hebrews 12:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will it be like, in this city, that will make it glad?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain anymore, for the former things have passed away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all to come. But what of now? For the psalm is rooted in this present age. But notice that even in this present age is the city of God, the bride of Christ, his church, made glad by his streams of living water. This is now. And there is one profound truth that is in common between that joyous day when tears are wiped away and the current turbulent time of the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God himself will be with them as their God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;God is in the midst of her; she shall not be moved; God will help her when morning dawns. The nations rage, the kingdoms totter; he utters his voice, the earth melts. The LORD of hosts is with us; the God of Jacob is our fortress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 46:5-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord of Hosts is with his people, his beloved ones, his city, and he is infinite in power and glory. For while these mountains fall into the heart of the sea in the tumult of our age and the earth gives way, the Lord speaks and the earth melts. And listen to what he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be still, and know that I am God. I will be exalted among the nations, I will be exalted in the earth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 46:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, immerse yourself in the river of life, and be still and know that he is God and that he is with you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Do not love your life</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-love-your-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-love-your-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/do-not-love-your-life/crawford-jolly-BjQTmNKlawg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Do not love your life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you love your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many do. But what does Jesus expect and require?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“And to the angel of the church in Smyrna write: ‘The words of the first and the last, who died and came to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘I know your tribulation and your poverty (but you are rich) and the slander of those who say that they are Jews and are not, but are a synagogue of Satan.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only two out of the seven churches are commended without rebuke, and Smyrna is one. Let&amp;rsquo;s first notice how much the currency of heaven differs from that of the world. These faithful ones in Smyrna were suffering and impoverished and slandered, and yet regarded by Jesus as rich. Rejoice that the currency of heaven is not that of the world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s also notice that they were slandered by those falsely claiming to be Jews. Slander is speech which is injurious to another&amp;rsquo;s good name. Jesus stands with and commends these slandered ones. And their accusers? A synagogue of Satan! Can you imagine a clearer or harsher or more final judgment? As in Ephesus, those seeming to hold and wield power were utterly rejected by him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could these faithful ones in Smyrna expect to receive for their patient endurance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Do not fear what you are about to suffer. Behold, the devil is about to throw some of you into prison, that you may be tested, and for ten days you will have tribulation. Be faithful unto death, and I will give you the crown of life.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering. Prison. Even greater tribulation. And for some, death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is a test! This time the test is not to endure years of waiting. This is a crisis time distilled into ten days, but let us not underestimate the severity of such testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews tells us what was similarly faced by others so highly commended for their faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some were tortured, refusing to accept release, so that they might rise again to a better life. Others suffered mocking and flogging, and even chains and imprisonment. They were stoned, they were sawn in two, they were killed with the sword.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:35-37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this the reward for faithfulness and patient endurance? By no means! The actual reward is clearly stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Be faithful unto death, and I will give you the crown of life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, have you noticed that for each of the letters to the seven churches, Jesus introduces himself differently, and for each so pertinently to the situation found there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And to the angel of the church in Smyrna write: ‘The words of the first and the last, who died and came to life.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t Jesus reminding those about to face death that that is not the end? Praise him for such grace and kindness and understanding!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul endured hardship and suffering and the prospect of death. What did he have to say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yes, and I will rejoice, for I know that through your prayers and the help of the Spirit of Jesus Christ this will turn out for my deliverance, as it is my eager expectation and hope that I will not be at all ashamed, but that with full courage now as always Christ will be honoured in my body, whether by life or by death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:18b-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is Paul rejoicing even in the face of the danger of death. And what is he most concerned about? That he will not be ashamed, that his courage will withstand, and that Christ may be honoured in his body, whether by life or by death!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this possible? He knew about that crown of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For to me to live is Christ, and to die is gain. If I am to live in the flesh, that means fruitful labour for me. Yet which I shall choose I cannot tell. I am hard pressed between the two. My desire is to depart and be with Christ, for that is far better. But to remain in the flesh is more necessary on your account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:21-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no death wish here, simply a crystal clear understanding of the joys that lie ahead in the heavenly realms. To die is gain, of course it is. To depart and be with Christ is far better. This must be fully understood! Observe and savour Paul&amp;rsquo;s peace and lightness of spirit, that he is able to quip about choosing as if the choice were his own! And through the prayers of the Philippian Christians and the help of the Spirit of Jesus Christ he knows that this will turn out for his deliverance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not neglect to pray for those facing such trials, that they may know the same, and know too that this is not something worth being anxious about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And which of you by being anxious can add a single hour to his span of life?⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 12:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Jesus answered them, “The hour has come for the Son of Man to be glorified. Truly, truly, I say to you, unless a grain of wheat falls into the earth and dies, it remains alone; but if it dies, it bears much fruit. Whoever loves his life loses it, and whoever hates his life in this world will keep it for eternal life. If anyone serves me, he must follow me; and where I am, there will my servant be also. If anyone serves me, the Father will honour him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 12:23-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This challenges us to the very core of our faith, oh how it does! And in all this, do not be eager to make claims about how lightly you hold your own life. This is no easy matter. Peter, bless him, underestimated this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simon Peter said to him, “Lord, where are you going?” Jesus answered him, “Where I am going you cannot follow me now, but you will follow afterward.” Peter said to him, “Lord, why can I not follow you now? I will lay down my life for you.” Jesus answered, “Will you lay down your life for me? Truly, truly, I say to you, the rooster will not crow till you have denied me three times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:36-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he did, as we know. But listen again to Jesus and be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. The one who conquers will not be hurt by the second death.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not love your life, but love the Lord and live for him alone, and look forward to receiving the crown of life, knowing that to live is Christ, and to die is gain! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
