<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>hope on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/hope/</link>
        <description>Recent content in hope on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/hope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Secrets</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/secrets/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/secrets/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/secrets/tim-evans-Uf-c4u1usFQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Secrets" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are there secrets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t mean the kind of secrets those lacking in credibility or legitimacy in leadership use to wield power over others. No, albeit grievous, that is straightforward to understand, just as Jesus said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And this is the judgment: the light has come into the world, and people loved the darkness rather than the light because their works were evil. For everyone who does wicked things hates the light and does not come to the light, lest his works should be exposed. But whoever does what is true comes to the light, so that it may be clearly seen that his works have been carried out in God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:19-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not worry about those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we must all appear before the judgment seat of Christ, so that each one may receive what is due for what he has done in the body, whether good or evil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 5:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I mean these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the LORD our God, but the things that are revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may do all the words of this law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/deuteronomy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 29:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret things belong to the Lord our God. Why are there such things that are secret? And why is it that so many of the most important things we would like to know seem to fall into this category, especially answers to those most desperate questions of Why? and How long?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And isn&amp;rsquo;t this at odds with what Jesus said?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You are my friends if you do what I command you. No longer do I call you servants, for the servant does not know what his master is doing; but I have called you friends, for all that I have heard from my Father I have made known to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 15:14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that Jesus has heard from our Heavenly Father he has made known. We must pause here, for isn&amp;rsquo;t this completely overwhelming in its relational depth? He has called you friend. He has called me friend. The very Son of God who died at Calvary to rescue and redeem the whole world, the Word of Life through whom the universe was made and who sustains it through each moment by his powerful word, this one calls you and me both friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend a few moments here to savour that intimacy in relationship. In our craving to know things, perhaps we have overlooked our wonderful Saviour whom we can know, who has made himself known. For Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And you know the way to where I am going.” Thomas said to him, “Lord, we do not know where you are going. How can we know the way?” Jesus said to him, “I am the way, and the truth, and the life. No one comes to the Father except through me. If you had known me, you would have known my Father also. From now on you do know him and have seen him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:4-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only can we know our wonderful Saviour, but we can know the Holy Spirit who dwells in us. Again, listen to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If you love me, you will keep my commandments. And I will ask the Father, and he will give you another Helper to be with you forever, even the Spirit of truth, whom the world cannot receive, because it neither sees him nor knows him. You know him, for he dwells with you and will be in you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:15-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And not only this, but we can also know that we are in Jesus, for he said exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Yet a little while and the world will see me no more, but you will see me. Because I live, you also will live. In that day you will know that I am in my Father, and you in me, and I in you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 14:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t the truth that so much has been made known that we are in danger of being overwhelmed by it all? For that is absolutely how we should be feeling!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what of those secret things which belong to the Lord our God? Here&amp;rsquo;s one, for example, about that glorious day on which Jesus will come again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But in those days, after that tribulation, the sun will be darkened, and the moon will not give its light, and the stars will be falling from heaven, and the powers in the heavens will be shaken. And then they will see the Son of Man coming in clouds with great power and glory. And then he will send out the angels and gather his elect from the four winds, from the ends of the earth to the ends of heaven.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 13:24-27_&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this in truth what we long for most?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a new heaven and a new earth, for the first heaven and the first earth had passed away, and the sea was no more. And I saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down out of heaven from God, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband. And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man. He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. He will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain anymore, for the former things have passed away.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 21:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When will this be, this most eagerly anticipated day of them all? Jesus says this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But concerning that day or that hour, no one knows, not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 13:32&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus himself does not know it! This is surely one of the most secret things of them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s insight to be gained here over those lesser secrets⸺those matters which so profoundly affect our own lives. O my soul, as you wait on the Lord for his good and faithful promise to be fulfilled, not knowing when or why or how but choosing to surrender to his wisdom and his sovereignty, notice what we do know about that day when Jesus will return, coming on the clouds with great power and glory. It will be the very best day of any of our lives, when all that has been so long awaited will be fulfilled by the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is for all those other secret things. Do not doubt the goodness of the one who holds back on Why? or How long? or even How? But simply trust, and wait with eager anticipation and full assurance for that lesser day which will surely come before that greatest of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not crave to know the secret things which belong to the Lord our God, but trust him on those, and rejoice in these wonderful things which have been revealed which belong to you! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The ordinariness of the spiritual battle</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-ordinariness-of-the-spiritual-battle/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-ordinariness-of-the-spiritual-battle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-ordinariness-of-the-spiritual-battle/denny-muller-FXrcBTOy8Fw-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The ordinariness of the spiritual battle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think the spiritual battle sounds exciting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it is not. It is mundane and energy sapping and potentially also demoralising and faith destroying. Or not. But which it is, you see, is entirely up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For we do not wrestle against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the cosmic powers over this present darkness, against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly places.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 6:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must be wise, for the enemy is cunning and does not show himself. How then does he fight? He fights using broken down cars and cancelled flights and malfunctioning equipment and heavy traffic and spilt drinks. He fights using sickness and frailty and sleeplessness. He fights using bad weather and lost opportunities. He fights using scowling disapproval and the withholding of affirmation. He fights in a myriad of subtle and devious ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He fights and so you too must fight. And how? One who would fight in the spiritual battle must first understand what is being fought over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Count it all joy, my brothers, when you meet trials of various kinds, for you know that the testing of your faith produces steadfastness. And let steadfastness have its full effect, that you may be perfect and complete, lacking in nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 1:2-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is being fought over is your very faith. Will you let it wither and die because of your sense of entitlement, that you should somehow escape what others endure? How can faith become anything at all without testing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand that the enemy&amp;rsquo;s goal for you in the spiritual battle is the opposite of steadfastness, that you become uncertain, uncommitted, fluctuating, faltering, and ultimately too discouraged even to want to continue in the walk of faith. And he has such mundane weapons in his arsenal. But,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ! According to his great mercy, he has caused us to be born again to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, to an inheritance that is imperishable, undefiled, and unfading, kept in heaven for you, who by God&amp;rsquo;s power are being guarded through faith for a salvation ready to be revealed in the last time. In this you rejoice, though now for a little while, if necessary, you have been grieved by various trials, so that the tested genuineness of your faith⸺more precious than gold that perishes though it is tested by fire⸺may be found to result in praise and glory and honour at the revelation of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 1:3-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there not a clear and present danger, that through this testing the things of this world may drag you down or so captivate your heart that you lose your first love?⸺not first chronologically, but first in importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same faith is both the means and the end in this spiritual battle. Take up the shield of faith. Believe what Jesus has said and remember what he has done. The disappointments and frustrations and suffering of this world cannot penetrate that shield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely the psalmist knew this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Out of the mouth of babies and infants, you have established strength because of your foes, to still the enemy and the avenger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 8:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spiritual battle deploy that childlike faith which does not seek to understand, but knows how to trust the one whose name is Faithful and True⸺Jesus Christ the righteous one⸺Jesus the lover of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will rejoice and be glad in your steadfast love, because you have seen my affliction; you have known the distress of my soul, and you have not delivered me into the hand of the enemy; you have set my feet in a broad place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you face these present difficulties, do you think the Lord is somehow ignorant of or indifferent to your affliction? He has seen it, and he has known your distress, O my soul. And he has set your feet in a broad place. In case you have felt trapped by circumstances know that in fact you are free. Because of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s steadfast love and faithfulness, he has set your feet in a broad place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God so that at the proper time he may exalt you, casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. Be sober-minded; be watchful. Your adversary the devil prowls around like a roaring lion, seeking someone to devour. Resist him, firm in your faith, knowing that the same kinds of suffering are being experienced by your brotherhood throughout the world. And after you have suffered a little while, the God of all grace, who has called you to his eternal glory in Christ, will himself restore, confirm, strengthen, and establish you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 5:6-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And listen again to what Jesus said to those Philadelphians, commended without reservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because you have kept my word about patient endurance, I will keep you from the hour of trial that is coming on the whole world, to try those who dwell on the earth. I am coming soon. Hold fast what you have, so that no one may seize your crown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, will you let the mundane troubles and trials of life steal away your peace and security and trust in the Lord? Steal away your faith in a good, wise and kind God of infinite power? Steal away your hope in your future salvation? Steal away the joy of the Lord? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, Jesus is coming soon, so hold fast to faith and hope and love, so that no one may seize your crown! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A new thing</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/a-new-thing/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/a-new-thing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/a-new-thing/tangerine-newt-TN09yTRftZ8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A new thing" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you worry that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will may be thwarted by those who have failed to perceive the new thing that he is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus says the LORD,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Remember not the former things, nor consider the things of old. Behold, I am doing a new thing; now it springs forth, do you not perceive it? I will make a way in the wilderness and rivers in the desert.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:16a, 18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you excited about the new thing that the Lord is doing, because he is indeed doing just that. Are you thirsty for it? The desert is a such a thirsty place but he will make rivers flow there. And he will make a way where there is no way, in this wilderness of unlove. Hallelujah! Hallelujah indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And have you noticed something? Have you noticed the most interesting of timings?⸺those events which have just happened to coincide so as to clear the way for this new thing? This new thing is so heralded, trumpeted by the very angels. And all apparently so very imminent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet at the same time are you not discomfited by the prospect of defeat being snatched from the jaws of victory by those who have not perceived this new thing that the Lord is doing and are standing in the way of it, blocking it from happening, because they are so very busy looking for something else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do you somehow see inevitability in this, a tragedy unfolding inexorably? Are you already grieving over that coming defeat even in advance of it being realised? Do you anticipate that the Lord&amp;rsquo;s perfect plans will in fact be thwarted? Are you even now weeping over it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well then stop that. Put aside your sense of impending doom and listen instead to the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Love the LORD, all you his saints! The LORD preserves the faithful but abundantly repays the one who acts in pride. Be strong, and let your heart take courage, all you who wait for the LORD!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:23-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be strong and let your heart take courage, and pay attention to what the Lord is and is not saying. Did you somehow hear, behold, I am trying to do a new thing if only they would let me? How could you have heard that? Wake up! Wake up and unblock your ears! This is the Almighty Creator God of the Universe. There is no try. Do or not do, that is all. Praise him! And rest in that sure knowledge with peace and confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there&amp;rsquo;s something else here, something interesting. Notice the command to remember not the former things, nor consider the things of old. Is this about leaving behind our own failure and shame? Well yes of course, it&amp;rsquo;s always about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new has come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has delivered us from the domain of darkness and transferred us to the kingdom of his beloved Son, in whom we have redemption, the forgiveness of sins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here in Isaiah there&amp;rsquo;s something else which is so interesting. Let&amp;rsquo;s hear the whole of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus says the LORD, who makes a way in the sea, a path in the mighty waters, who brings forth chariot and horse, army and warrior; they lie down, they cannot rise, they are extinguished, quenched like a wick: “Remember not the former things, nor consider the things of old.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These particular former things are the Lord&amp;rsquo;s parting of the Red Sea so the Israelites could pass safely and escape from their oppressors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus the LORD saved Israel that day from the hand of the Egyptians, and Israel saw the Egyptians dead on the seashore. Israel saw the great power that the LORD used against the Egyptians, so the people feared the LORD, and they believed in the LORD and in his servant Moses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 14:30-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are past events of miraculous deliverance by the Lord. But do not dwell on these⸺the Lord will not part the waters again. Do not long for the miracle of yesterday for it is no longer needed. In our own time we need an entirely new miracle and it is this that the Lord will do, a new thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some will not perceive this new thing. Jesus said as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And no one puts new wine into old wineskins. If he does, the new wine will burst the skins and it will be spilled, and the skins will be destroyed. But new wine must be put into fresh wineskins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And no one after drinking old wine desires new, for he says, ‘The old is good.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 5:37-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is doing a new thing and yet still some will say the old is good. Expect this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in your not remembering, take care to remember. We must not expect a repeat of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s miracle, but we must remember the person and character of God. Hear the Lord speaking through Isaiah again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember this and stand firm, recall it to mind, you transgressors, remember the former things of old; for I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me, declaring the end from the beginning and from ancient times things not yet done, saying, ‘My counsel shall stand, and I will accomplish all my purpose,’ calling a bird of prey from the east, the man of my counsel from a far country. I have spoken, and I will bring it to pass; I have purposed, and I will do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 46:8-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember not but remember. Only three chapters later, is Isaiah contradicting himself? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you simply must remember who God is and what he has done. Marvel at the intricacy of his plans and purposes, the multiple and concurrent factors at play: a bird of prey from the east, a man of his counsel from a far country. And he will do it. What he has purposed he will do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But do not expect him merely to do what he did before. Today he is doing a new thing because today almost everything is different. Almost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember this and stand firm, recall it to mind, you transgressors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 46:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who went before us were wretched sinners and so are we. May we never forget that. And may we never forget how the Lord deals with such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 1:15a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, rest confidently in his sufficiency, marvel at the intricacy of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s perfect plans and purposes, this new thing that he is already doing, and praise him with your whole heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Do not love your life</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-love-your-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-love-your-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/do-not-love-your-life/crawford-jolly-BjQTmNKlawg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Do not love your life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you love your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many do. But what does Jesus expect and require?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“And to the angel of the church in Smyrna write: ‘The words of the first and the last, who died and came to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘I know your tribulation and your poverty (but you are rich) and the slander of those who say that they are Jews and are not, but are a synagogue of Satan.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only two out of the seven churches are commended without rebuke, and Smyrna is one. Let&amp;rsquo;s first notice how much the currency of heaven differs from that of the world. These faithful ones in Smyrna were suffering and impoverished and slandered, and yet regarded by Jesus as rich. Rejoice that the currency of heaven is not that of the world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s also notice that they were slandered by those falsely claiming to be Jews. Slander is speech which is injurious to another&amp;rsquo;s good name. Jesus stands with and commends these slandered ones. And their accusers? A synagogue of Satan! Can you imagine a clearer or harsher or more final judgment? As in Ephesus, those seeming to hold and wield power were utterly rejected by him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could these faithful ones in Smyrna expect to receive for their patient endurance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘Do not fear what you are about to suffer. Behold, the devil is about to throw some of you into prison, that you may be tested, and for ten days you will have tribulation. Be faithful unto death, and I will give you the crown of life.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering. Prison. Even greater tribulation. And for some, death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is a test! This time the test is not to endure years of waiting. This is a crisis time distilled into ten days, but let us not underestimate the severity of such testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews tells us what was similarly faced by others so highly commended for their faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some were tortured, refusing to accept release, so that they might rise again to a better life. Others suffered mocking and flogging, and even chains and imprisonment. They were stoned, they were sawn in two, they were killed with the sword.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:35-37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this the reward for faithfulness and patient endurance? By no means! The actual reward is clearly stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Be faithful unto death, and I will give you the crown of life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, have you noticed that for each of the letters to the seven churches, Jesus introduces himself differently, and for each so pertinently to the situation found there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“And to the angel of the church in Smyrna write: ‘The words of the first and the last, who died and came to life.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t Jesus reminding those about to face death that that is not the end? Praise him for such grace and kindness and understanding!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul endured hardship and suffering and the prospect of death. What did he have to say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yes, and I will rejoice, for I know that through your prayers and the help of the Spirit of Jesus Christ this will turn out for my deliverance, as it is my eager expectation and hope that I will not be at all ashamed, but that with full courage now as always Christ will be honoured in my body, whether by life or by death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:18b-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is Paul rejoicing even in the face of the danger of death. And what is he most concerned about? That he will not be ashamed, that his courage will withstand, and that Christ may be honoured in his body, whether by life or by death!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this possible? He knew about that crown of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For to me to live is Christ, and to die is gain. If I am to live in the flesh, that means fruitful labour for me. Yet which I shall choose I cannot tell. I am hard pressed between the two. My desire is to depart and be with Christ, for that is far better. But to remain in the flesh is more necessary on your account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:21-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no death wish here, simply a crystal clear understanding of the joys that lie ahead in the heavenly realms. To die is gain, of course it is. To depart and be with Christ is far better. This must be fully understood! Observe and savour Paul&amp;rsquo;s peace and lightness of spirit, that he is able to quip about choosing as if the choice were his own! And through the prayers of the Philippian Christians and the help of the Spirit of Jesus Christ he knows that this will turn out for his deliverance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not neglect to pray for those facing such trials, that they may know the same, and know too that this is not something worth being anxious about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And which of you by being anxious can add a single hour to his span of life?⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 12:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Jesus answered them, “The hour has come for the Son of Man to be glorified. Truly, truly, I say to you, unless a grain of wheat falls into the earth and dies, it remains alone; but if it dies, it bears much fruit. Whoever loves his life loses it, and whoever hates his life in this world will keep it for eternal life. If anyone serves me, he must follow me; and where I am, there will my servant be also. If anyone serves me, the Father will honour him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 12:23-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This challenges us to the very core of our faith, oh how it does! And in all this, do not be eager to make claims about how lightly you hold your own life. This is no easy matter. Peter, bless him, underestimated this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simon Peter said to him, “Lord, where are you going?” Jesus answered him, “Where I am going you cannot follow me now, but you will follow afterward.” Peter said to him, “Lord, why can I not follow you now? I will lay down my life for you.” Jesus answered, “Will you lay down your life for me? Truly, truly, I say to you, the rooster will not crow till you have denied me three times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:36-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he did, as we know. But listen again to Jesus and be encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. The one who conquers will not be hurt by the second death.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not love your life, but love the Lord and live for him alone, and look forward to receiving the crown of life, knowing that to live is Christ, and to die is gain! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The trust test</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-trust-test/guzman-barquin-Qd688l1yDOI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The trust test" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How important is it to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I say trust, I mean completely depend upon him, fully committed, with no way out and no room for doubt. No wavering. No second guessing. None at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus said &amp;hellip; “Do not fear, only believe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 5:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such trust is life and health and strength. Why would anyone not live like this? And yet many do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall with me the sorry saga of the Israelites failing to trust the Lord, their ongoing enslavement to fear and uncertainty and doubt. And recall too the Lord&amp;rsquo;s uncompromising response, his righteous anger burning against them, his chosen people, his beloved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What reason did the Israelites have to trust the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the sight of their fathers he performed wonders in the land of Egypt, in the fields of Zoan. He divided the sea and let them pass through it, and made the waters stand like a heap. In the daytime he led them with a cloud, and all the night with a fiery light. He split rocks in the wilderness and gave them drink abundantly as from the deep. He made streams come out of the rock and caused waters to flow down like rivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:12-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the God who miraculously delivered his people from slavery in Egypt, parting the waters of the Red Sea so they could pass safely. And led them through the desert, miraculously guiding them and remaining with them. And slaked their thirst in the desert, again, miraculously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he fed them with manna from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Moses, “Behold, I am about to rain bread from heaven for you, and the people shall go out and gather a day&amp;rsquo;s portion every day, that I may test them, whether they will walk in my law or not.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 16:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was the test. This is the trust test. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that the Israelites faced time and again. It&amp;rsquo;s the test that we ourselves face time and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how did they do, those Israelites, those chosen people, those beloved ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They forgot his works and the wonders that he had shown them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They forgot all the reasons they had to trust him! Their earlier fear of the Lord and belief in him was so feeble it had simply evaporated like the morning mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet they sinned still more against him, rebelling against the Most High in the desert. They tested God in their heart by demanding the food they craved. They spoke against God, saying, “Can God spread a table in the wilderness? He struck the rock so that water gushed out and streams overflowed. Can he also give bread or provide meat for his people?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:17-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the sneering doubt here, the sheer contempt for their provider, the complete absence of trust? O my soul, be appalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, when the LORD heard, he was full of wrath; a fire was kindled against Jacob; his anger rose against Israel, because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I do not want you to be unaware, brothers, that our fathers were all under the cloud, and all passed through the sea, and all were baptized into Moses in the cloud and in the sea, and all ate the same spiritual food, and all drank the same spiritual drink. For they drank from the spiritual Rock that followed them, and the Rock was Christ. Nevertheless, with most of them God was not pleased, for they were overthrown in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They drank from the Rock which was Christ no less and yet they failed the trust test. Overthrown means struck down. In judgment for their lack of trust most of them were struck down by the Lord, their hitherto protector and provider, the Faithful One. Most of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The anger of God rose against them, and he killed the strongest of them and laid low the young men of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Because they did not believe in God and did not trust his saving power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 78:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how important it is to trust, to believe, to depend upon the Lord without wavering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of our own trust test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even when things are very dark indeed you must trust the Lord and depend upon him relentlessly. He is faithful and true. Never doubt that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who among you fears the LORD and obeys the voice of his servant? Let him who walks in darkness and has no light trust in the name of the LORD and rely on his God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 50:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is tested when our lives are at stake, when our hearts are breaking, when things are entirely beyond us and all we can do is depend upon the Lord, upon his faithfulness to all that he has promised and to all that he is, when the way ahead is unseeable. But without the unseeable there can be no faith! O my soul, will you trust him then? Will you trust him now? Will you continue to trust him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now hope that is seen is not hope. For who hopes for what he sees? But if we hope for what we do not see, we wait for it with patience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in this waiting time of unseeing are you tempted to doubt? Are you tempted to despair? Are you tempted to run ahead of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will in your own strength? Resist! You must resist! Hold on to what is true. Hold on to the one whose name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No temptation has overtaken you that is not common to man. God is faithful, and he will not let you be tempted beyond your ability, but with the temptation he will also provide the way of escape, that you may be able to endure it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can endure this, O my soul. Repudiate doubt and all that drags you down, and trust him. Trust him! You must endure with steadfast faith, believing and not doubting. Trust Jesus, whose name is Faithful and True!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The penalty for failing the truth test is severe, as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen. For standing firm, however, there are two stupendous prizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him, and he will act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in him, O my soul, and he will act!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD’s delight is in those who fear him, those who put their hope in his unfailing love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 147:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing this, by walking this path of trust and dependence and unwavering hope in him, waiting with patience, you can delight our Heavenly Father. You can delight him! What more motivation could you have to choose to trust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 15:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, put all your hope in his unfailing love and trust in the faithfulness of your Heavenly Father, and so delight him! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My strength is almost gone</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/todd-trapani-v2Jf_jpNamc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My strength is almost gone" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you weary? So very weary? So weary in fact that you wonder whether you can carry on at all, even not quite knowing what that would mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is it that we are commanded to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be patient in tribulation. And go on being patient. And on. And on. Being patient. In tribulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when will it all end? Will it ever end? How can you continue to endure this, O my soul? Isn&amp;rsquo;t the prolonged nature of it all simply wearing you down?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you made Job&amp;rsquo;s heart-cry your very own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I don’t have the strength to endure. I have nothing to live for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 6:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will it ever end? What is there to live for? Does anything even matter any more?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my Soul, listen to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By your endurance you will gain your lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 21:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is speaking of the great tribulation, but it makes no difference. By your endurance you will gain your life, O my soul. Your endurance matters then, O how it matters! Your life depends upon it. But what is it exactly? What is this endurance by which you will gain your life, beyond simply managing to exist through the trial? What indeed? And where will this endurance come from, that you may live?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s first consider the why, and through that understand the what and the how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have need of endurance, so that when you have done the will of God you may receive what is promised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you want to receive what is promised? Do you want to receive what has been promised from the one whose name is Faithful and True? Then you have need of endurance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This endurance is what will enable you to do the will of God, and to keep on doing it. So now we must ask, what is the will of God here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then they said to him, “What must we do, to be doing the works of God?” Jesus answered them, “This is the work of God, that you believe in him whom he has sent.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 6:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is it. This is what it means to endure. Believe in Jesus, the one whom the Lord has sent! Above all else this means trust him. Trust him, absolutely and completely, and depend upon him, and on him alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Trust in the LORD with all your heart, and do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make straight your paths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 3:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own understanding is quite simply not up to the task. This is entirely beyond me. O my soul, at that point beyond which you cannot understand what or why or how, you must surrender your need to understand, and simply trust the one who does⸺the one whose name is Faithful and True. Trust Jesus! And depend on him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be mindful that straight does not mean easy, but it does mean that there is a way. There is a way ahead, and by taking one step after another on this straight path, trusting and not doubting, you can continue. You can continue, O my soul, so do that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as you resolve to continue to take this path ahead, wondering whether you have the strength even for that, you must understand where strength comes from. It comes from hope. Hold on to hope. The one who promised is Faithful and True. Rejoice in that hope!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength comes from hope. It comes from trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who trust in the LORD will find new strength. They will soar high on wings like eagles. They will run and not grow weary. They will walk and not faint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:31 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my Soul, I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to soaring on wings like an eagle, as that may be inconceivable for now. But know this. The word used for trust is the Hebrew &lt;em&gt;qâvâh&lt;/em&gt;, which could be translated wait for, or hope in, or expect. Yes, more waiting. More waiting, O my soul, but waiting in hope. And rejoicing in that hope. Paul and Isaiah are perfectly aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope. Trust in and depend on Jesus, that he may be the one to lift you up. Oh, and be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in the Lord, O my soul, and find there new strength to carry on! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>That was yesterday</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/that-was-yesterday/istrfry-marcus-NX0WjgdQl58-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post That was yesterday" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened yesterday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were you hoping for great things? Were you expecting great things? And are you tempted to say, “nothing”? That nothing happened? (You would be so very wrong about that, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that nothing happened yesterday, now what? What will you do now? Where is hope? How can hope survive the passing of yet another day, the unrelenting accumulation of which become inexorable years? How can faith survive this, O my soul? How will this rollercoaster of expectation and disappointment not simply grind you down into the dust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How indeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how. There are three reasons. The first reason is to understand that disappointment is a lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointment is a lie because it presupposes failure. But what failure would that be, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Joshua, now old and well advanced in years, passing on some wisdom at the end of his own life to those who would come after him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And now I am about to go the way of all the earth, and you know in your hearts and souls, all of you, that not one word has failed of all the good things that the LORD your God promised concerning you. All have come to pass for you; not one of them has failed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/joshua&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Joshua 23:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not one of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s promises had failed, nor has failed, nor will fail. Know that he is faithful and true, O my soul, to all that he has said, and to all that he is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that what you were hoping for yesterday didn&amp;rsquo;t happen, what you were expecting, what you were so committed in faith to receiving, then listen to the Lord himself, speaking through Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me, declaring the end from the beginning and from ancient times things not yet done, saying, ‘My counsel shall stand, and I will accomplish all my purpose,’ calling a bird of prey from the east, the man of my counsel from a far country. I have spoken, and I will bring it to pass; I have purposed, and I will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 46:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sure, there are things not yet done, but there is none like God, declaring the end from the beginning, from ancient times. O my soul, he will do it! He will accomplish all he has purposed! Know that nothing has failed. Trust him still and praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason is because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts. Poured out for you, O my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we have been justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ. Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope, and hope does not put us to shame, because God&amp;rsquo;s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will have to return another time to rejoicing in our sufferings but for now consider just that final verse, for which the Berean Standard Bible rendition is particularly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And hope does not disappoint us, because God has poured out His love into our hearts through the Holy Spirit, whom He has given us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:5 BSB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope does not disappoint. God himself is both the giver and the one who pours. It is his own great love. He poured out that same love at Calvary, O my soul. Rejoice in hope of the glory of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and final reason is to understand at least something of what did actually happen yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was I hoping for? Isaiah knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Oh that you would rend the heavens and come down, that the mountains might quake at your presence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that the Creator God of the Universe, awesome in power and terrifying in purity but also so very good and kind, would break into this impossible situation, breathing out grace and truth and power into my own life and those around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So did he?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From of old no one has heard or perceived by the ear, no eye has seen a God besides you, who acts for those who wait for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 64:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah tells us that the Lord acts. Not that he will act, or even that he did act, but that he acts, in the present tense. He is working right now with great power for those who wait for him. Will you be that, O my soul? Will you continue to be that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is it that he is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habbakuk knows and it cannot be told. The Lord himself declares it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Look among the nations, and see; wonder and be astounded. For I am doing a work in your days that you would not believe if told.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/habakkuk&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Habakkuk 1:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonder and be astounded, O my soul, at what the Lord is already doing in your life, and renounce disappointment! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>This is the day!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/this-is-the-day/robert-lukeman-_RBcxo9AU-U-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post This is the day!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do you expect change will come?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After so many years spent hoping and trusting, holding on to your promise from the Lord and yet still waiting, are you tempted to give up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or do you still somehow expect that the Lord will act with great power to fulfil that promise? And when exactly do you expect that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one answer which honours the Lord and that is today. You must continue to expect it and you must expect it today! It is imperative that you do so. Your very faith depends upon it. Your life and health and strength depend upon it. How else could you live a life that honours him, other than in complete trust and dependence upon him, and other than in expectation of the imminent outworking of his great power in your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who promised is indeed faithful. His very name is Faithful and True (Rev 19:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is it quite so important to hold fast to this hope, this expectation of imminent fulfilment, without wavering?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the midst of a spiritual battle and the fighting is fierce. To expect anything other than imminent fulfilment would open the door to doubt ⸺that doubt which is so ready to creep in and steal away hope and joy and expectation. That doubt which would cause all to unravel and expose the tattered remains of a faith which once was. That doubt which must be resisted with all strength. Be steadfast, O my soul! Cry out to the Faithful One, Lord I believe! Help my unbelief!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Ahab sent to all the people of Israel and gathered the prophets together at Mount Carmel. And Elijah came near to all the people and said, “How long will you go limping between two different opinions? If the LORD is God, follow him; but if Baal, then follow him.” And the people did not answer him a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they took the bull that was given them, and they prepared it and called upon the name of Baal from morning until noon, saying, “O Baal, answer us!” But there was no voice, and no one answered. And they limped around the altar that they had made. And at noon Elijah mocked them, saying, “Cry aloud, for he is a god. Either he is musing, or he is relieving himself, or he is on a journey, or perhaps he is asleep and must be awakened.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:20-21, 26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, are you tempted to such thoughts while you wait on the living God, the God of your life? Repudiate them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And at the time of the offering of the oblation, Elijah the prophet came near and said, “O LORD, God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let it be known this day that you are God in Israel, and that I am your servant, and that I have done all these things at your word. Answer me, O LORD, answer me, that this people may know that you, O LORD, are God, and that you have turned their hearts back.” Then the fire of the LORD fell and consumed the burnt offering and the wood and the stones and the dust, and licked up the water that was in the trench. And when all the people saw it, they fell on their faces and said, “The LORD, he is God; the LORD, he is God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-kings&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Kings 18:36-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord, he is God! Praise him, O my soul!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s answer to our most earnest praying, the outworking of his mighty strength in our lives to fulfil all that he has promised, is that all may know that the Lord, he is God! And his grace and kindness is that you, O my soul, may know it. Expect it today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our experience of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power being outworked in our lives is limited only by our faith to believe it, our faith to receive it. This is why it is quite so important that we do not hold back in expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And as Jesus passed on from there, two blind men followed him, crying aloud, “Have mercy on us, Son of David.” When he entered the house, the blind men came to him, and Jesus said to them, “Do you believe that I am able to do this?” They said to him, “Yes, Lord.” Then he touched their eyes, saying, “According to your faith be it done to you.” And their eyes were opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 9:27-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you believe that he is able to do this? According to your faith be it done to you. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s yet more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him. Whoever believes in him is not condemned, but whoever does not believe is condemned already, because he has not believed in the name of the only Son of God.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you dare to believe, O my soul, of the only Son of God. Do not hold back in expectation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the day that the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the day, O my soul! Expect great things in it! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hope in God</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 07:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/hope-in-god/jeremy-bishop-DLICfSD33as-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hope in God" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you downcast?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your life not as it once was? Are you grieving for things that once were and are no longer?  So was the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These things I remember, as I pour out my soul: how I would go with the throng and lead them in procession to the house of God with glad shouts and songs of praise, a multitude keeping festival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a man who used to live a life of affirmation and exaltation. But things changed and he became a pariah, even in his own church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As with a deadly wound in my bones, my adversaries taunt me, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, O my soul, does the Lord seem to have withdrawn? Are you no longer enjoying that intimacy, the sweetness of his felt presence in your life? Nor was the psalmist. But the desire for that had not left him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My soul thirsts for God, for the living God. When shall I come and appear before God? My tears have been my food day and night, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multitude keeping festival, those privileged and self-satisfied ones, had closed ranks, and he was no longer among them. And it seemed to him that God himself had passed him by, forgotten him, rejected him. He was oppressed, scorned, and despised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any hope? Is anything to be done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why are you cast down, O my soul, and why are you in turmoil within me? Hope in God; for I shall again praise him, my salvation and my God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:5-6, also v11 and Psalm 43:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you cast down, O my soul? This is not a question in search of an answer. This is a rebuke. It is a rebuke delivered to one who has taken their eyes off the Lord, and has become overwhelmed by their own difficulties and disappointments, defeated by them and yet dwelling in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in God, O my soul! Hope in the only one in whom you really can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul does indeed thirst for God. But where is hope?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By day the LORD commands his steadfast love, and at night his song is with me, a prayer to the God of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 42:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His love is steadfast. All his paths are steadfast love and faithfulness (Psalm 25:10). And he is the God of my life⸺the God of my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is not ignorant of nor indifferent to what is happening in my life. He has plans and purposes for me that are beyond my understanding. He is ambitious for me in ways that would blow my mind if I only knew. He is transforming me into the likeness of Christ, and he knows how to do it, O how he knows! He is the God of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What must I do then? I must trust. I must trust the God of my life, who knows his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is this song that is with me through the night, when tears are my only food? The psalmist knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is my strength and my song; he has become my salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 118:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Behold, God is my salvation; I will trust, and will not be afraid; for the LORD GOD is my strength and my song, and he has become my salvation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these are borrowed words. They are Moses&amp;rsquo; words. This is Moses&amp;rsquo; song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is my strength and my song, and he has become my salvation; this is my God, and I will praise him, my father&amp;rsquo;s God, and I will exalt him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 15:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is the context of Moses&amp;rsquo; song?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Moses stretched out his hand over the sea, and the LORD drove the sea back by a strong east wind all night and made the sea dry land, and the waters were divided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the LORD saved Israel that day from the hand of the Egyptians, and Israel saw the Egyptians dead on the seashore. Israel saw the great power that the LORD used against the Egyptians, so the people feared the LORD, and they believed in the LORD and in his servant Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 14:21, 30-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song must be the refrain of your life: the habit of remembering who the Lord is and what he has done. It is the habit of remembering as you do the dishes, as you drive to work, as you grapple with the challenges of life. It is the habit of remembering the God of your life and the great power that he uses to rescue those he loves. Dwell in that, my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not underestimate the discipline and determination required to sing this song, to make it the habit of your life, but this you must do, single-mindedly, doggedly, courageously.  It is a matter of life and death. Take your eyes off yourself, look to the Lord and hope in him.  There is no other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in the Lord, O my soul, for there is no other! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
