<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>anger on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/anger/</link>
        <description>Recent content in anger on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/anger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Do not be angry</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/cas-holmes-_zyt1WWWdv4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Do not be angry" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that righteous anger we examined last week the right response to all the sin in the world, that sin which corrupts and stains everything, that sin which we see all around us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus came to the temple on another occasion, and this visit was so very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Early in the morning he came again to the temple. All the people came to him, and he sat down and taught them. The scribes and the Pharisees brought a woman who had been caught in adultery, and placing her in the midst they said to him, “Teacher, this woman has been caught in the act of adultery. Now in the Law, Moses commanded us to stone such women. So what do you say?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:2-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this woman epitomise all that&amp;rsquo;s wrong with society? Everyone choosing to do what they want with no regard for God&amp;rsquo;s holy law, and no regard for the cost in human suffering and shame? Surely that righteous anger is the fitting response to such a thing, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pharisees were clearly angry, but let&amp;rsquo;s pause for a moment and look into the reason for their anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This they said to test him, that they might have some charge to bring against him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth they didn&amp;rsquo;t really care about honouring the Lord, and they certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t care about the woman herself⸺she evidently meant nothing to them. They were out to test Jesus, to bring a charge against him, to bring him down. Perhaps they saw him as soft on sin, or at least soft on sinners. Their aim was to trap him into contradicting the law so that they could discredit him. Is this not precisely the behaviour of vain and dishonest men of rank? Theirs was so clearly not a righteous anger then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of Jesus&amp;rsquo; righteous anger that we saw previously?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus bent down and wrote with his finger on the ground. And as they continued to ask him, he stood up and said to them, “Let him who is without sin among you be the first to throw a stone at her.” And once more he bent down and wrote on the ground. But when they heard it, they went away one by one, beginning with the older ones, and Jesus was left alone with the woman standing before him. Jesus stood up and said to her, “Woman, where are they? Has no one condemned you?” She said, “No one, Lord.” And Jesus said, “Neither do I condemn you; go, and from now on sin no more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:6b-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon being confronted with their own sinfulness, and beginning with the older ones, they went away one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning with the older ones. Perhaps only eventually do each of us understand how far we fall short. Is there not sometimes a harshness to be seen among the younger generation in their zealous pursuit of what is right and true? Perhaps only with the passage of time and the humble recognition of ongoing failure and shame in our own lives is each of us able to say with Paul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 1:15b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s put aside then that righteous anger that Jesus would have been feeling towards those vain and dishonest men of rank, and ask, what was he feeling towards the adulterous woman?⸺for the answer to that addresses our opening question on how we should respond to all that sin and brokenness we see in the world, that sin which corrupts all. Notice what he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus stood up and said to her, “Woman, where are they? Has no one condemned you?” She said, “No one, Lord.” And Jesus said, “Neither do I condemn you; go, and from now on sin no more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus did not condemn and he does not condemn, but it matters that each one sin no more. O my soul, from now on sin no more. Your Saviour demands it! And listen to Jesus explain why he came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so the answer is compassion, not anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Father&amp;rsquo;s compassion for our broken and dysfunctional world and our own brokenness was the reason for sending his only Son to rescue and redeem, to die at Calvary where that great love was poured out for all, and to rise again in resurrection victory and power over sin and death and all that corrupts and spoils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do need to pause however and ask whether the Pharisees had a point. In all his compassion, is Jesus in fact soft on sin? And if his sacrifice at Calvary was sufficient to pay the debt of eight billion sinners, why would we any longer be concerned about the sin that remains. Cannot all be forgiven?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not so quickly forget Jesus&amp;rsquo; final words to the adulterous woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go, and from now on sin no more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:11b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else did Jesus have to say about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whoever causes one of these little ones who believe in me to sin, it would be better for him if a great millstone were hung around his neck and he were thrown into the sea. And if your hand causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life crippled than with two hands to go to hell to the unquenchable fire. And if your foot causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life lame than with two feet to be thrown into hell. And if your eye causes you to sin, tear it out. It is better for you to enter the kingdom of God with one eye than with two eyes to be thrown into hell, ‘where their worm does not die and the fire is not quenched.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 9:42-48&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are these the words of one who is soft on sin? O my soul, you must purge the sin from your own life, and you must be ruthless in this. Do not tolerate it any longer. Do not be deceived⸺look ahead to what will happen at the end of this present age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a great white throne and him who was seated on it. From his presence earth and sky fled away, and no place was found for them. And I saw the dead, great and small, standing before the throne, and books were opened. Then another book was opened, which is the book of life. And the dead were judged by what was written in the books, according to what they had done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 20:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tremble at these things, and be grateful for the book of life, written at such great cost by the author of life. Such is compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So thank and praise the Lord for his compassion which rescues and redeems. Put aside your righteous anger before it becomes self-righteousness, soften your heart, and reach out with compassion and kindness and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great rescue for this broken world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, learn to live with humility as one who was once lost and is now saved, put aside that anger, and put on a grateful and compassionate heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Be angry</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/be-angry/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/be-angry/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/be-angry/todd-trapani-91T-rq-pY28-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Be angry" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you make of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry. Why? It is commanded! And in that, do not sin. How? How can this be done? We&amp;rsquo;ll need to give some serious thought to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by considering the new life that is in Christ. Paul sets the context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God. Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth. For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God.  When Christ who is your life appears, then you also will appear with him in glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not progress past this too quickly⸺it is heady truth indeed! I have died and my life is hidden with Christ in God. My eternal being is secure and unassailable. Indeed my very life is Christ. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then? Paul continues in typical fashion with a therefore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Put to death therefore what is earthly in you: sexual immorality, impurity, passion, evil desire, and covetousness, which is idolatry. On account of these the wrath of God is coming. In these you too once walked, when you were living in them. But now you must put them all away: anger, wrath, malice, slander, and obscene talk from your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these have any place in the new life, and of these things that must be put away, did you notice that anger appeared first in the list? But still,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may conclude that there are two different kinds of anger. And indeed the words are different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the anger which must be put aside, having no place in the new life in Christ, Paul uses the Greek word &lt;em&gt;orgē&lt;/em&gt;, which is an anger full of emotion, violent passion in fact. This is the anger of not getting one&amp;rsquo;s own way. It is the anger of a bruised ego. And the word used for wrath means rage or passion. It is selfish, even childish in its inability to show restraint. Those must be put aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist wrote in Hebrew, which precludes direct comparison, but Paul also writes of the anger of the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry and do not sin; do not let the sun go down on your anger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here he uses the Greek word &lt;em&gt;parorgismos&lt;/em&gt;, which means indignation or wrath or exasperation. This is not rage. This is a righteous anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the command is to be angry with that righteous anger, with indignation at what ought not to be. But what is that? What should be the object of such anger? To answer that let&amp;rsquo;s consider what was the object of Jesus&amp;rsquo; anger⸺for from time to time he was indeed angry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s one example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And they came to Jerusalem. And he entered the temple and began to drive out those who sold and those who bought in the temple, and he overturned the tables of the money-changers and the seats of those who sold pigeons. And he would not allow anyone to carry anything through the temple. And he was teaching them and saying to them, “Is it not written, ‘My house shall be called a house of prayer for all the nations?’ But you have made it a den of robbers.” And the chief priests and the scribes heard it and were seeking a way to destroy him, for they feared him, because all the crowd was astonished at his teaching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who were the subject of his anger were very much on the inside of the religious establishment of the day, but their behaviour was brazen in its dishonouring of the Lord. Worthy of anger, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you agree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way each gospel writer orders their account is interesting and surely rich in meaning. There&amp;rsquo;s just such a juxtaposition here which must be noticed, for this account of Jesus clearing the temple is immediately followed by this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As they passed by in the morning, they saw the fig tree withered away to its roots. And Peter remembered and said to him, “Rabbi, look! The fig tree that you cursed has withered.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you recall how I &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;grappled previously&lt;/a&gt; with this hard teaching of the poor little fig tree being cursed for failing to bear figs out of season?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; anger with that fig tree paralleled his anger with the Pharisees⸺those heinously prideful ones who should have been fruitful for the Kingdom but were not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s return to our psalm and observe the context out of which it is written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Answer me when I call, O God of my righteousness! You have given me relief when I was in distress. Be gracious to me and hear my prayer!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the psalm as a whole we see a man earnestly desiring to live a right life before the Lord while being so very aware of his dependence upon the Lord for that. O my soul, do you know this humble passion for personal holiness combined with complete dependence on Christ for his righteousness? I know that you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist has been in distress previously, and is again, and why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O men, how long shall my honour be turned into shame? How long will you love vain words and seek after lies?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is despised and rejected by vain and dishonest men. And who are they? Their description is nuanced, literally &lt;em&gt;sons of men&lt;/em&gt;. The ESV alternative translation renders it &lt;em&gt;men of rank&lt;/em&gt;. So, privileged ones. Exalted ones. Vain and dishonest. Pharisees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry, O my soul, you must be angry at that which ought not to be, that which so dishonours the Lord, that pride and hypocrisy. And do not sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how are we not to sin in this? There are two ways. The psalmist tells us the first right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin; ponder in your own hearts on your beds, and be silent. Offer right sacrifices, and put your trust in the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own righteous anger know that you are not called to table-flipping and temple-clearing. That is Jesus&amp;rsquo; work. Ponder on your bed and be silent. Put your trust in the Lord. Do you think he hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen this heinous behaviour? Do you think he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know? Do you think he won&amp;rsquo;t respond?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Paul tells us the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry and do not sin; do not let the sun go down on your anger, and give no opportunity to the devil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? Do not let the sun go down on your anger. Do not hold on to it. You must lay it down and let it go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Beloved, never avenge yourselves, but leave it to the wrath of God, for it is written, “Vengeance is mine, I will repay, says the Lord.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And where does that leave the psalmist? Blessed and at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have put more joy in my heart than they have when their grain and wine abound. In peace I will both lie down and sleep; for you alone, O LORD, make me dwell in safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be angry and do not sin! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The dam on the river</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-dam-on-the-river/vlad-d-5j6tOZ4LdN4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The dam on the river" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you build a dam across the river of living water? Would you reduce to a trickle that which has been flowing so abundantly? Would you be a busy little beaver, hoarding and assembling your pain and disappointment and cementing it all in place with  unforgiveness and resentment? Would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that I do understand why you would want to build your dam. I acknowledge that you have been treated heinously and that you have been brushed aside and disregarded. And I know that you&amp;rsquo;re hurting, really hurting, and from time to time you want to assert that nobody cares. You want to shout it out across the rooftops at the top of your voice: nobody cares. It&amp;rsquo;s a lie, by the way, that nobody cares. For sure, there are some who don&amp;rsquo;t, perhaps several, and others who are only pretending. But there remain those who are loving and kind and faithful and true. Be grateful for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those insolent ones whose behaviour has been so heinous⸺those who should care and yet do not? Beware, my soul, of how you regard them in return. This is perilous ground indeed upon which you stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul. This means that you must forgive and you must let go of all resentment. You must do these things! And you must not build that dam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me remind you just what is at stake here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, ‘Out of his heart will flow rivers of living water.’” Now this he said about the Spirit, whom those who believed in him were to receive, for as yet the Spirit had not been given, because Jesus was not yet glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 7:37-39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you thirst? Do you thirst for love and wholeness and relational authenticity? Come to Jesus and drink. Believe in him and listen to him. Listen to him in your sorrow and pain and dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But I say to you, Do not resist the one who is evil. But if anyone slaps you on the right cheek, turn to him the other also.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:39&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Judge not, and you will not be judged; condemn not, and you will not be condemned; forgive, and you will be forgiven; give, and it will be given to you. Good measure, pressed down, shaken together, running over, will be put into your lap. For with the measure you use it will be measured back to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37-38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive and you will be forgiven. Extend love and kindness to those who do not, and it will be measured back to you, O my soul, how it will! And rivers of living water will flow out of your heart and you will be a blessing to many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t the way these insolent ones carry on simply egregious? Yes of course it is, and appallingly so. What&amp;rsquo;s to be done then about their heinous behaviour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin; ponder in your own hearts on your beds, and be silent. Offer right sacrifices, and put your trust in the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry, O my soul. Be angry and do not sin. Notice it is “and” not “but”. Interesting! The dam on the river is not made of anger. Was Jesus angry when he cleared the temple? Yes of course he was and rightly so. There is a righteous anger and it is of the Lord. Be angry and do not sin. The behaviour is egregious and it cannot be excused. It can only be forgiven, and this you must do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And listen to the heart-cry of the Psalmist to the Lord. Make it your own as you put your trust in the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal bountifully with your servant, that I may live and keep your word. Open my eyes, that I may behold
wondrous things out of your law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You rebuke the insolent, accursed ones, who wander from your commandments. Take away from me scorn and contempt, for I have kept your testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:17-18, 21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord himself is the one who rebukes these insolent ones. And there&amp;rsquo;s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word of the LORD came to me: “Son of man, prophesy against the shepherds of Israel; prophesy, and say to them, even to the shepherds, Thus says the Lord GOD: Ah, shepherds of Israel who have been feeding yourselves! Should not shepherds feed the sheep? You eat the fat, you clothe yourselves with the wool, you slaughter the fat ones, but you do not feed the sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says the Lord GOD, Behold, I am against the shepherds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:1-3,10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is good news indeed for these poor sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I myself will be the shepherd of my sheep, and I myself will make them lie down, declares the Lord GOD. I will seek the lost, and I will bring back the strayed, and I will bind up the injured, and I will strengthen the weak, and the fat and the strong I will destroy. I will feed them in justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beware, O my soul, there is a warning also to these very same sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it not enough for you to feed on the good pasture, that you must tread down with your feet the rest of your pasture; and to drink of clear water, that you must muddy the rest of the water with your feet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will rescue my flock; they shall no longer be a prey. And I will judge between sheep and sheep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ezekiel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ezekiel 34:18,22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then are we to do? Two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Forgive, and you will be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 6:37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you pour yourself out for the hungry and satisfy the desire of the afflicted, then shall your light rise in the darkness and your gloom be as the noonday. And the LORD will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must do what those insolent ones will not, and then you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water. You must forgive, and love and care for the hungry and the afflicted, and pursue humility and hope and joy in the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, O my soul, for from it flow the springs of life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
