<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>gentleness on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/gentleness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in gentleness on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/gentleness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Knitting</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/knitting/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/knitting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/knitting/tanaphong-toochinda-WddCult7llk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Knitting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you know about knitting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the Apostle Paul&amp;rsquo;s most earnest desire for the Colossians and for those at Laodicea and for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I want you to know how great a struggle I have for you and for those at Laodicea and for all who have not seen me face to face, that their hearts may be encouraged, being knit together in love, to reach all the riches of full assurance of understanding and the knowledge of God&amp;rsquo;s mystery, which is Christ, in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul desires that hearts may be encouraged by being knit together in love.  So let&amp;rsquo;s think about knitting for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essence of knitting is that the integrity of the whole garment is determined by the integrity of each and every stitch.  Every stitch matters for if any single one fails the whole garment unravels into a tangled and useless mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each and every one matters, and the integrity and well-being of each and every one is essential to the integrity and well-being of the whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not only is it about being knit together, it is about being knit together &lt;em&gt;in love&lt;/em&gt;.  It is only love which can provide stitches of sufficient strength to withstand the trials of life and the attacks of the evil one.  Paul expands upon this in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I therefore, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to walk in a manner worthy of the calling to which you have been called, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; speaking the truth in love, we are to grow up in every way into him who is the head, into Christ, from whom the whole body, joined and held together by every joint with which it is equipped, when each part is working properly, makes the body grow so that it builds itself up in love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:1-2,15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word for held together is the very same as our word for knitting.  The whole body is knit together by each and every joint with which it is equipped, by each and every one, and this is from Christ, so that the body builds itself up in love.  It is entirely love and building up and knitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each part must be working properly.  O my soul, is each part in fact working properly?  Or are some parts neglected or rejected or denied the freedom to function as intended by the Creator?  The body must build itself up in love.  It must! And every stitch must be protected and nourished and cherished. It must!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is Paul&amp;rsquo;s exhortation here quite so earnest and so urgent.  He tells us precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I say this in order that no one may delude you with plausible arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See to it that no one takes you captive by philosophy and empty deceit, according to human tradition, according to the elemental spirits of the world, and not according to Christ. For in him the whole fullness of deity dwells bodily, and you have been filled in him, who is the head of all rule and authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore let no one pass judgment on you in questions of food and drink, or with regard to a festival or a new moon or a Sabbath. These are a shadow of the things to come, but the substance belongs to Christ. Let no-one disqualify you, insisting on asceticism and worship of angels, going on in detail about visions, puffed up without reason by his sensuous mind, and not holding fast to the Head, from whom the whole body, nourished and knit together through its joints and ligaments, grows with a growth that is from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:4,8-10,16-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware!  The danger here is from within the church, and it is real and present.  Beware those who go on about visions, puffed up without reason by self-importance and their sensuous minds.  Beware oh-so-plausible arguments.  Beware those who insist on asceticism.  Beware empty deceit according to human tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will save us from these real and present dangers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk in him, rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christ who saves, and we must be abounding in thanksgiving, for thanksgiving is the great leveller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified by his grace as a gift, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:23-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is thanksgiving that says I am nothing but a recipient of unmerited grace, and yet at the same time this unmerited grace is all I need.  Thank you Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what?  Paul already told us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I therefore, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to walk in a manner worthy of the calling to which you have been called, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let each one walk worthy with the humility that comes from being rescued, with gentleness and patience, bearing with one another in love.  Imagine if we all stuck to our knitting, loving and looking after and building up the body of Christ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, stick to your knitting and love one another! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Curse the accuser?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/curse-the-accuser/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/curse-the-accuser/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/curse-the-accuser/miguel-alcantara-19IDRDmMLgU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Curse the accuser?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What outcome do you desire for your accusers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To suffer a character assassination from the shadows is utterly reprehensible. Who are these who whisper lies against you? Of course you do not know because the accusations have not been brought into the light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And this is the judgment: the light has come into the world, and people loved the darkness rather than the light because their works were evil. For everyone who does wicked things hates the light and does not come to the light, lest his works should be exposed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These accusations are indeed thoroughly wicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wicked and deceitful mouths are opened against me, speaking against me with lying tongues. They encircle me with words of hate, and attack me without cause. In return for my love they accuse me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:2b-4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ironic that in your attempt to bring a message of love you are repelled by wicked and deceitful mouths and lying tongues and words of hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, I do know the harm that they have done to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am poor and needy, and my heart is stricken within me. I am gone like a shadow at evening; I am shaken off like a locust. My knees are weak through fasting; my body has become gaunt, with no fat. I am an object of scorn to my accusers; when they see me, they wag their heads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your accusers have crushed you. So again I have to ask, what outcome do you desire for them? What outcome do you pray for? For I know that you pray, oh how you pray! And I know that you continue to praise, even in the despising and the rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be not silent, O God of my praise! For wicked and deceitful mouths are opened against me, speaking against me with lying tongues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In return for my love they accuse me, but I give myself to prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:1-2, 4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a psalm of David, that man after God&amp;rsquo;s own heart. And here is something to notice right away. The Hebrew for “but I give myself to prayer” is literally “but I am prayer”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am prayer. O my soul, make it so. Clothe yourself in your prayer and wrap it tightly around you. Become that prayer. I am prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Help me, O LORD my God! Save me according to your steadfast love!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what? Know that David was beset by wicked and deceitful mouths speaking against him with lying tongues. So what was his response? What was his heart-cry? What what his prayer for his accuser? Listen and be appalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May his days be few; may another take his office! May his children be fatherless and his wife a widow!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His prayer was for divine judgment of death upon his accuser. And not only that but financial disaster upon the remnant of his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May his children wander about and beg, seeking food far from the ruins they inhabit! May the creditor seize all that he has; may strangers plunder the fruits of his toil!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And not only that but also for them childlessness and destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May his posterity be cut off; may his name be blotted out in the second generation!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This diatribe of a prayer continues for fifteen verses. Fifteen verses! What an outpouring of anger and bewilderment and pain and grief and dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several such imprecatory psalms in the Bible and some harsher even than this. What are we to make of them? And what are we to take from this? Is this to be a model for our own praying in such times?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you must understand how to take these prayers of David, how to use them, how to learn from them. For his curses upon his accusers are simply repugnant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are they here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He loved to curse; let curses come upon him! He did not delight in blessing; may it be far from him! He clothed himself with cursing as his coat; may it soak into his body like water, like oil into his bones! May it be like a garment that he wraps around him, like a belt that he puts on every day! May this be the reward of my accusers from the LORD, of those who speak evil against my life!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:17-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David is hurting. The whispered accusations have crushed him. He has been destroyed by wicked and deceitful mouths speaking against him with lying tongues, and it really hurts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, it hurts, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? And it is so unjust. It is absolutely and thoroughly wicked, and it contradicts all that Jesus taught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David&amp;rsquo;s fifteen verses of diatribe show us how much he is hurting as he lashes out in prayer. With some relief we can finally observe him get it all out and move on to something more reasonable, to a curse more proportionate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May my accusers be clothed with dishonour; may they be wrapped in their own shame as in a cloak!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 109:29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that he got all that out of his system is this where we should stand together with David? Again no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“You have heard that it was said, ‘You shall love your neighbour and hate your enemy.’ But I say to you, Love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you, so that you may be sons of your Father who is in heaven. For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:43-45&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, having been the victim of deceitful mouths and lying tongues, of accusations whispered from the shadows from those who do not come into the light, your response must be love and prayer, and to be exceedingly clear, prayer for repentance and rescue and transformation and not for harm. For what is the best possible outcome?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So that you may be sons of your Father who is in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:45a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one day you can stand alongside your accusers as sons of your Father, then you will be brothers with them⸺brothers and sisters in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, you cannot love your faceless accusers without knowing who they are. But you can forgive them. You can choose not to resent them. You can pray for them. And you can desire reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, observe the harm and the hurt done to David by his accusers, know that you are not alone in your own hurt, and now put that aside and respond with gentleness and forgiveness! 😭🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
