<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>failure on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/failure/</link>
        <description>Recent content in failure on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/failure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Everything beautiful in its time</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/everything-beautiful-in-its-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/everything-beautiful-in-its-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/everything-beautiful-in-its-time/dietmar-becker-8Zt0xOOK4nI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Everything beautiful in its time" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did Solomon in fact discover anything of value on his tragic quest, on his journey of self-destruction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He most certainly did. He was after all the wisest man who ever lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have seen the business that God has given to the children of man to be busy with. He has made everything beautiful in its time. Also, he has put eternity into man&amp;rsquo;s heart, yet so that he cannot find out what God has done from the beginning to the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 3:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider this carefully, for there is enormous blessing in Solomon&amp;rsquo;s insight here, such that we should be grateful to him for the sacrifice he made of himself to uncover it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has made everything beautiful in its time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 3:11a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s focus in then on just one of these beautiful things. O my soul, let&amp;rsquo;s focus on your own failure and shame and loss and searing pain, and your despising and rejection. Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on these, for he has made everything beautiful in its time, even this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how could this possibly be true? How could something so wrong, so shameful, and so humiliating, be made beautiful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we may have to receive this in the prophetic past tense. He has made everything beautiful in its time. It is a certainty, but it may not yet have been fulfilled. The Lord&amp;rsquo;s timing is such a mystery but his faithfulness is not. His name is Faithful and True.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s dig in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is near to the brokenhearted and saves the crushed in spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can heartbreak and loss be made beautiful? Because they are a gateway. The Lord is near to the brokenhearted.  This is both consolation and exceeding joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must know, however, that you have a choice here. In your pain and loss and suffering and heartbreak, you can harden your heart and set your face and resent your situation and turn away from the Lord, or you can soften your heart and run to the Lord and cast yourself upon him and pour out your sorrow there, and surrender to his goodness and sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which will you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For in heartbreak and loss you have a unique advantage. The things of this world have lost their grip on you. If all you have is the Lord, it is so much more straightforward to put him at the centre of your life, to love him and live for him alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delight yourself in the LORD, and he will give you the desires of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 37:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This of course is nothing less than an astonishing and lavish promise from the Lord that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/how-to-get-what-you-want/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;he will give himself to the one who delights in him alone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The things of this world are such a distraction, such a barrier to wholehearted love and devotion to the Lord. We saw that with Solomon. The Apostle Paul expands upon this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But whatever gain I had, I counted as loss for the sake of Christ. Indeed, I count everything as loss because of the surpassing worth of knowing Christ Jesus my Lord. For his sake I have suffered the loss of all things and count them as rubbish, in order that I may gain Christ and be found in him, not having a righteousness of my own that comes from the law, but that which comes through faith in Christ, the righteousness from God that depends on faith⸺that I may know him and the power of his resurrection, and may share his sufferings, becoming like him in his death, that by any means possible I may attain the resurrection from the dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 3:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not shy away from sharing in Christ&amp;rsquo;s sufferings. Marvel at the intimacy with the Saviour which is to be found there. What a privilege and what a joy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And suffering also can be a gateway to holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Since therefore Christ suffered in the flesh, arm yourselves with the same way of thinking, for whoever has suffered in the flesh has ceased from sin, so as to live for the rest of the time in the flesh no longer for human passions but for the will of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-peter&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Peter 4:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not overlook your choice which will determine whether the suffering becomes a process of sanctification or of hardening. O my soul, soften your heart and surrender to the work of the Saviour upon you. It is more painful by far but the rewards are great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also do not overlook in the pain and the shame and the humiliation the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great power to use precisely these to excise all pride from your life and replace it with humble gratitude. Hallelujah! What a Saviour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beware. As you start upon this path and become more aware of the enormous blessing you are receiving and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s mighty work of transformation in your life, be most careful to avoid this mistaken belief: that it is the Lord who caused your failure and shame and pain, and for this reason. For might it not be natural to suppose that he would consider the sacrifice to be worth it? But this is not how he works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord works these painful and shameful things together for good, but he did not cause them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is mystery here, and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s ways are difficult to fathom indeed, but in the heartbreak and in the pain have you noticed that your longing for the Lord is beginning to be satisfied?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have seen the business that God has given to the children of man to be busy with. He has made everything beautiful in its time. Also, he has put eternity into man&amp;rsquo;s heart, yet so that he cannot find out what God has done from the beginning to the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 3:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that the Lord is making beauty from the ashes of your life, and he is not done yet! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Walk before me and be blameless</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/anton-darius-zjGa2RQphRA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Walk before me and be blameless" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How on earth will you walk before the Lord and be blameless?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless, that I may make my covenant between me and you, and may multiply you greatly.” Then Abram fell on his face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall why Abraham fell on his face. Despite holding that impossible promise from the Lord for all those years, his life had been defined by cowardice and lies and failure and shame. He was at this time living with the consequence of having tried to fulfil that promise in his own strength, by fathering a child with the slave-girl Hagar. And I&amp;rsquo;m quite sure he enjoyed that at the time, having sex with the youthful Egyptian slave-girl rather than his ancient wife. But not now. Not when confronted with his sin and his shame and his failure by the Holy God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thirteen long years of living with the mess of that shameful failure all together in close proximity in that dysfunctional household,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham was overwhelmed by his own sin and shame and wretchedness, and when confronted by the holiness of God and his command, “Walk before me, and be blameless,” he fell on his face. There is nothing else he could have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whatever your situation, whatever shameful failure lies in your own past, and whatever the stumbling in more recent times, this is also addressed to you. It is exactly that to which each one of us is called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been chosen for you, but how on earth will you walk before this Holy God yourself and be holy and blameless? You must do this if you would enjoy his strong support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the eyes of the LORD run to and fro throughout the whole earth, to give strong support to those whose heart is blameless toward him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:9a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t this all too much to ask of an unholy people? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Creator God of the Universe chose each one of us in Christ, even before the foundation of the world, to be holy and blameless before him. He chose you for this and he chose me. You and I both must surrender to the choice of the one who is wise and strong and who knows how to achieve his plans and purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Job&amp;rsquo;s profession of faith after he had been confronted by the overwhelming greatness and majesty of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Job answered the LORD and said: “I know that you can do all things, and that no purpose of yours can be thwarted.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same overwhelmingly great and majestic God has a purpose for you and for me both, that we should be holy and blameless before him. So cry out to him along with the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfils his purpose for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not think you can resist the irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many are the plans in the mind of a man, but it is the purpose of the LORD that will stand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 19:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must surrender your life to the Holy Spirit as he does his sanctifying work in you. Resistance is futile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can unholy creatures be made holy? The answer is found only in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you, who once were alienated and hostile in mind, doing evil deeds, he has now reconciled in his body of flesh by his death, in order to present you holy and blameless and above reproach before him, if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has reconciled each one to himself in Christ&amp;rsquo;s body and by his death in order to present each one holy and blameless and above reproach before him. So do not shift from the hope of the gospel that you have heard, but which may not just now be in the forefront of your mind. Make it so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can we become holy, even according to his purposes? His strong and sure work of grace in our lives? If you desire this end, you must set your heart upon it. But isn&amp;rsquo;t it all just too hard? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I am up against. So how then can I co-operate with the Spirit of Christ in being transformed and made holy? Simply by noticing this: the strong connection between blamelessness and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now may our God and Father himself, and our Lord Jesus, direct our way to you, and may the Lord make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all, as we do for you, so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father, at the coming of our Lord Jesus with all his saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 3:11-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the Lord himself make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all precisely so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father. Oh my!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love that abounds more and more is the way to become pure and blameless for the day of Christ, and also quite remarkably how to fulfil the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Love does no wrong to a neighbour; therefore love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the power of love that will transform each one, and this fruit of righteousness comes only through Jesus. So set your course with determination to love the Lord with all your heart, soul, mind, and strength, and to love your neighbour as yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even as you wait on the Lord, even as you cry out to him through these long years of waiting, walk before him and be blameless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will sing of steadfast love and justice; to you, O LORD, I will make music. I will ponder the way that is blameless. Oh when will you come to me? I will walk with integrity of heart within my house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 101:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the waiting and the longing here? Oh when will you come to me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But above all, know that you will only be able to do any of this because of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to keep you from stumbling and to present you blameless before the presence of his glory with great joy, to the only God, our Saviour, through Jesus Christ our Lord, be glory, majesty, dominion, and authority, before all time and now and forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/jude&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude 1:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even in the waiting time, even in the heartbreak and the desperate longing, ensure to increase and abound in love, and so walk before him and be blameless! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Plan B</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/plan-b/senjuti-kundu-JfolIjRnveY-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Plan B" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life as God had intended?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was hated by his brothers to the extent that they wanted to murder him. Narrowly escaping death at their hands he was sold into slavery at the age of seventeen and then thrown into prison in Egypt for a crime he didn&amp;rsquo;t commit, where he was incarcerated for more than ten years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this what God had intended for him? Why had this all happened? Is this what the Lord&amp;rsquo;s perfect plans and purposes look like for those he loves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means! We simply must account for human folly and foolishness. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s own life and his whole family were dominated by these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Israel loved Joseph more than any other of his sons, because he was the son of his old age. And he made him a robe of many colours. But when his brothers saw that their father loved him more than all his brothers, they hated him and could not speak peacefully to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacob, now called Israel, fathered Joseph in his old age and doted upon him, unwisely favouring him above his brothers whose subsequent envy grew to become hatred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Joseph demonstrated that he was his father&amp;rsquo;s son through his own lack of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Joseph, being seventeen years old, was pasturing the flock with his brothers. He was a boy with the sons of Bilhah and Zilpah, his father&amp;rsquo;s wives. And Joseph brought a bad report of them to their father.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At seventeen shouldn&amp;rsquo;t he have known better how to get on with his brothers than telling tales about them to their own father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now Joseph had a dream, and when he told it to his brothers they hated him even more. He said to them, “Hear this dream that I have dreamed: Behold, we were binding sheaves in the field, and behold, my sheaf arose and stood upright. And behold, your sheaves gathered around it and bowed down to my sheaf.” His brothers said to him, “Are you indeed to reign over us? Or are you indeed to rule over us?” So they hated him even more for his dreams and for his words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph&amp;rsquo;s dream was from the Lord and revealed a glorious future. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that. But this revelation caused his brothers to hate him even more. They hated him even more because he was unwise enough to tell them of that prophecy which did indeed come to pass, eventually. Nevertheless, sharing it with his brothers as he did was both foolish and inflammatory. He was his father&amp;rsquo;s son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was a mistake he repeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he dreamed another dream and told it to his brothers and said, “Behold, I have dreamed another dream. Behold, the sun, the moon, and eleven stars were bowing down to me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 37:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps such things are better kept to one&amp;rsquo;s self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later when he arrived in Egypt as a slave he was equally naive. Let&amp;rsquo;s first notice how this foreign slave without credentials or experience became the trusted overseer of the household of Potiphar, the captain of the guard of the Pharaoh of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD was with Joseph, and he became a successful man, and he was in the house of his Egyptian master. His master saw that the LORD was with him and that the LORD caused all that he did to succeed in his hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t this blessing from the Lord all entirely undeserved? Grace and favour were raining down from heaven on this naive young man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then he was accused by Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife of attempted rape. But notice again the pattern here. Just as Joseph had been unwise to share that dream with his brothers, so also he was unwise to be in the house alone with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now Joseph was handsome in form and appearance. And after a time his master&amp;rsquo;s wife cast her eyes on Joseph and said, “Lie with me.” But he refused &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as she spoke to Joseph day after day, he would not listen to her, to lie beside her or to be with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:6-8, 10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it continued day after day. His woeful encounter with Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife was not an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As soon as his master heard the words that his wife spoke to him, “This is the way your servant treated me,” his anger was kindled. And Joseph&amp;rsquo;s master took him and put him into the prison, the place where the king&amp;rsquo;s prisoners were confined, and he was there in prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:19-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph again got what he deserved for his own foolishness, didn&amp;rsquo;t he? But what do we find, again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But the LORD was with Joseph and showed him steadfast love and gave him favour in the sight of the keeper of the prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The undeserved steadfast love of the Lord continued to rain down upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And whatever he did, the LORD made it succeed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 39:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually⸺and never was a word so appropriate as here in Joseph&amp;rsquo;s life⸺eventually, Joseph came before Pharaoh himself, in a way which was indeed by the hand of the Lord, interpreted his dream, and was freed to a great and glorious future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Pharaoh said to Joseph, “Since God has shown you all this, there is none so discerning and wise as you are. You shall be over my house, and all my people shall order themselves as you command. Only as regards the throne will I be greater than you.” And Pharaoh said to Joseph, “See, I have set you over all the land of Egypt.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 41:39-41&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ironic. Through those long years of incarceration God had transformed that foolish youth into a man so discerning and wise. What a miracle of grace. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, you know the rest. Famine in Canaan caused Jacob to send his sons to Egypt to buy food. After some scheming by Joseph which we could see as teaching his brothers a lesson (and who could blame him for that?) there was an emotional reconciliation. And then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thus Israel settled in the land of Egypt, in the land of Goshen. And they gained possessions in it, and were fruitful and multiplied greatly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 47:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this story all about then? The Lord&amp;rsquo;s incredible rescue of Joseph&amp;rsquo;s family from famine in their own land? Yes, certainly it is that. A family reconciliation after separation caused by hatred and betrayal? Yes, that too. Rescue and restoration of a naive young man from the consequences of his own foolishness? Indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ultimately isn&amp;rsquo;t this in fact all about the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for undeserving sinners? A Plan B so good and full of grace it seems to improve upon that hypothetical Plan A which never transpired. This Plan B which was wrought out of folly and foolishness and disappointment and shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much had gone wrong, but none of this pain and heartbreak and suffering was intended by the Lord nor attributable to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with us. He is the great rescuer, fully able to pick up the pieces of ruined lives and work all things together for good. His plans and purposes are not thwarted by our mistakes nor by our foolishness. Praise the Lord! And throughout Joseph&amp;rsquo;s story never once did God&amp;rsquo;s grace and steadfast love and faithfulness reach its limit. His grace is sufficient. Yes, the rescue took its time, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t it so well worth the wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s glorious Plan B for your own ruined life! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
