<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>compassion on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/compassion/</link>
        <description>Recent content in compassion on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/compassion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>New mercy</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/karl-magnuson-HQR_JXd-fPs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post New mercy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is far more significant than the new year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is new mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;As I remarked previously&lt;/a&gt; the context of these verses is the destruction of Jerusalem after Nebuchadnezzar&amp;rsquo;s siege of a year-and-a-half, and the exile of Judah to Babylon⸺the grimmest of times indeed, and moreover, the judgment of the Lord on his own people for their ongoing waywardness and apostasy. Enough was enough. But we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have unceasing steadfast love and mercy, &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt;, which so often go together and are surely &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/love-mercy/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Lord&amp;rsquo;s most defining attributes&lt;/a&gt; as he revealed on Mount Sinai in response to Moses&amp;rsquo; request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.” And Moses quickly bowed his head toward the earth and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:18, 34:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of such power and love and mercy, Moses&amp;rsquo; response was the only one possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s description of himself was &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;nâsâh&lt;/em&gt;, the last of which means forgiving, or so beautifully, lifting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, take a breath right now and worship the Lord of Hosts, whose name is love and mercy and forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must not move past this revelation of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s character without noticing where it came in the sequence of events. Moses had previously been with the Lord on Mount Sinai for forty days and forty nights, during which time he received instruction on how the Israelites were to live to honour the Lord, which was written on those two tablets of stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he gave to Moses, when he had finished speaking with him on Mount Sinai, the two tablets of the testimony, tablets of stone, written with the finger of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 31:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what did Moses find when he descended from the mountain of God? The Israelites had made for themselves a golden calf which they worshipped. In dismay Moses threw the tablets to the ground and broke them, and directed the faithful remnant, the Levites, to strap on swords and execute their brothers and neighbours throughout the camp, about three thousand. More subsequently died of the plague sent by the Lord in judgment on his people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this relevant? Because of what happened next. Moses was instructed to make new tablets, and the Lord revealed himself again as the God of love and mercy and forgiveness and also vengeance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said, “Behold, I am making a covenant. Before all your people I will do marvels, such as have not been created in all the earth or in any nation. And all the people among whom you are shall see the work of the LORD, for it is an awesome thing that I will do with you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they were given instructions. Again. Including this. Again. O my soul, grieve that this was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You shall not make for yourself any gods of cast metal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But also, interestingly, this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You shall not offer the blood of my sacrifice with anything leavened, or let the sacrifice of the Feast of the Passover remain until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which echoes in this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the flesh of the sacrifice of his peace offerings for thanksgiving shall be eaten on the day of his offering. He shall not leave any of it until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/leviticus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 7:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sacrifice was not to be left until the morning. But why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is precisely where we came in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s mercy is new every morning. It is simply not appropriate that the sacrifice remain until the next morning because new mercy has flooded in and it is overwhelmingly sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is new about this mercy? It is precisely because of the context of these verses⸺the propensity of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people to continue in their waywardness and apostasy, as it ever has been and still remains to this day. His mercy is new every morning and so very needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not be deceived. There are two mistakes you must avoid. The first is to think that somehow your own heart is different from those Israelites, that you are somehow better. You are not. That propensity for waywardness and unbelief and sin remains, and so you must be vigilant and disciplined and repentant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second mistake is to doubt the sufficiency of that new mercy. But his mercy is more, and his mercy is new every morning! And his forgiveness is a lifting up anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So rejoice in the very next verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The LORD is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is indeed my portion and my inheritance. He is all I need and therefore I will hope in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just as with Moses, there is only one possible response to this revelation of the character of God, and it is worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bless the LORD, O my soul, and all that is within me, bless his holy name! Bless the LORD, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits, who forgives all your iniquity, who heals all your diseases, who redeems your life from the pit, who crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, who satisfies you with good so that your youth is renewed like the eagle&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 103:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt;. He crowns you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, worship the one who crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, and put all your hope in him for this brave new year! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Do not be angry</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/do-not-be-angry/cas-holmes-_zyt1WWWdv4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Do not be angry" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that righteous anger we examined last week the right response to all the sin in the world, that sin which corrupts and stains everything, that sin which we see all around us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus came to the temple on another occasion, and this visit was so very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Early in the morning he came again to the temple. All the people came to him, and he sat down and taught them. The scribes and the Pharisees brought a woman who had been caught in adultery, and placing her in the midst they said to him, “Teacher, this woman has been caught in the act of adultery. Now in the Law, Moses commanded us to stone such women. So what do you say?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:2-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this woman epitomise all that&amp;rsquo;s wrong with society? Everyone choosing to do what they want with no regard for God&amp;rsquo;s holy law, and no regard for the cost in human suffering and shame? Surely that righteous anger is the fitting response to such a thing, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pharisees were clearly angry, but let&amp;rsquo;s pause for a moment and look into the reason for their anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This they said to test him, that they might have some charge to bring against him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:6a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth they didn&amp;rsquo;t really care about honouring the Lord, and they certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t care about the woman herself⸺she evidently meant nothing to them. They were out to test Jesus, to bring a charge against him, to bring him down. Perhaps they saw him as soft on sin, or at least soft on sinners. Their aim was to trap him into contradicting the law so that they could discredit him. Is this not precisely the behaviour of vain and dishonest men of rank? Theirs was so clearly not a righteous anger then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of Jesus&amp;rsquo; righteous anger that we saw previously?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus bent down and wrote with his finger on the ground. And as they continued to ask him, he stood up and said to them, “Let him who is without sin among you be the first to throw a stone at her.” And once more he bent down and wrote on the ground. But when they heard it, they went away one by one, beginning with the older ones, and Jesus was left alone with the woman standing before him. Jesus stood up and said to her, “Woman, where are they? Has no one condemned you?” She said, “No one, Lord.” And Jesus said, “Neither do I condemn you; go, and from now on sin no more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:6b-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon being confronted with their own sinfulness, and beginning with the older ones, they went away one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning with the older ones. Perhaps only eventually do each of us understand how far we fall short. Is there not sometimes a harshness to be seen among the younger generation in their zealous pursuit of what is right and true? Perhaps only with the passage of time and the humble recognition of ongoing failure and shame in our own lives is each of us able to say with Paul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 1:15b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s put aside then that righteous anger that Jesus would have been feeling towards those vain and dishonest men of rank, and ask, what was he feeling towards the adulterous woman?⸺for the answer to that addresses our opening question on how we should respond to all that sin and brokenness we see in the world, that sin which corrupts all. Notice what he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jesus stood up and said to her, “Woman, where are they? Has no one condemned you?” She said, “No one, Lord.” And Jesus said, “Neither do I condemn you; go, and from now on sin no more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus did not condemn and he does not condemn, but it matters that each one sin no more. O my soul, from now on sin no more. Your Saviour demands it! And listen to Jesus explain why he came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so the answer is compassion, not anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Father&amp;rsquo;s compassion for our broken and dysfunctional world and our own brokenness was the reason for sending his only Son to rescue and redeem, to die at Calvary where that great love was poured out for all, and to rise again in resurrection victory and power over sin and death and all that corrupts and spoils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do need to pause however and ask whether the Pharisees had a point. In all his compassion, is Jesus in fact soft on sin? And if his sacrifice at Calvary was sufficient to pay the debt of eight billion sinners, why would we any longer be concerned about the sin that remains. Cannot all be forgiven?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not so quickly forget Jesus&amp;rsquo; final words to the adulterous woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go, and from now on sin no more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 8:11b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else did Jesus have to say about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whoever causes one of these little ones who believe in me to sin, it would be better for him if a great millstone were hung around his neck and he were thrown into the sea. And if your hand causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life crippled than with two hands to go to hell to the unquenchable fire. And if your foot causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life lame than with two feet to be thrown into hell. And if your eye causes you to sin, tear it out. It is better for you to enter the kingdom of God with one eye than with two eyes to be thrown into hell, ‘where their worm does not die and the fire is not quenched.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 9:42-48&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are these the words of one who is soft on sin? O my soul, you must purge the sin from your own life, and you must be ruthless in this. Do not tolerate it any longer. Do not be deceived⸺look ahead to what will happen at the end of this present age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I saw a great white throne and him who was seated on it. From his presence earth and sky fled away, and no place was found for them. And I saw the dead, great and small, standing before the throne, and books were opened. Then another book was opened, which is the book of life. And the dead were judged by what was written in the books, according to what they had done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 20:11-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tremble at these things, and be grateful for the book of life, written at such great cost by the author of life. Such is compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So thank and praise the Lord for his compassion which rescues and redeems. Put aside your righteous anger before it becomes self-righteousness, soften your heart, and reach out with compassion and kindness and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great rescue for this broken world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, learn to live with humility as one who was once lost and is now saved, put aside that anger, and put on a grateful and compassionate heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
