<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>pride on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/pride/</link>
        <description>Recent content in pride on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/pride/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The sacrifice of forgiveness</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-forgiveness/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-forgiveness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/the-sacrifice-of-forgiveness/iurii-melentsov-7iKuB62CQBU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The sacrifice of forgiveness" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it simply too hard to forgive your accusers for their whispered lies against you? For the way they have crushed you from the shadows? For the way they have acted in blatant disregard for Jesus&amp;rsquo; teaching?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is that teaching?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“If your brother sins against you, go and tell him his fault, between you and him alone. If he listens to you, you have gained your brother.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 18:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course they did not do that. Whatever offence they allege you have committed against them, rather than seek reconciliation as Jesus commanded, instead they have held on to their own hurt, nurturing it and tending to it until it established itself as bitterness and resentment, until it became a grudge, fueling their whispering against you in the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what now? How will you respond? Interestingly Jesus moves straight on to the parable of the unmerciful servant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Peter came up and said to him, “Lord, how often will my brother sin against me, and I forgive him? As many as seven times?” Jesus said to him, “I do not say to you seven times, but seventy-seven times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Therefore the kingdom of heaven may be compared to a king who wished to settle accounts with his servants.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 18:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parable is familiar, and links our own forgiveness of others with our Heavenly Father&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness of us. It is the same in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if you forgive others their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you, but if you do not forgive others their trespasses, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 6:12, 14-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link between our own forgiveness of others and the Lord&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness of our own trespasses is stark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t this forgiveness too hard? Too painful? Are you expected simply to absorb that pain and the hurt they have caused you, as if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course it matters! It matters terribly! It is grievous. So what to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must recognise that you are being tempted. You are being tempted by the Father of Lies, to hold on to your own hurt, nurturing it and tending to it just as your accusers must have done with theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again I find the juxtaposition of passages in the Bible to be so revealing. For not only do we have here in Matthew Chapter 18 the teaching on reconciliation followed immediately by the parable of the unmerciful servant, but what do we find Jesus teaching just before this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Woe to the world for temptations to sin! For it is necessary that temptations come, but woe to the one by whom the temptation comes!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 18:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temptation here means stumbling block. It is necessary that stumbling blocks come. Necessary? How can this be necessary? Let&amp;rsquo;s apply this to your own temptation to withhold forgiveness for your accusers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Peter came up and said to him, “Lord, how often will my brother sin against me, and I forgive him? As many as seven times?” Jesus said to him, “I do not say to you seven times, but seventy-seven times.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 18:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke records Jesus as saying the same thing, but here the emphasis on the ongoing need to forgive is even stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Pay attention to yourselves! If your brother sins, rebuke him, and if he repents, forgive him, and if he sins against you seven times in the day, and turns to you seven times, saying, ‘I repent,’ you must forgive him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 17:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven times in a day! And the next day likely the same. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this test the limits of forgiveness? But isn&amp;rsquo;t that exactly the point? Those limits must be exposed and then removed. There can be no limit here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Put on then, as God&amp;rsquo;s chosen ones, holy and beloved, compassionate hearts, kindness, humility, meekness, and patience, bearing with one another and, if one has a complaint against another, forgiving each other; as the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When did you last need forgiveness from the Lord? Was it not today? And has today&amp;rsquo;s count reached seven, or are you in truth far beyond that? And the day before? And tomorrow? O my soul, you do know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Indeed, under the law almost everything is purified with blood, and without the shedding of blood there is no forgiveness of sins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 9:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And when they came to the place that is called The Skull, there they crucified him, and the criminals, one on his right and one on his left. And Jesus said, “Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do.”⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 23:33-34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a cost to forgiveness and it is enormous. Jesus paid the price, and even as he was paying that price, “Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so too there is a cost for you to forgive and it is more than pain. Something has to die. What is that something? It is that spirit which demands to justify your own position. It is that spirit which desires to fight back. It is that spirit which would take all of your own pain and hurt and return it in kind. It is pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repudiate that spirit of pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive. “Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put to death the pride that stands in the way of forgiveness. It is painful for sure. But know that the biggest pain sensor in the human body is called the ego. Put it to death. Make it your sacrifice of forgiveness to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notice what Paul commanded must be put on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Put on then &amp;hellip; humility, &amp;hellip; , forgiving each other; as the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:12-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are these stumbling blocks so necessary? These temptations to withhold forgiveness? Because how can we do a thing without first learning how to do it? And how can we learn without doing it again, and again. And over again. Seven times in a day. More than seven. Seventy seven times. Seventy times seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not overlook that seven symbolises perfection. Your forgiveness must be perfect. So keep practising! It is necessary that you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two last points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul writes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Anyone whom you forgive, I also forgive. Indeed, what I have forgiven, if I have forgiven anything, has been for your sake in the presence of Christ, so that we would not be outwitted by Satan; for we are not ignorant of his designs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 2:10-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satan is constantly at work drip-feeding his poison into the ears of believers. Forgiveness is such a powerful weapon to neutralise this. May we not be ignorant of his designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally and most importantly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the evening of that day, the first day of the week, the doors being locked where the disciples were for fear of the Jews, Jesus came and stood among them and said to them, “Peace be with you.” When he had said this, he showed them his hands and his side. Then the disciples were glad when they saw the Lord. Jesus said to them again, “Peace be with you. As the Father has sent me, even so I am sending you.” And when he had said this, he breathed on them and said to them, “Receive the Holy Spirit. If you forgive the sins of any, they are forgiven them; if you withhold forgiveness from any, it is withheld.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 20:19-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tremble at the responsibility you have been given. If you forgive the sins of any, they are forgiven them; if you withhold forgiveness from any, it is withheld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, forgiveness is Kingdom work. Will you do it? 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Humility before honour</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/humility-before-honour/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/humility-before-honour/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/humility-before-honour/sergio-garcia-peILg94wWd8-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Humility before honour" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my Soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you still not enjoying being brushed aside and disregarded? Consider this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before destruction a man&amp;rsquo;s heart is haughty, but humility comes before honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 18:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the original Hebrew the second simply says, humility before honour. How interesting. Humility before honour. We&amp;rsquo;ll come to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But firstly, before destruction a man&amp;rsquo;s heart is haughty. Haughty is somewhat of an old-fashioned word. What would be a more modern rendition? Conceited. Arrogant. Superior. Full of oneself. Prideful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This then is about the greatest sin of them all: pride. And so the first part of this proverbial couplet is simply pride comes before a fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD preserves the faithful but abundantly repays the one who acts in pride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 31:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly did you suppose this repayment to comprise? Did you think it would be less than destruction? Did you think the fall would be anything other than divine judgment? Had you perhaps underestimated the severity of the sin of pride?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Scoffer” is the name of the arrogant, haughty man who acts with arrogant pride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 21:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not suppose that it is a small thing to carry the name of scoffer, nor something easily excused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whoever plans to do evil will be called a schemer. The devising of folly is sin, and the scoffer is an abomination to mankind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 24:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An abomination to mankind no less!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the LORD of hosts has a day against all that is proud and lofty, against all that is lifted up⸺and it shall be brought low;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the haughtiness of man shall be humbled, and the lofty pride of men shall be brought low, and the LORD alone will be exalted in that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 2:12, 17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pride challenges the Lord himself. Do you wonder then that he will not tolerate it? For it displaces the Lord from his throne. It deceives and it defiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [Jesus] said, “What comes out of a person is what defiles him. For from within, out of the heart of man, come evil thoughts, sexual immorality, theft, murder, adultery, coveting, wickedness, deceit, sensuality, envy, slander, pride, foolishness. All these evil things come from within, and they defile a person.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 7:20-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a shocking list, and pride is right there in the thick of it. But what else did Jesus say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are the meek, for they shall inherit the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s return to our proverb in the context of inheriting the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Humility before honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 18:12b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word for honour is &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt;, although this is a word mostly not translated honour. Mostly not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fear of the LORD is instruction in wisdom, and humility comes before honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 15:33&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The reward for humility and fear of the LORD is riches and honour and life.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 22:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One&amp;rsquo;s pride will bring him low, but he who is lowly in spirit will obtain honour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 29:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job uses the same word in speaking of what he has received from the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He has stripped from me my &lt;em&gt;glory&lt;/em&gt; and taken the crown from my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 19:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As does the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But you, O LORD, are a shield about me, my &lt;em&gt;glory&lt;/em&gt;, and the lifter of my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 3:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at this word &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt;. For far more than honour is it translated glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the LORD said to Moses, “This very thing that you have spoken I will do, for you have found favour in my sight, and I know you by name.” Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.” And Moses quickly bowed his head toward the earth and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:17-18, 34:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at the glory of the Lord and marvel further that this same word &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt; is used for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lift up your heads, O gates! And be lifted up, O ancient doors, that the King of glory may come in. Who is this King of glory? The LORD, strong and mighty, the LORD, mighty in battle! Lift up your heads, O gates! And lift them up, O ancient doors, that the King of glory may come in. Who is this King of glory? The LORD of hosts, he is the King of glory!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 24:7-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the year that King Uzziah died I saw the Lord sitting upon a throne, high and lifted up; and the train of his robe filled the temple. Above him stood the seraphim. Each had six wings: with two he covered his face, and with two he covered his feet, and with two he flew. And one called to another and said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Holy, holy, holy is the LORD of hosts; the whole earth is full of his glory!”⁠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 6:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord will not tolerate the pride that challenges his own exaltation, his own glory, and yet he bestows honour and glory upon the meek and humble⸺glory carried in the same word as his very own!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bestowing of honour is seen so clearly in the echo of the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD is high above all nations, and his glory above the heavens! Who is like the LORD our God, who is seated on high, who looks far down on the heavens and the earth? He raises the poor from the dust and lifts the needy from the ash heap, to make them sit with princes, with the princes of his people. He gives the barren woman a home, making her the joyous mother of children. Praise the LORD!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 113:4-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;em&gt;kâbôd&lt;/em&gt; which is the glory of the Lord. And the echo is in Hannah&amp;rsquo;s prayer⸺Hannah, that barren woman whose womb was opened by the Lord, making her the joyous mother of Samuel, the Lord&amp;rsquo;s prophet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Hannah prayed and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The LORD makes poor and makes rich; he brings low and he exalts. He raises up the poor from the dust; he lifts the needy from the ash heap to make them sit with princes and inherit a seat of honour. For the pillars of the earth are the LORD&amp;rsquo;s, and on them he has set the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-samuel&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Samuel 2:1a, 7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake. The pillars of the earth are indeed the Lord&amp;rsquo;s. He alone is Creator God, and evermore to be praised. And he alone lifts the needy from the ash heap to make them sit with princes and inherit a seat of honour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be content to live in humility and the fear of the Lord, praising the one who alone is worthy, and know that he alone rewards with honour and glory! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Be angry</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/be-angry/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/be-angry/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/be-angry/todd-trapani-91T-rq-pY28-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Be angry" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you make of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry. Why? It is commanded! And in that, do not sin. How? How can this be done? We&amp;rsquo;ll need to give some serious thought to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by considering the new life that is in Christ. Paul sets the context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God. Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth. For you have died, and your life is hidden with Christ in God.  When Christ who is your life appears, then you also will appear with him in glory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:1-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not progress past this too quickly⸺it is heady truth indeed! I have died and my life is hidden with Christ in God. My eternal being is secure and unassailable. Indeed my very life is Christ. Praise the Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then? Paul continues in typical fashion with a therefore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Put to death therefore what is earthly in you: sexual immorality, impurity, passion, evil desire, and covetousness, which is idolatry. On account of these the wrath of God is coming. In these you too once walked, when you were living in them. But now you must put them all away: anger, wrath, malice, slander, and obscene talk from your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 3:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these have any place in the new life, and of these things that must be put away, did you notice that anger appeared first in the list? But still,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may conclude that there are two different kinds of anger. And indeed the words are different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the anger which must be put aside, having no place in the new life in Christ, Paul uses the Greek word &lt;em&gt;orgē&lt;/em&gt;, which is an anger full of emotion, violent passion in fact. This is the anger of not getting one&amp;rsquo;s own way. It is the anger of a bruised ego. And the word used for wrath means rage or passion. It is selfish, even childish in its inability to show restraint. Those must be put aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist wrote in Hebrew, which precludes direct comparison, but Paul also writes of the anger of the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry and do not sin; do not let the sun go down on your anger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here he uses the Greek word &lt;em&gt;parorgismos&lt;/em&gt;, which means indignation or wrath or exasperation. This is not rage. This is a righteous anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the command is to be angry with that righteous anger, with indignation at what ought not to be. But what is that? What should be the object of such anger? To answer that let&amp;rsquo;s consider what was the object of Jesus&amp;rsquo; anger⸺for from time to time he was indeed angry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s one example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And they came to Jerusalem. And he entered the temple and began to drive out those who sold and those who bought in the temple, and he overturned the tables of the money-changers and the seats of those who sold pigeons. And he would not allow anyone to carry anything through the temple. And he was teaching them and saying to them, “Is it not written, ‘My house shall be called a house of prayer for all the nations?’ But you have made it a den of robbers.” And the chief priests and the scribes heard it and were seeking a way to destroy him, for they feared him, because all the crowd was astonished at his teaching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:15-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who were the subject of his anger were very much on the inside of the religious establishment of the day, but their behaviour was brazen in its dishonouring of the Lord. Worthy of anger, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you agree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way each gospel writer orders their account is interesting and surely rich in meaning. There&amp;rsquo;s just such a juxtaposition here which must be noticed, for this account of Jesus clearing the temple is immediately followed by this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As they passed by in the morning, they saw the fig tree withered away to its roots. And Peter remembered and said to him, “Rabbi, look! The fig tree that you cursed has withered.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 11:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you recall how I &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/hard-teaching/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;grappled previously&lt;/a&gt; with this hard teaching of the poor little fig tree being cursed for failing to bear figs out of season?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&amp;rsquo; anger with that fig tree paralleled his anger with the Pharisees⸺those heinously prideful ones who should have been fruitful for the Kingdom but were not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s return to our psalm and observe the context out of which it is written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Answer me when I call, O God of my righteousness! You have given me relief when I was in distress. Be gracious to me and hear my prayer!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the psalm as a whole we see a man earnestly desiring to live a right life before the Lord while being so very aware of his dependence upon the Lord for that. O my soul, do you know this humble passion for personal holiness combined with complete dependence on Christ for his righteousness? I know that you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist has been in distress previously, and is again, and why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;O men, how long shall my honour be turned into shame? How long will you love vain words and seek after lies?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is despised and rejected by vain and dishonest men. And who are they? Their description is nuanced, literally &lt;em&gt;sons of men&lt;/em&gt;. The ESV alternative translation renders it &lt;em&gt;men of rank&lt;/em&gt;. So, privileged ones. Exalted ones. Vain and dishonest. Pharisees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be angry, O my soul, you must be angry at that which ought not to be, that which so dishonours the Lord, that pride and hypocrisy. And do not sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how are we not to sin in this? There are two ways. The psalmist tells us the first right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry, and do not sin; ponder in your own hearts on your beds, and be silent. Offer right sacrifices, and put your trust in the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, in your own righteous anger know that you are not called to table-flipping and temple-clearing. That is Jesus&amp;rsquo; work. Ponder on your bed and be silent. Put your trust in the Lord. Do you think he hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen this heinous behaviour? Do you think he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know? Do you think he won&amp;rsquo;t respond?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Paul tells us the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be angry and do not sin; do not let the sun go down on your anger, and give no opportunity to the devil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:26-27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? Do not let the sun go down on your anger. Do not hold on to it. You must lay it down and let it go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Beloved, never avenge yourselves, but leave it to the wrath of God, for it is written, “Vengeance is mine, I will repay, says the Lord.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And where does that leave the psalmist? Blessed and at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You have put more joy in my heart than they have when their grain and wine abound. In peace I will both lie down and sleep; for you alone, O LORD, make me dwell in safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 4:7-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, be angry and do not sin! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Self-satisfied and delusional</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/nick-fewings-XpG9JaN_SXQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Self-satisfied and delusional" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a church completely and comprehensively lose its way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Laodicea write: ‘The words of the Amen, the faithful and true witness, the beginning of God&amp;rsquo;s creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works: you are neither cold nor hot. Would that you were either cold or hot! So, because you are lukewarm, and neither hot nor cold, I will spit you out of my mouth. For you say, I am rich, I have prospered, and I need nothing, not realizing that you are wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:14-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, grieve with Jesus over this self-satisfied and delusional church. And grieve further over their complete and unmitigated failure and shame. Recall that even in that dead church in Sardis there were some who had not soiled their garments, who being worthy would walk with Jesus in white. In Laodicea no such are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could there have been such a gulf between how Jesus saw the church and how they saw themselves? Laodicea was a wealthy city and we may deduce that its church also was affluent and middle-class, seeing itself as rich in every way, lacking nothing. But how self-satisfied they were!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They thought they were rich, but they had failed to understand the currency of eternity. In reality they were paupers. And if they saw themselves as discerning, in reality they were blind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laodicea was entirely deception and delusion, but Jesus knew, and he knew they were wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked. How had this happened? How does this happen to any church which seems to be richly blessed, which maybe even gives the appearance of delighting in the Lord? Perhaps they had simply made their lives all about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah prophecies against just such. Note well the nature of the offence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cry aloud; do not hold back; lift up your voice like a trumpet; declare to my people their transgression, to the house of Jacob their sins. Yet they seek me daily and delight to know my ways, as if they were a nation that did righteousness and did not forsake the judgment of their God; they ask of me righteous judgments; they delight to draw near to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how the house of Jacob delighted to draw near to God. Everything was simply magnificent, wasn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. No it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. O my soul, be appalled at their pride and listen to their self-justification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why have we fasted, and you see it not? Why have we humbled ourselves, and you take no knowledge of it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord thought otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, in the day of your fast you seek your own pleasure, and oppress all your workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how they were rebuked for their self-interest and lack of concern for others, and be dismayed with quite how much this contradicted what the Lord required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is not this the fast that I choose: to loose the bonds of wickedness, to undo the straps of the yoke, to let the oppressed go free, and to break every yoke? Is it not to share your bread with the hungry and bring the homeless poor into your house; when you see the naked, to cover him, and not to hide yourself from your own flesh?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus say later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A new commandment I give to you, that you love one another: just as I have loved you, you also are to love one another. By this all people will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? Loving one another is the barometer of discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And humility? In their pride and self-satisfaction, how many Laodiceans would have been able to identify with Paul in saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 1:15b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the answer would have been none. Certainly none are mentioned by Jesus in his letter. In all six of the other churches, Jesus found at least something to commend⸺even in Sardis. But here, nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, wake up to this reality! Jesus&amp;rsquo; warning is as urgent as it is vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but the one who does the will of my Father who is in heaven. On that day many will say to me, ‘Lord, Lord, did we not prophesy in your name, and cast out demons in your name, and do many mighty works in your name?’ And then will I declare to them, ‘I never knew you; depart from me, you workers of lawlessness.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now recall that those Philadelphians, with such little power, were commended by Jesus without reservation. Do we see in Laodicea a church condemned without reservation? No we don&amp;rsquo;t⸺at least not that terrible and final condemnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, marvel over the grace and generosity in Jesus&amp;rsquo; lavish invitation to this prideful and delusional church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I counsel you to buy from me gold refined by fire, so that you may be rich, and white garments so that you may clothe yourself and the shame of your nakedness may not be seen, and salve to anoint your eyes, so that you may see. Those whom I love, I reprove and discipline, so be zealous and repent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus had not given up on this smug and self-satisfied church, and neither must you. They were wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked, and yet look what Jesus was offering. Was it not exactly what they needed? What they really needed? And all they had to do to receive these things was to repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite unlike that open door in Philadelphia, the Laodiceans had firmly closed their own door. But listen again to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent invitation to prideful ones who have completely and comprehensively lost their way. Astonishingly, final condemnation is held back, and what is offered in its place is an invitation to repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who conquers, I will grant him to sit with me on my throne, as I also conquered and sat down with my Father on his throne. He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, listen to what Jesus is saying, repent of self-interest and self-satisfaction, humble yourself, and reach out with love for others! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fooled by our own reputation</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/fooled-by-our-own-reputation/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/fooled-by-our-own-reputation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/fooled-by-our-own-reputation/julio-rionaldo-CmuCyTRBDGg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fooled by our own reputation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is reputed to be alive but is in fact dead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One answer of course is the church in Sardis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Sardis write: ‘The words of him who has the seven spirits of God and the seven stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works. You have the reputation of being alive, but you are dead.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(But we would be fools to think this is the only answer.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can understand about Jesus&amp;rsquo; diagnosis of this dead church. Firstly and quite surprisingly, given the severity of the indictment, doesn&amp;rsquo;t his judgment seem to be rather non-specific?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wake up, and strengthen what remains and is about to die, for I have not found your works complete in the sight of my God. Remember, then, what you received and heard. Keep it, and repent. If you will not wake up, I will come like a thief, and you will not know at what hour I will come against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has been going on here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are works but they are not complete. What was received and heard has been forgotten. Repentance is required. And they are asleep. Jesus&amp;rsquo; verdict is that the net effect of these apparently innocuous elements is that the church is dead. Dead, no less!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can understand how that could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word used to describe those works which were not complete is the Greek verb &lt;em&gt;plēroō&lt;/em&gt;, which mostly gets translated fulfilled or fulfil. Their works were not fulfilled. So we should ask, what would be works that were fulfilled? Paul tells us, using the parallel Greek noun &lt;em&gt;plērōma&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there was a deficit of love in Sardis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s consider what could have been received and heard and subsequently forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More than that, we also rejoice in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we have now received reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For if, because of one man&amp;rsquo;s trespass, death reigned through that one man, much more will those who receive the abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness reign in life through the one man Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 5:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you did not receive the spirit of slavery to fall back into fear, but you have received the Spirit of adoption as sons, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What had been received was reconciliation, abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness, and the Spirit of adoption as sons and daughters, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, grieve with Jesus that this could have been forgotten. How could this be? What could possibly happen that such things be forgotten? Here&amp;rsquo;s what. What happens is that pride enters the human heart, and self-satisfaction displaces gratitude such that one&amp;rsquo;s own status as one who has been rescued is no longer foremost in the mind. It is pride and self-satisfaction that kill humble gratitude and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So if there is any encouragement in Christ, any comfort from love, any participation in the Spirit, any affection and sympathy, complete my joy by being of the same mind, having the same love, being in full accord and of one mind. Do nothing from selfish ambition or conceit, but in humility count others more significant than yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as in the church in Thyatira so too in Sardis there was a call to repent. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it complacency which deafens ears to such a call?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jesus urges them to wake up lest he come like a thief in the night, unexpected and frankly unwelcome. Does this not remind us of Jesus&amp;rsquo; warning to his own disciples, concerning his return in glory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But concerning that day or that hour, no one knows, not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father. Be on guard, keep awake. For you do not know when the time will come. It is like a man going on a journey, when he leaves home and puts his servants in charge, each with his work, and commands the doorkeeper to stay awake. Therefore stay awake⸺for you do not know when the master of the house will come, in the evening, or at midnight, or when the rooster crows, or in the morning⸺lest he come suddenly and find you asleep. And what I say to you I say to all: Stay awake.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 13:32-37&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, stay awake!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And tremble also because of Jesus&amp;rsquo; words to the church in Sardis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you will not wake up, I will come like a thief, and you will not know at what hour I will come against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against you! Against the ones who had received reconciliation, abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness, and the Spirit of adoption as sons and daughters. These ones who were now found by Jesus to be on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, was there ever such complacency? But wake up. It is in fact all around us. All. Around. Us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite this we must notice something vital. While it may have been endemic, this spirit of complacency had not vanquished all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet you have still a few names in Sardis, people who have not soiled their garments, and they will walk with me in white, for they are worthy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not despair. There was a faithful remnant, even here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is to be done? Two things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, be appalled at those who have soiled their garments. Those complacent ones. Those who have a reputation of being alive but are in fact dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, put aside your own complacency and smug self-satisfaction, choose the path of humility, and walk with Jesus in white. And you must be careful to understand what that means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After this I looked, and behold, a great multitude that no one could number, from every nation, from all tribes and peoples and languages, standing before the throne and before the Lamb, clothed in white robes, with palm branches in their hands, and crying out with a loud voice, “Salvation belongs to our God who sits on the throne, and to the Lamb!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one of the elders addressed me, saying, “Who are these, clothed in white robes, and from where have they come?” I said to him, “Sir, you know.” And he said to me, “These are the ones coming out of the great tribulation. They have washed their robes and made them white in the blood of the Lamb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 7:9-10, 13-14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no other way to walk with Jesus in white other than by being washed in the blood of the Lamb, other than by receiving reconciliation, abundance of grace and the free gift of righteousness, and the Spirit of adoption as sons and daughters. And holding on to these with humble gratitude! O my soul, hold on to these precious gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But God, being rich in mercy, because of the great love with which he loved us, even when we were dead in our trespasses, made us alive together with Christ⸺by grace you have been saved⸺and raised us up with him and seated us with him in the heavenly places in Christ Jesus, so that in the coming ages he might show the immeasurable riches of his grace in kindness toward us in Christ Jesus. For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:4-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So walk with a grateful heart in humility, as one rescued, as one whose life now belongs to another. For it is so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, wash your robes in the blood of the Lamb and walk worthy! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
