<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>exhaustion on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/exhaustion/</link>
        <description>Recent content in exhaustion on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/exhaustion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Why have you forsaken me?</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/why-have-you-forsaken-me/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/why-have-you-forsaken-me/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/why-have-you-forsaken-me/massimiliano-sarno-0Zg-9QGS0gg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Why have you forsaken me?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to give up? To throw in the towel? Are you utterly spent? Empty and exhausted? Does it seem to you that you have been abandoned by God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My God, my God, why have you forsaken me? Why are you so far from saving me, from the words of my groaning? O my God, I cry by day, but you do not answer, and by night, but I find no rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the psalmist, crying out in bewilderment to God, my God: Why have you forsaken me? Unable to sleep. Exhausted. Empty. Groaning in misery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:1a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is no answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is what lies ahead simply too hard? Is this the end? Is the enemy too strong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many bulls encompass me; strong bulls of Bashan surround me; they open wide their mouths at me, like a ravening and roaring lion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am poured out like water, and all my bones are out of joint; my heart is like wax; it is melted within my breast; my strength is dried up like a potsherd, and my tongue sticks to my jaws; you lay me in the dust of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:12-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am truly poured out. Has God himself laid me in the dust of death? I have nothing left. I am completely spent. There is no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, but there is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For there are two voices in the psalm. It is a conversation, a to and fro. We have heard from despair. But there is also hope. Listen now to hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet you are holy, enthroned on the praises of Israel. In you our fathers trusted; they trusted, and you delivered them. To you they cried and were rescued; in you they trusted and were not put to shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:3-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is hope, and here are reasons for hope. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider four reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly and most obviously, the Lord is trustworthy. Those who went before us cried out to God, they trusted him, and he delivered them. &lt;em&gt;He delivered them&lt;/em&gt;. They were not put to shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“For I the LORD do not change; therefore you, O children of Jacob, are not consumed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/malachi&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Malachi 3:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope in the Lord does not disappoint. It never has. So hope in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a second and slightly less obvious reason for hope, which is that the Lord is holy, enthroned on the praises of his people. Why is this a reason?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All around us we see reason to despair, to lose hope, to give up. People are duplicitous and there are ulterior motives. Shady and shadowy conversations abound. Self-interest is everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Surely there is not a righteous man on earth who does good and never sins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 7:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Lord is not like that. He is set apart from all that contaminates and all that corrupts. He is holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice that the Lord is holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third reason?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yet you are he who took me from the womb; you made me trust you at my mother&amp;rsquo;s breasts. On you was I cast from my birth, and from my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb you have been my God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, not only has the Lord been faithful to those who went before, he has been faithful to you, your whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which leads us to the fourth and by far the most important reason for hope. Because of course the psalm is prophetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For dogs encompass me; a company of evildoers encircles me; they have pierced my hands and feet⸺I can count all my bones⸺they stare and gloat over me; they divide my garments among them, and for my clothing they cast lots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rather doubt that David even knew why he was writing this. But we know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they brought [Jesus] to the place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they crucified him and divided his garments among them, casting lots for them, to decide what each should take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:22,24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, if you think you have been abandoned by God, you need to think again about who actually was abandoned on your behalf, and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And when the sixth hour had come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour. And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, “Eloi, Eloi, lema sabachthani?” which means, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jesus uttered a loud cry and breathed his last. And the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 15:33,34,37,38&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? The psalmist tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the ends of the earth shall remember and turn to the LORD, and all the families of the nations shall worship before you. For kingship belongs to the LORD, and he rules over the nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posterity shall serve him; it shall be told of the Lord to the coming generation; they shall come and proclaim his righteousness to a people yet unborn, that he has done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 22:27,28,30,31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has done it! The curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. Nothing now separates us from our Heavenly Father. Thank and praise the Lord that he has done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who shall bring any charge against God&amp;rsquo;s elect? It is God who justifies. Who is to condemn? Christ Jesus is the one who died⸺more than that, who was raised⸺who is at the right hand of God, who indeed is interceding for us. Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 8:33-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, rejoice that nothing can separate you from the love of Christ, no matter how hard the journey seems! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My strength is almost gone</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/my-strength-is-almost-gone/todd-trapani-v2Jf_jpNamc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My strength is almost gone" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you weary? So very weary? So weary in fact that you wonder whether you can carry on at all, even not quite knowing what that would mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is it that we are commanded to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be patient in tribulation. And go on being patient. And on. And on. Being patient. In tribulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when will it all end? Will it ever end? How can you continue to endure this, O my soul? Isn&amp;rsquo;t the prolonged nature of it all simply wearing you down?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you made Job&amp;rsquo;s heart-cry your very own?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I don’t have the strength to endure. I have nothing to live for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 6:11 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will it ever end? What is there to live for? Does anything even matter any more?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my Soul, listen to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By your endurance you will gain your lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 21:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is speaking of the great tribulation, but it makes no difference. By your endurance you will gain your life, O my soul. Your endurance matters then, O how it matters! Your life depends upon it. But what is it exactly? What is this endurance by which you will gain your life, beyond simply managing to exist through the trial? What indeed? And where will this endurance come from, that you may live?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s first consider the why, and through that understand the what and the how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For you have need of endurance, so that when you have done the will of God you may receive what is promised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 10:36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you want to receive what is promised? Do you want to receive what has been promised from the one whose name is Faithful and True? Then you have need of endurance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This endurance is what will enable you to do the will of God, and to keep on doing it. So now we must ask, what is the will of God here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then they said to him, “What must we do, to be doing the works of God?” Jesus answered them, “This is the work of God, that you believe in him whom he has sent.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 6:28-29&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is it. This is what it means to endure. Believe in Jesus, the one whom the Lord has sent! Above all else this means trust him. Trust him, absolutely and completely, and depend upon him, and on him alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Trust in the LORD with all your heart, and do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make straight your paths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 3:5-6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own understanding is quite simply not up to the task. This is entirely beyond me. O my soul, at that point beyond which you cannot understand what or why or how, you must surrender your need to understand, and simply trust the one who does⸺the one whose name is Faithful and True. Trust Jesus! And depend on him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be mindful that straight does not mean easy, but it does mean that there is a way. There is a way ahead, and by taking one step after another on this straight path, trusting and not doubting, you can continue. You can continue, O my soul, so do that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as you resolve to continue to take this path ahead, wondering whether you have the strength even for that, you must understand where strength comes from. It comes from hope. Hold on to hope. The one who promised is Faithful and True. Rejoice in that hope!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 12:12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength comes from hope. It comes from trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Those who trust in the LORD will find new strength. They will soar high on wings like eagles. They will run and not grow weary. They will walk and not faint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:31 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my Soul, I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to soaring on wings like an eagle, as that may be inconceivable for now. But know this. The word used for trust is the Hebrew &lt;em&gt;qâvâh&lt;/em&gt;, which could be translated wait for, or hope in, or expect. Yes, more waiting. More waiting, O my soul, but waiting in hope. And rejoicing in that hope. Paul and Isaiah are perfectly aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice in hope. Trust in and depend on Jesus, that he may be the one to lift you up. Oh, and be constant in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust in the Lord, O my soul, and find there new strength to carry on! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
