<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>repentance on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/repentance/</link>
        <description>Recent content in repentance on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/repentance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Self-satisfied and delusional</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/self-satisfied-and-delusional/nick-fewings-XpG9JaN_SXQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Self-satisfied and delusional" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a church completely and comprehensively lose its way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Laodicea write: ‘The words of the Amen, the faithful and true witness, the beginning of God&amp;rsquo;s creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works: you are neither cold nor hot. Would that you were either cold or hot! So, because you are lukewarm, and neither hot nor cold, I will spit you out of my mouth. For you say, I am rich, I have prospered, and I need nothing, not realizing that you are wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:14-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, grieve with Jesus over this self-satisfied and delusional church. And grieve further over their complete and unmitigated failure and shame. Recall that even in that dead church in Sardis there were some who had not soiled their garments, who being worthy would walk with Jesus in white. In Laodicea no such are mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could there have been such a gulf between how Jesus saw the church and how they saw themselves? Laodicea was a wealthy city and we may deduce that its church also was affluent and middle-class, seeing itself as rich in every way, lacking nothing. But how self-satisfied they were!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They thought they were rich, but they had failed to understand the currency of eternity. In reality they were paupers. And if they saw themselves as discerning, in reality they were blind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laodicea was entirely deception and delusion, but Jesus knew, and he knew they were wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked. How had this happened? How does this happen to any church which seems to be richly blessed, which maybe even gives the appearance of delighting in the Lord? Perhaps they had simply made their lives all about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah prophecies against just such. Note well the nature of the offence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cry aloud; do not hold back; lift up your voice like a trumpet; declare to my people their transgression, to the house of Jacob their sins. Yet they seek me daily and delight to know my ways, as if they were a nation that did righteousness and did not forsake the judgment of their God; they ask of me righteous judgments; they delight to draw near to God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how the house of Jacob delighted to draw near to God. Everything was simply magnificent, wasn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. No it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. O my soul, be appalled at their pride and listen to their self-justification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why have we fasted, and you see it not? Why have we humbled ourselves, and you take no knowledge of it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord thought otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, in the day of your fast you seek your own pleasure, and oppress all your workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:3b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how they were rebuked for their self-interest and lack of concern for others, and be dismayed with quite how much this contradicted what the Lord required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is not this the fast that I choose: to loose the bonds of wickedness, to undo the straps of the yoke, to let the oppressed go free, and to break every yoke? Is it not to share your bread with the hungry and bring the homeless poor into your house; when you see the naked, to cover him, and not to hide yourself from your own flesh?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 58:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus say later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A new commandment I give to you, that you love one another: just as I have loved you, you also are to love one another. By this all people will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see? Loving one another is the barometer of discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And humility? In their pride and self-satisfaction, how many Laodiceans would have been able to identify with Paul in saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-timothy&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Timothy 1:15b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the answer would have been none. Certainly none are mentioned by Jesus in his letter. In all six of the other churches, Jesus found at least something to commend⸺even in Sardis. But here, nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, wake up to this reality! Jesus&amp;rsquo; warning is as urgent as it is vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but the one who does the will of my Father who is in heaven. On that day many will say to me, ‘Lord, Lord, did we not prophesy in your name, and cast out demons in your name, and do many mighty works in your name?’ And then will I declare to them, ‘I never knew you; depart from me, you workers of lawlessness.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 7:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now recall that those Philadelphians, with such little power, were commended by Jesus without reservation. Do we see in Laodicea a church condemned without reservation? No we don&amp;rsquo;t⸺at least not that terrible and final condemnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, marvel over the grace and generosity in Jesus&amp;rsquo; lavish invitation to this prideful and delusional church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I counsel you to buy from me gold refined by fire, so that you may be rich, and white garments so that you may clothe yourself and the shame of your nakedness may not be seen, and salve to anoint your eyes, so that you may see. Those whom I love, I reprove and discipline, so be zealous and repent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus had not given up on this smug and self-satisfied church, and neither must you. They were wretched, pitiable, poor, blind, and naked, and yet look what Jesus was offering. Was it not exactly what they needed? What they really needed? And all they had to do to receive these things was to repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite unlike that open door in Philadelphia, the Laodiceans had firmly closed their own door. But listen again to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent invitation to prideful ones who have completely and comprehensively lost their way. Astonishingly, final condemnation is held back, and what is offered in its place is an invitation to repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The one who conquers, I will grant him to sit with me on my throne, as I also conquered and sat down with my Father on his throne. He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 3:21-22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, listen to what Jesus is saying, repent of self-interest and self-satisfaction, humble yourself, and reach out with love for others! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Repent!</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/repent/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/repent/cj-botha-PTztNC4yKY0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Repent!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear Jesus&amp;rsquo; urgent call to repent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This call to repent went out long ago to the church in Thyatira and it remains today. But let&amp;rsquo;s first marvel at Jesus&amp;rsquo; generous assessment of that church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And to the angel of the church in Thyatira write: ‘The words of the Son of God, who has eyes like a flame of fire, and whose feet are like burnished bronze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I know your works, your love and faith and service and patient endurance, and that your latter works exceed the first.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:18-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the church in Thyatira were these commended by Jesus for their love and faith and service and patient endurance. O my soul, how are your own love and faith and service and patient endurance? Jesus knows! His eyes are like a flame of fire and nothing is hidden from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did you notice the generosity in his assessment? Their latter works exceeded the first⸺some were slow starters. Jesus did not dwell on what came before. He commended them for how they were now. O my soul, leave the past behind! Jesus does not dwell on what came before and nor must you. Know that he is generous in his assessment also of you, desiring for you only what is good. He loves you and is committed to you and demands reciprocity in these. Rejoice that it is so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was not all good news in Thyatira.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But I have this against you, that you tolerate that woman Jezebel, who calls herself a prophetess and is teaching and seducing my servants to practice sexual immorality and to eat food sacrificed to idols. I gave her time to repent, but she refuses to repent of her sexual immorality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we come specifically to the seduction and the sexual immorality, let&amp;rsquo;s notice something significant here⸺a similarity and a difference with what we read in Jesus&amp;rsquo; letter to the church in Ephesus. Here we have a woman calling herself a prophetess and leading the church astray. In the church in Ephesus there were false apostles also leading the church astray. If that is the similarity what is the difference? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it that she was given time to repent and they were not? Recall that there was no call to repentance for those false apostles in Ephesus. They were simply excluded by Jesus and rejected. Tremble at that judgment and that rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now our instinct may be to characterise Jezebel&amp;rsquo;s sin as utterly heinous, far worse than what was happening in Ephesus, but pause to consider that Jesus did in fact give her that time to repent. This is not something we can understand in its entirety but surely warns us off ranking sins and ranking sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of those she was leading astray?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Behold, I will throw her onto a sickbed, and those who commit adultery with her I will throw into great tribulation, unless they repent of her works, and I will strike her children dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:22-23a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repent! O my soul, notice the urgency to repent. Jesus came to break the chains of bondage to sin and death and to give life in all its abundance, and repentance and faith are the means to receive this precious and lavish gift. But her children, her spiritual offspring who refuse this gift will be struck dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is this death? Is it not that final, second death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. The one who conquers will not be hurt by the second death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what then of the specifics of the sin⸺sexual immorality and eating of food sacrificed to idols. Of the former we can say one thing immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you not know that your bodies are members of Christ? Shall I then take the members of Christ and make them members of a prostitute? Never!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flee from sexual immorality. Every other sin a person commits is outside the body, but the sexually immoral person sins against his own body. Or do you not know that your body is a temple of the Holy Spirit within you, whom you have from God? You are not your own, for you were bought with a price. So glorify God in your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 6:15, 18-20&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How different this is from how our own world views such things. Sexual immorality deeply grieves the Lord, for it is a corruption and a debasement of his wonderful gift to those he made in his own image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is something wider going on here. The pagan worship of the day was centred around ritual sexual acts with temple prostitutes and eating of food sacrificed to idols, and this had come in to the church. How this dishonoured the Lord! It was the worldliness of the day invading his church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of worldliness invading the church in our own time? How this dishonours the Lord! And lest you be thinking that what was being rebuked in Thyatira was merely outward behaviour, think again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And all the churches will know that I am he who searches mind and heart, and I will give to each of you according to your works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:23b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the one who searches mind and heart. Mind and heart are where the Lord is first honoured or dishonoured. As Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What comes out of a person is what defiles him. For from within, out of the heart of man, come evil thoughts, sexual immorality, theft, murder, adultery, coveting, wickedness, deceit, sensuality, envy, slander, pride, foolishness. All these evil things come from within, and they defile a person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 7:20-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what must &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; repent of? O my soul, do not brush this question aside in complacency. Jesus searches mind and heart, and so must you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 4:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hear again Jesus&amp;rsquo; own voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Just so, I tell you, there is joy before the angels of God over one sinner who repents.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 15:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, repent, leave the past behind, and bring joy before the angels of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
