<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>love on O my Soul</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/tags/love/</link>
        <description>Recent content in love on O my Soul</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omysoul.faith/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Knitting</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/knitting/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/knitting/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/knitting/tanaphong-toochinda-WddCult7llk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Knitting" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you know about knitting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the Apostle Paul&amp;rsquo;s most earnest desire for the Colossians and for those at Laodicea and for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I want you to know how great a struggle I have for you and for those at Laodicea and for all who have not seen me face to face, that their hearts may be encouraged, being knit together in love, to reach all the riches of full assurance of understanding and the knowledge of God&amp;rsquo;s mystery, which is Christ, in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul desires that hearts may be encouraged by being knit together in love.  So let&amp;rsquo;s think about knitting for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essence of knitting is that the integrity of the whole garment is determined by the integrity of each and every stitch.  Every stitch matters for if any single one fails the whole garment unravels into a tangled and useless mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it is with the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each and every one matters, and the integrity and well-being of each and every one is essential to the integrity and well-being of the whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not only is it about being knit together, it is about being knit together &lt;em&gt;in love&lt;/em&gt;.  It is only love which can provide stitches of sufficient strength to withstand the trials of life and the attacks of the evil one.  Paul expands upon this in his letter to the Ephesians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I therefore, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to walk in a manner worthy of the calling to which you have been called, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; speaking the truth in love, we are to grow up in every way into him who is the head, into Christ, from whom the whole body, joined and held together by every joint with which it is equipped, when each part is working properly, makes the body grow so that it builds itself up in love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:1-2,15-16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word for held together is the very same as our word for knitting.  The whole body is knit together by each and every joint with which it is equipped, by each and every one, and this is from Christ, so that the body builds itself up in love.  It is entirely love and building up and knitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each part must be working properly.  O my soul, is each part in fact working properly?  Or are some parts neglected or rejected or denied the freedom to function as intended by the Creator?  The body must build itself up in love.  It must! And every stitch must be protected and nourished and cherished. It must!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is Paul&amp;rsquo;s exhortation here quite so earnest and so urgent.  He tells us precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I say this in order that no one may delude you with plausible arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See to it that no one takes you captive by philosophy and empty deceit, according to human tradition, according to the elemental spirits of the world, and not according to Christ. For in him the whole fullness of deity dwells bodily, and you have been filled in him, who is the head of all rule and authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore let no one pass judgment on you in questions of food and drink, or with regard to a festival or a new moon or a Sabbath. These are a shadow of the things to come, but the substance belongs to Christ. Let no-one disqualify you, insisting on asceticism and worship of angels, going on in detail about visions, puffed up without reason by his sensuous mind, and not holding fast to the Head, from whom the whole body, nourished and knit together through its joints and ligaments, grows with a growth that is from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:4,8-10,16-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware!  The danger here is from within the church, and it is real and present.  Beware those who go on about visions, puffed up without reason by self-importance and their sensuous minds.  Beware oh-so-plausible arguments.  Beware those who insist on asceticism.  Beware empty deceit according to human tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will save us from these real and present dangers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk in him, rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 2:6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Christ who saves, and we must be abounding in thanksgiving, for thanksgiving is the great leveller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified by his grace as a gift, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 3:23-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is thanksgiving that says I am nothing but a recipient of unmerited grace, and yet at the same time this unmerited grace is all I need.  Thank you Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then what?  Paul already told us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I therefore, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to walk in a manner worthy of the calling to which you have been called, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 4:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let each one walk worthy with the humility that comes from being rescued, with gentleness and patience, bearing with one another in love.  Imagine if we all stuck to our knitting, loving and looking after and building up the body of Christ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, stick to your knitting and love one another! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Alone</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/alone/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/alone/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/alone/christophe-dutour-Yg9UYltaplA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Alone" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are you finding being alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all your efforts to journey with others, to reach out, to care and protect, to invite others in, to share reciprocally even the most private and painful aspects of yours and others&amp;rsquo; situations, ultimately to love just as Jesus commanded, are you not still heart-breakingly lonely?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have evidently experienced that it is not good to be alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD God said, “It is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him a helper fit for him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 2:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this verse is about marriage⸺marriage that was God&amp;rsquo;s good and perfect gift to that first lonely man. Marriage that parallels the holy union between Christ and his beloved church. A beautiful gift. But like every other good and perfect gift from our Heavenly Father, one that has been spoiled and corrupted and taken out of its proper place and made an ultimate thing by our sinful generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For it is not an ultimate thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Jesus said to them, “The sons of this age marry and are given in marriage, but those who are considered worthy to attain to that age and to the resurrection from the dead neither marry nor are given in marriage, for they cannot die anymore, because they are equal to angels and are sons of God, being sons of the resurrection.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/luke&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Luke 20:34-36&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marriage is a temporary gift for those journeying through this lonely world, not an eternal one. And the Apostle Paul provides a perspective which many have overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now as a concession, not a command, I say this. I wish that all were as I myself am. But each has his own gift from God, one of one kind and one of another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the unmarried and the widows I say that it is good for them to remain single, as I am. But if they cannot exercise self-control, they should marry. For it is better to marry than to burn with passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-corinthians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 7:6-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we read Paul&amp;rsquo;s letters, do we not find him to be richly relational, a man steeped in love one another? And this found in a single man!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humankind was created for relationship, and marriage is just one outworking of that, but nevertheless one which has dominated and to some extent spoiled other outworkings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Solomon&amp;rsquo;s word of wisdom often quoted in the context of marriage is not in fact about marriage at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Two are better than one, because they have a good reward for their toil. For if they fall, one will lift up his fellow. But woe to him who is alone when he falls and has not another to lift him up!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ecclesiastes&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ecclesiastes 4:9-10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word fellow here means companion or associate. There is not a even a hint that it means spouse. Has this word of wisdom in fact been misappropriated by the married?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notice how our understanding of the riches of relationship in its wider context is impoverished by such a reinterpretation. O my soul, reinstate this wonderful verse into its proper place of relationship in general, and of Christian love and friendship and commitment in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But surely you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that loneliness is not the preserve of the single. How painfully and utterly alone one can be even in a marriage⸺and is that not a hundred times worse?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So know that you are not alone in being alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But notice also this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And after [Jesus] had dismissed the crowds, he went up on the mountain by himself to pray. When evening came, he was there alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 14:23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was there alone, and not only was this ok, it was in fact a critical part of his rich and full relationship with his Heavenly Father. He was often alone but never, at least not until his final hours, was he lonely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the one who came to show us wholeness in relationship did in fact spend so much of his time in close fellowship with his disciples. For human friendship is necessary for life and health and strength. Shame on any who draw back from friendship outside of their own marriages, excusing themselves with the platitude that Jesus is all the single people need, for the Father does not agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, Adam originally enjoyed full access to God in the coolness of the garden, and what did God have to say about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD God said, “It is not good that the man should be alone.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 2:18a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So human friendship is vital and life-giving, and what we were all created for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so what exactly is loneliness, and how is it different from being alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t loneliness about isolation? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it a sign of insufficient or insufficiently rich relationship? And isn&amp;rsquo;t this in fact a failure of each one of us to live out Jesus&amp;rsquo; new commandment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“A new commandment I give to you, that you love one another: just as I have loved you, you also are to love one another.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That loneliness is found even within the church shames us all. For ultimately the gospel is about relationship⸺restoration of our broken relationship with the Father, and restoration and healing in our relationships with one another. This is the entirety of the gospel, surely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in our broken world, loneliness is the pandemic of our time. What a mission field! What more does each lost soul crave but to be loved? So how can love not be our response? How can it not be my response? How can it not be the fulfillment of the Great Commission?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Just as I have loved you, you also are to love one another. By this all people will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 13:34b-35&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is love one another which is the barometer of discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So cry out to the Lord with the psalmist for deliverance from loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turn to me and be gracious to me, for I am lonely and afflicted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And above all, love one another!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also, you are not alone. You have faithful and kind friends. Cherish them! And be thankful, even if you find yourself living on the crumbs of relationship that fall from the table of those who have been richly and relationally blessed. Be thankful for crumbs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Oh, magnify the LORD with me, and let us exalt his name together!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 34:3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, magnify the Lord from your place of heartbreak, together with your friends, and above all, love one another! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Love marks the spot</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/love-marks-the-spot/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/love-marks-the-spot/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/love-marks-the-spot/suhash-villuri-DYWHwLZyJ64-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Love marks the spot" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you find the way to that treasure in heaven yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ought to have done so because it&amp;rsquo;s not well hidden and you have a map. But if perhaps you are thinking that X marks the spot you would be wrong. For it is in fact love which marks the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And behold, a man came up to [Jesus], saying, “Teacher, what good deed must I do to have eternal life?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn a lesson from this likeable young man, for many make similar mistakes and he made several, and there&amp;rsquo;s one right here in the first thing he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“What good deed must I do to have eternal life?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One good deed? In the singular? Just one? Will that be enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And [Jesus] said to him, “Why do you ask me about what is good? There is only one who is good. If you would enter life, keep the commandments.” He said to him, “Which ones?” And Jesus said, “You shall not murder, You shall not commit adultery, You shall not steal, You shall not bear false witness, Honour your father and mother, and, You shall love your neighbour as yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:17-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this interesting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus has quoted only six of the Ten Commandments. He skipped the first four. Why would he do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall the context in which the Lord introduced the Ten Commandments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And God spoke all these words, saying, “I am the LORD your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of slavery.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 20:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commandments were given to the Israelites by their rescuer and redeemer who had every right to command obedience⸺the one who is also our own rescuer and redeemer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are the four commandments which Jesus skipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You shall have no other gods before me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not make for yourself a carved image, or any likeness of anything that is in heaven above, or that is in the earth beneath, or that is in the water under the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not take the name of the LORD your God in vain,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Remember the Sabbath day, to keep it holy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 20:3-4,7a,8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll come to Jesus&amp;rsquo; skipping⸺or as we&amp;rsquo;ll see, not skipping⸺over these headline commandments. But before we do that, let&amp;rsquo;s notice his rephrasing of the tenth commandment. Listen to the continuation as originally given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Honour your father and your mother, that your days may be long in the land that the LORD your God is giving you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not commit adultery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not bear false witness against your neighbour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shall not covet your neighbour&amp;rsquo;s house; you shall not covet your neighbour&amp;rsquo;s wife, or his male servant, or his female servant, or his ox, or his donkey, or anything that is your neighbour&amp;rsquo;s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 20:12-17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Jesus said, “You shall not murder, You shall not commit adultery, You shall not steal, You shall not bear false witness, Honour your father and mother, and, You shall love your neighbour as yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:18b-19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus restated the commandment not to covet as, “You shall love your neighbour as yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How interesting! Why would he do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was unwrapping the commandment to reveal the full extent of its reach, which is far more than its original hearers had understood, and far more than any of us have understood. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that his main point in the Sermon on the Mount?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice too the young man&amp;rsquo;s eagerness to claim obedience to these and how Jesus gently exposed his shortfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The young man said to him, “All these I have kept. What do I still lack?” Jesus said to him, “If you would be perfect, go, sell what you possess and give to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven; and come, follow me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:20-21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The young man hadn&amp;rsquo;t remotely kept these commandments and as such was so much like us. So Jesus simply showed him the full extent of “love your neighbour as yourself” until the young man understood his shortfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the young man heard this he went away sorrowful, for he had great possessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:22&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only was his failure to love revealed but suddenly too were his idols exposed. For what was it that defined him? What was he living for? What had he built his life upon? Jesus showed him and he went away sorrowful. What a tragic figure he was, and how very much like us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For are we ourselves not overflowing in material wealth in our western affluence? Are we not rich like that tragic young man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And Jesus said to his disciples, “Truly, I say to you, only with difficulty will a rich person enter the kingdom of heaven. Again I tell you, it is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich person to enter the kingdom of God.” When the disciples heard this, they were greatly astonished, saying, “Who then can be saved?” But Jesus looked at them and said, “With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:23-26&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clearly impossible for a camel to pass through the eye of a needle, notwithstanding the weasel words of reinterpretation imposed upon this verse by commentators throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hear Jesus&amp;rsquo; words, and cry out in gratitude and adoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:26b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what about Jesus&amp;rsquo; skipping over the first four commandments? Are these not in fact the more important, for it is these which concern our relationship with our Heavenly Father, which must surely come ahead of our relationships with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And one of the scribes came up and heard them disputing with one another, and seeing that he answered them well, asked him, “Which commandment is the most important of all?” Jesus answered, “The most important is, ‘Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. And you shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength.’ The second is this: ‘You shall love your neighbour as yourself.’ There is no other commandment greater than these.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 12:28-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So notice how Jesus returns to exactly this in our passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Peter said in reply, “See, we have left everything and followed you. What then will we have?” Jesus said to them, “Truly, I say to you, in the new world, when the Son of Man will sit on his glorious throne, you who have followed me will also sit on twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel. And everyone who has left houses or brothers or sisters or father or mother or children or lands, for my name&amp;rsquo;s sake, will receive a hundredfold and will inherit eternal life. But many who are first will be last, and the last first.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 19:27-30&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this not in fact precisely the commandment? Have no other gods before the Lord, and worship no idols. Put the Lord ahead of houses and brothers and sisters and father and mother and children and lands. And is Jesus not doing for us precisely what he did for that young man when he showed him how completely and comprehensively he had failed to understand “love your neighbour as yourself”, but now in the context of “love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these verses are addressed also to us. Have we actually understood “You shall have no other gods before me”? How the idols creep in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, what is it that you have you placed ahead of the Lord? Gently and firmly and unequivocally Jesus says repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what a return on that investment you can expect! A hundredfold! So do not hold back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, love the Lord with all of your being, and your neighbour as yourself, and you shall have treasure in heaven, a hundredfold of what you surrender for the Kingdom! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A love song</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/a-love-song/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/a-love-song/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/a-love-song/darius-F8E2tks5N04-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A love song" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your heart overflowing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore we must pay much closer attention to what we have heard, lest we drift away from it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 2:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay much closer attention then. But to what? To what must we pay closer attention? How about this love song?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To the choirmaster: according to Lilies. A Maskil of the Sons of Korah; a love song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45 heading&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here in fact is the very best of love songs. O my soul, are you ready to sing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My heart overflows with a pleasing theme; I address my verses to the king; my tongue is like the pen of a ready scribe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to address the king? Is your tongue ready like the pen of a scribe? So who is this king? And what will you write? Let&amp;rsquo;s consider him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You are the most handsome of the sons of men; grace is poured upon your lips; therefore God has blessed you forever. Gird your sword on your thigh, O mighty one, in your splendour and majesty!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45:2-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This king is most handsome and mighty in splendour and majesty. But how is any of this relevant? Isn&amp;rsquo;t this merely some dusty old psalm about David or one of those other so very few noble kings of Israel. By no means!  Let us behold here something truly wondrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In your majesty ride out victoriously for the cause of truth and meekness and righteousness; let your right hand teach you awesome deeds! Your arrows are sharp in the heart of the king&amp;rsquo;s enemies; the peoples fall under you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The king&amp;rsquo;s cause is truth and meekness and righteousness. Meekness is our first real clue as to his identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your throne, O God, is forever and ever. The sceptre of your kingdom is a sceptre of uprightness; you have loved righteousness and hated wickedness. Therefore God, your God, has anointed you with the oil of gladness beyond your companions; your robes are all fragrant with myrrh and aloes and cassia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45:6-8a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the reveal⸺the anointing and the robes and the fragrance. For the anointing is with the oil of gladness and the fragrance is of myrrh and aloes. It is the fragrance of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After [Jesus died] Joseph of Arimathea, who was a disciple of Jesus, but secretly for fear of the Jews, asked Pilate that he might take away the body of Jesus, and Pilate gave him permission. So he came and took away his body. Nicodemus also, who earlier had come to Jesus by night, came bringing a mixture of myrrh and aloes, about seventy-five pounds in weight. So they took the body of Jesus and bound it in linen cloths with the spices, as is the burial custom of the Jews. Now in the place where he was crucified there was a garden, and in the garden a new tomb in which no one had yet been laid. So because of the Jewish day of Preparation, since the tomb was close at hand, they laid Jesus there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 19:38-42&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what of cassia? Moses was instructed in that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Moses, “Take the finest spices: of liquid myrrh 500 shekels, and of sweet-smelling cinnamon half as much, that is, 250, and 250 of aromatic cane, and 500 of cassia, according to the shekel of the sanctuary, and a hin of olive oil. And you shall make of these a sacred anointing oil blended as by the perfumer; it shall be a holy anointing oil.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 30:22-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a holy anointing oil. It is an oil of holiness and of death and yet also an oil of gladness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where is the love song we were promised? Right here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hear, O daughter, and consider, and incline your ear: forget your people and your father&amp;rsquo;s house, and the king will desire your beauty. Since he is your lord, bow to him. The people of Tyre will seek your favour with gifts, the richest of the people.⁠&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45:10-12&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if the king is Jesus who is this daughter whose beauty he desires? She is the one who has made him her Lord. She is the one who has left her past behind and who is living for him. She is his church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And look how he sees her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All glorious is the princess in her chamber, with robes interwoven with gold. In many-coloured robes she is led to the king, with her virgin companions following behind her. With joy and gladness they are led along as they enter the palace of the king.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45:13-15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is his glorious church, his beloved bride. And with joy and gladness she enters his presence, the palace of the king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the love song between Jesus and his church. It is a song founded on myrrh and aloes. It is a song founded on her leaving and cleaving. It is our song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what happens as we sing this song?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will cause your name to be remembered in all generations; therefore nations will praise you forever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 45:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, sing this love song to Jesus, our Lord and Saviour, that his name be remembered in all generations! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Walk before me and be blameless</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/walk-before-me-and-be-blameless/anton-darius-zjGa2RQphRA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Walk before me and be blameless" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How on earth will you walk before the Lord and be blameless?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless, that I may make my covenant between me and you, and may multiply you greatly.” Then Abram fell on his face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1-3a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall why Abraham fell on his face. Despite holding that impossible promise from the Lord for all those years, his life had been defined by cowardice and lies and failure and shame. He was at this time living with the consequence of having tried to fulfil that promise in his own strength, by fathering a child with the slave-girl Hagar. And I&amp;rsquo;m quite sure he enjoyed that at the time, having sex with the youthful Egyptian slave-girl rather than his ancient wife. But not now. Not when confronted with his sin and his shame and his failure by the Holy God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thirteen long years of living with the mess of that shameful failure all together in close proximity in that dysfunctional household,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old the LORD appeared to Abram and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 17:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham was overwhelmed by his own sin and shame and wretchedness, and when confronted by the holiness of God and his command, “Walk before me, and be blameless,” he fell on his face. There is nothing else he could have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And whatever your situation, whatever shameful failure lies in your own past, and whatever the stumbling in more recent times, this is also addressed to you. It is exactly that to which each one of us is called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been chosen for you, but how on earth will you walk before this Holy God yourself and be holy and blameless? You must do this if you would enjoy his strong support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the eyes of the LORD run to and fro throughout the whole earth, to give strong support to those whose heart is blameless toward him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/2-chronicles&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Chronicles 16:9a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But isn&amp;rsquo;t this all too much to ask of an unholy people? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the Creator God of the Universe chose each one of us in Christ, even before the foundation of the world, to be holy and blameless before him. He chose you for this and he chose me. You and I both must surrender to the choice of the one who is wise and strong and who knows how to achieve his plans and purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Job&amp;rsquo;s profession of faith after he had been confronted by the overwhelming greatness and majesty of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then Job answered the LORD and said: “I know that you can do all things, and that no purpose of yours can be thwarted.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same overwhelmingly great and majestic God has a purpose for you and for me both, that we should be holy and blameless before him. So cry out to him along with the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfils his purpose for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 57:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not think you can resist the irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many are the plans in the mind of a man, but it is the purpose of the LORD that will stand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 19:21&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you must surrender your life to the Holy Spirit as he does his sanctifying work in you. Resistance is futile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can unholy creatures be made holy? The answer is found only in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And you, who once were alienated and hostile in mind, doing evil deeds, he has now reconciled in his body of flesh by his death, in order to present you holy and blameless and above reproach before him, if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/colossians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:21-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has reconciled each one to himself in Christ&amp;rsquo;s body and by his death in order to present each one holy and blameless and above reproach before him. So do not shift from the hope of the gospel that you have heard, but which may not just now be in the forefront of your mind. Make it so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? How can we become holy, even according to his purposes? His strong and sure work of grace in our lives? If you desire this end, you must set your heart upon it. But isn&amp;rsquo;t it all just too hard? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it seem to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 7:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I am up against. So how then can I co-operate with the Spirit of Christ in being transformed and made holy? Simply by noticing this: the strong connection between blamelessness and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now may our God and Father himself, and our Lord Jesus, direct our way to you, and may the Lord make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all, as we do for you, so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father, at the coming of our Lord Jesus with all his saints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-thessalonians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Thessalonians 3:11-13&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the Lord himself make you increase and abound in love for one another and for all precisely so that he may establish your hearts blameless in holiness before our God and Father. Oh my!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love that abounds more and more is the way to become pure and blameless for the day of Christ, and also quite remarkably how to fulfil the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Love does no wrong to a neighbour; therefore love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the power of love that will transform each one, and this fruit of righteousness comes only through Jesus. So set your course with determination to love the Lord with all your heart, soul, mind, and strength, and to love your neighbour as yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even as you wait on the Lord, even as you cry out to him through these long years of waiting, walk before him and be blameless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I will sing of steadfast love and justice; to you, O LORD, I will make music. I will ponder the way that is blameless. Oh when will you come to me? I will walk with integrity of heart within my house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 101:1-2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you hear the waiting and the longing here? Oh when will you come to me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But above all, know that you will only be able to do any of this because of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now to him who is able to keep you from stumbling and to present you blameless before the presence of his glory with great joy, to the only God, our Saviour, through Jesus Christ our Lord, be glory, majesty, dominion, and authority, before all time and now and forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/jude&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jude 1:24-25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, even in the waiting time, even in the heartbreak and the desperate longing, ensure to increase and abound in love, and so walk before him and be blameless! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>New mercy</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/new-mercy/karl-magnuson-HQR_JXd-fPs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post New mercy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is far more significant than the new year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is new mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/but-this-i-call-to-mind-and-therefore-i-have-hope/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;As I remarked previously&lt;/a&gt; the context of these verses is the destruction of Jerusalem after Nebuchadnezzar&amp;rsquo;s siege of a year-and-a-half, and the exile of Judah to Babylon⸺the grimmest of times indeed, and moreover, the judgment of the Lord on his own people for their ongoing waywardness and apostasy. Enough was enough. But we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have unceasing steadfast love and mercy, &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt;, which so often go together and are surely &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://letterstoamy.org/love-mercy/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Lord&amp;rsquo;s most defining attributes&lt;/a&gt; as he revealed on Mount Sinai in response to Moses&amp;rsquo; request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD descended in the cloud and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the LORD. The LORD passed before him and proclaimed, “The LORD, the LORD, a God merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love and faithfulness, keeping steadfast love to the thousandth generation, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, but who will by no means clear the guilty, visiting the iniquity of the fathers on the children and the children&amp;rsquo;s children, to the third and the fourth generation.” And Moses quickly bowed his head toward the earth and worshipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 33:18, 34:5-8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of such power and love and mercy, Moses&amp;rsquo; response was the only one possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s description of himself was &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;nâsâh&lt;/em&gt;, the last of which means forgiving, or so beautifully, lifting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, take a breath right now and worship the Lord of Hosts, whose name is love and mercy and forgiveness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must not move past this revelation of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s character without noticing where it came in the sequence of events. Moses had previously been with the Lord on Mount Sinai for forty days and forty nights, during which time he received instruction on how the Israelites were to live to honour the Lord, which was written on those two tablets of stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he gave to Moses, when he had finished speaking with him on Mount Sinai, the two tablets of the testimony, tablets of stone, written with the finger of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 31:18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what did Moses find when he descended from the mountain of God? The Israelites had made for themselves a golden calf which they worshipped. In dismay Moses threw the tablets to the ground and broke them, and directed the faithful remnant, the Levites, to strap on swords and execute their brothers and neighbours throughout the camp, about three thousand. More subsequently died of the plague sent by the Lord in judgment on his people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this relevant? Because of what happened next. Moses was instructed to make new tablets, and the Lord revealed himself again as the God of love and mercy and forgiveness and also vengeance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said, “Behold, I am making a covenant. Before all your people I will do marvels, such as have not been created in all the earth or in any nation. And all the people among whom you are shall see the work of the LORD, for it is an awesome thing that I will do with you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:10&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they were given instructions. Again. Including this. Again. O my soul, grieve that this was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You shall not make for yourself any gods of cast metal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But also, interestingly, this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You shall not offer the blood of my sacrifice with anything leavened, or let the sacrifice of the Feast of the Passover remain until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/exodus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:25&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which echoes in this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And the flesh of the sacrifice of his peace offerings for thanksgiving shall be eaten on the day of his offering. He shall not leave any of it until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/leviticus&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Leviticus 7:15&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sacrifice was not to be left until the morning. But why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is precisely where we came in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:22-23&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s mercy is new every morning. It is simply not appropriate that the sacrifice remain until the next morning because new mercy has flooded in and it is overwhelmingly sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is new about this mercy? It is precisely because of the context of these verses⸺the propensity of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people to continue in their waywardness and apostasy, as it ever has been and still remains to this day. His mercy is new every morning and so very needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do not be deceived. There are two mistakes you must avoid. The first is to think that somehow your own heart is different from those Israelites, that you are somehow better. You are not. That propensity for waywardness and unbelief and sin remains, and so you must be vigilant and disciplined and repentant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second mistake is to doubt the sufficiency of that new mercy. But his mercy is more, and his mercy is new every morning! And his forgiveness is a lifting up anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So rejoice in the very next verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The LORD is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/lamentations&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lamentations 3:24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord is indeed my portion and my inheritance. He is all I need and therefore I will hope in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just as with Moses, there is only one possible response to this revelation of the character of God, and it is worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bless the LORD, O my soul, and all that is within me, bless his holy name! Bless the LORD, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits, who forgives all your iniquity, who heals all your diseases, who redeems your life from the pit, who crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, who satisfies you with good so that your youth is renewed like the eagle&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 103:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, &lt;em&gt;chêsêd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;racham&lt;/em&gt;. He crowns you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, worship the one who crowns you with steadfast love and mercy, and put all your hope in him for this brave new year! 🙏❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Open your own eyes</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 06:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/open-your-own-eyes/ben-white-EMZxDosijJ4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Open your own eyes" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you desire that the Lord light up your eyes, what are you doing about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you surprised that I ask what you are doing, as if it could make any difference? Whether the Lord chooses to light up your eyes is entirely out of your hands isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen again to the psalmist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The law of the LORD is perfect, reviving the soul; the testimony of the LORD is sure, making wise the simple; the precepts of the LORD are right, rejoicing the heart; the commandment of the LORD is pure, enlightening the eyes; the fear of the LORD is clean, enduring forever; the rules of the LORD are true, and righteous altogether. More to be desired are they than gold, even much fine gold; sweeter also than honey and drippings of the honeycomb. Moreover, by them is your servant warned; in keeping them there is great reward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 19:7-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by noticing the pure commandment of the Lord which enlightens the eyes. But we must ingest the whole of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you desire the rules of the Lord? Do you know their sweetness? Do you know that great reward which is keeping them? Do you desire to be revived? Are you feeding and watering that desire that it may flourish, and you with it? Do you even know how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is telling it, over and over. The law of the Lord is perfect. The testimony of the Lord is sure. The precepts of the Lord are right. The commandment of the Lord is pure. These revive the soul, make wise the simple, rejoice the heart, and enlighten the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my question to you is, have you immersed yourself in these and do you continue to do so? Do you begin each new day by plunging into the word of God, his law, his testimony, his precepts, and his commandments? And if not, why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is joy here in the face of a demoralising and depressing world. There is power here in the face of the overwhelming and apparently insoluble problems of the world⸺oppression, self-interest, corruption, exploitation, hatred, and war. In such contrast to the world&amp;rsquo;s murkiness and moral ambiguity, the commandment of the Lord is pure and it enlightens the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, steep yourself in the word of God, each morning and throughout the day. Wrap yourself in it and walk in it, with rejoicing and a grateful heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you have been waiting for deliverance now for so long you have started to think there is nothing else you can do. O my soul, you must not wallow in your waiting, as if there is nothing to be done. That could not be further from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your waiting, as days become weeks and weeks become months and with each passing year, are you growing in your desire for the Lord? Are you growing in faith? Are you growing in love and holiness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, this year is so very rapidly approaching its end. Ask yourself, does my heart desire the Lord more so now than at its beginning? Is my faith stronger and more resilient? Have I grown in love and holiness? If not, it has surely been a waste of a year. Do not be so negligent as to waste the next one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your own longing for change listen to the longing of the psalmist. It is above all a longing for personal holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are those whose way is blameless,
who walk in the law of the LORD! Blessed are those who keep his testimonies, who seek him with their whole heart, who also do no wrong, but walk in his ways! You have commanded your precepts to be kept diligently. Oh that my ways may be steadfast in keeping your statutes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:1-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is both longing and determination here, and also realism, for doesn&amp;rsquo;t this task seem to be utterly beyond us? But it is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your testimonies are wonderful; therefore my soul keeps them. The unfolding of your words gives light; it imparts understanding to the simple. I open my mouth and pant, because I long for your commandments. Turn to me and be gracious to me, as is your way with those who love your name. Keep steady my steps according to your promise, and let no iniquity get dominion over me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:129-133&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, you must be diligent to let no iniquity get dominion over you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three more things that remain to be done, and these can be learnt from the Apostle Paul in just half a sentence. The whole sentence is simply too overwhelming to take in at one go, because this is Paul! He has just been describing our glorious inheritance in Christ and the guarantee we have in the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this reason, because I have heard of your faith in the Lord Jesus and your love toward all the saints, I do not cease to give thanks for you, remembering you in my prayers, that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of him, having the eyes of your hearts enlightened &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 1:15-18a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these three things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is to exercise faith in the Lord Jesus, so it may grow. Are you waiting on an impossible promise from the Lord? Then keep on waiting, believing and not doubting, and he will light up your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is to pray. This is Paul&amp;rsquo;s prayer for the saints in Ephesus. Make it your own and not only yours. Pray for the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of the Lord to light up the eyes of your heart, those eyes of faith, which must shine in expectation and reflected glory. And pray this also for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third is to love. Do not hold back from loving all the saints. The saints are simply the Lord&amp;rsquo;s people, although some are not yet so very saintly to be sure, being still in the early stages of sanctification and humility. But you must love, and you must not overlook that little word &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt;. If you desire that the Lord light up your eyes, then you must love all the saints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desiring the law of the Lord and his testimonies and his precepts and his commandments and his rules is ultimately an outworking of love itself, our love for the Lord in response to his own great love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you starting to understand how to put yourself in the place of the Lord lighting up your eyes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, love the Lord and do not hold back! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Enduring in love</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/enduring-in-love/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/enduring-in-love/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/enduring-in-love/mahmoud-sulaiman-aO9nGw9Cbk0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Enduring in love" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the most important thing? And what must remain the most important thing even when confronted by unbearable evil?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this let&amp;rsquo;s examine both Jesus&amp;rsquo; commendation and his rebuke of the church in Ephesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“To the angel of the church in Ephesus write: ‘The words of him who holds the seven stars in his right hand, who walks among the seven golden lampstands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘I know your works, your toil and your patient endurance, and how you cannot bear with those who are evil, but have tested those who call themselves apostles and are not, and found them to be false. I know you are enduring patiently and bearing up for my name&amp;rsquo;s sake, and you have not grown weary.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the words of the risen Lord Jesus, who holds the angels of the seven churches in his right hand, who walks among the seven churches, and whose name is Faithful and True. Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly let&amp;rsquo;s notice the patient endurance which is so highly commended, and the toil. Enduring patiently is hard work! It is heart work. These Ephesian Christians were enduring patiently and not growing weary. How they must have been fixing their eyes on Jesus!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us, looking to Jesus, the founder and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is seated at the right hand of the throne of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider him who endured from sinners such hostility against himself, so that you may not grow weary or fainthearted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/hebrews&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 12:1-3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you notice an absolutely vital element of patient endurance here? It is personal holiness. &lt;em&gt;Let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely.&lt;/em&gt; A life beset by sin saps endurance and loses the race. A holy life endures and wins the race. Choose to live a holy life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now endurance is only so in the face of adversity. So what was the adversity in Ephesus? We are told immediately. There was a clear and present evil, namely those who called themselves apostles and were not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be said about those self-proclaimed and false apostles? They were surely found among the Ephesian church, because otherwise what testing would have been required, and what would these patient and enduring ones have had to bear? These patient ones so highly commended by Jesus? But at the same time, those false apostles did not belong to the church. Strikingly, this letter to the church is not addressed to them. They are third parties, judged by Jesus himself to be inconsequential and irrelevant. There is no call for their repentance. They are simply not part of his church. O my soul, tremble at this complete and comprehensive rejection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can wonder at the impact they were having on the Ephesian church. It was likely profound. But Jesus&amp;rsquo; focus is on those he calls his own, whom he commends for enduring patiently and bearing up for his name&amp;rsquo;s sake⸺for Jesus&amp;rsquo; name&amp;rsquo;s sake⸺for the sake of all he is and all he has done. This is why they endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And quite remarkably, they have not grown weary. O my soul, think on that. How wearisome would be this opposition and yet their strength remains. Praise the Lord for his strengthening under such adversarial circumstances!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet these very ones commended for their patient endurance are at the same time rebuked by the Lord. Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But I have this against you, that you have abandoned the love you had at first. Remember therefore from where you have fallen; repent, and do the works you did at first. If not, I will come to you and remove your lampstand from its place, unless you repent.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:4-5&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rebuke is for lack of love, abandonment even, of the very most important thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And one of the scribes came up and heard them disputing with one another, and seeing that he answered them well, asked him, “Which commandment is the most important of all?” Jesus answered, “The most important is, ‘Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. And you shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind and with all your strength.’ The second is this: ‘You shall love your neighbour as yourself.’ There is no other commandment greater than these.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/mark&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mark 12:28-31&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is indeed no other commandment greater than these. Not only does love conquer all, but it must be ahead of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These who patiently endured had once loved with Jesus&amp;rsquo; own love, but they had fallen away from this. And notice Jesus&amp;rsquo; exhortation that they &lt;em&gt;do the works they did at first&lt;/em&gt;. Love is such a practical thing. It is something to be done. Both love for the Lord and love for one another are evidenced by works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful here. Some are rather eager to ask, what does that look like? But that is entirely the wrong question. How so? It is vital that this be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is required is love⸺our own love response to that great Calvary love poured out. Who can say what action might result from that? But one thing is clear. It is the love that counts. The action is merely evidence of that love. Aping this is of little value. Action without love is hollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And notice this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What good is it, my brothers, if someone says he has faith but does not have works? Can that faith save him? If a brother or sister is poorly clothed and lacking in daily food, and one of you says to them, “Go in peace, be warmed and filled,” without giving them the things needed for the body, what good is that? So also faith by itself, if it does not have works, is dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But someone will say, “You have faith and I have works.” Show me your faith apart from your works, and I will show you my faith by my works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/james&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James 2:14-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with faith so with love. It is seen by works but those works cannot substitute for love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we must not neglect to notice just how much is at stake here. Here is a wake-up call for those whose love is mediocre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. To the one who conquers I will grant to eat of the tree of life, which is in the paradise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 2:7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conquering here is relearning to love⸺there was no other rebuke. And we know what this tree of life is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then the LORD God said, “Behold, the man has become like one of us in knowing good and evil. Now, lest he reach out his hand and take also of the tree of life and eat, and live forever—” therefore the LORD God sent him out from the garden of Eden to work the ground from which he was taken. He drove out the man, and at the east of the garden of Eden he placed the cherubim and a flaming sword that turned every way to guard the way to the tree of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:22-24&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fruit of the tree of life is well guarded, kept for the one who conquers. O my soul, think about that love you had at first. That great Calvary love, poured out for you. And be that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By this we know love, that he laid down his life for us, and we ought to lay down our lives for the brothers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We love because he first loved us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 4:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, love again with that love you had at first, that great Calvary love poured out for you!🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A pure heart</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 06:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/a-pure-heart/bas-glaap-DEQS0GFk4AM-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A pure heart" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you given much thought to what is pure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honourable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 4:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is pure then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The words of the LORD are pure words, like silver refined in a furnace on the ground, purified seven times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 12:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This psalm underlines the striking contrast between the purity of the Lord and his words and the double-mindedness of humankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everyone utters lies to his neighbour; with flattering lips and a double heart they speak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 12:2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words of the Lord then are pure, but what else? Is the catalogue of what is pure in fact a very short list indeed? Could we add to that list? What else could be pure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/matthew&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 5:8&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this one beatitude stand out from among the others as utterly intimidating? Being poor in spirit, mourning, meekness, hunger and thirsting for righteousness, being merciful⸺isn&amp;rsquo;t our response to those others, yes Lord? But being pure in heart? Isn&amp;rsquo;t our response to this, O Lord have mercy on me, a sinner? Yes of course it is, at least it is if we have any honesty in our own self-evaluation. And that is because it seems to be utterly beyond us. But is it? Is it really? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this, and as we do, give thought to the prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you want to see God? Then resolve to do this, to be pure in heart. But how? How can we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job&amp;rsquo;s friend Eliphaz uttered much foolishness in his earnest desire to help Job. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can mortal man be in the right before God? Can a man be pure before his Maker?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 4:17&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He followed up with two rhetorical questions, revealing the limitations of his own understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is man, that he can be pure? Or he who is born of a woman, that he can be righteous?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 15:14&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was wrong, O my soul. Rejoice that he was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The LORD said to Eliphaz the Temanite: “My anger burns against you and against your two friends, for you have not spoken of me what is right, as my servant Job has.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/job&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 42:7b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s try to answer the question by understanding how. How is it possible to be pure before the Lord? There are three elements which must come together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 1:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleanse means purify. Jesus came and died for you and for me and for all of humankind, that we may be forgiven our sin, that we may be justified and redeemed, and that we may be purified from all unrighteousness. The justification and redemption were an immediate and once-and-for-all-time thing. The purification is a rest-of-our-life thing and is the ongoing work of the Holy Spirit. Without the body and blood of Jesus there can be no meaningful purification, so perhaps Eliphaz was not entirely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first and most fundamental element of purification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psalmist points us to the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can a young man keep his way pure? By guarding it according to your word. With my whole heart I seek you; let me not wander from your commandments! I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/psalms&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 119:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this. I am that young man, so desiring to keep my way pure and yet so aware of the challenge in that, and so aware of my own propensity to sin⸺so aware of how I fall short, and therefore so resolute in guarding my heart according to the revealed word of God. And seeking him will take my whole heart, but it will be so worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you, declares the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/jeremiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Jeremiah 29:13-14a&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all my heart I will seek the Lord, ruthlessly and unrelentingly. No holding back. No compromise. No distractions. My heart-cry is, let me not wander from your commandments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, do you understand what it means to store up his word in your heart? Immerse yourself in the Bible. It is his precious gift to us. Read it. Savour it. Chew on it. Digest it. Commit it to memory. And do it. It will guard your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second element of purification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third? The third element is surprising and inclined to be overlooked in this regard, but it is in fact the game-changer, the red pill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third element is the extraordinary power of love, both the Lord&amp;rsquo;s great love which came first, and our love response to his rescue⸺our love for the Lord and our love for one another. Isn&amp;rsquo;t this simply astonishing? That the outworking of authentic and abounding love could be a pure heart? Let&amp;rsquo;s think about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fruit of righteousness comes through Jesus Christ, and is to the glory and praise of God. It is his own work in us, and it is all of grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/ephesians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:8-9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We love because he first loved us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/1-john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 John 4:19&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is love from a grateful heart. But how can purity be the result of this love? Didn&amp;rsquo;t the Pharisees expend so much energy dotting every &lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt; and crossing every &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; in order to become pure? And there are so many commandments to keep. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it all utterly wearying, completely beyond us? By no means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Owe no one anything, except to love each other, for the one who loves another has fulfilled the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/romans&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Romans 13:8, 10b&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is the fulfilling of the law, and surely this is purity before the Lord. A pure heart then is the outworking of authentic and abounding love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Who can say, “I have made my heart pure; I am clean from my sin?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/proverbs&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Proverbs 20:9&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, know that this is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s will for you, so receive it and embrace it and pursue it with your whole heart! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Created for his glory</title>
        <link>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 06:30:00 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://omysoul.faith/created-for-his-glory/mohamed-nohassi-odxB5oIG_iA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Created for his glory" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;O my soul,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, why do you exist? What were you created for? You must know this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading in Isaiah, and I am overwhelmed by what I read. Before we come to my question though, let&amp;rsquo;s consider how the Lord regards us, his beloved ones. Let&amp;rsquo;s lose ourselves in the love letter which is Isaiah Chapter 43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD, he who created you, O Jacob, he who formed you, O Israel: “Fear not, for I have redeemed you; I have called you by name, you are mine.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember Jacob? He was that despicable little man, that man entirely without honour, a liar and a cheat. The man who wrestled with God, all night. The man to whom God gave a new name, Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So these words addressed to Jacob, who are they for? Their setting was the Babylonian exile. Jacob had been dead for perhaps a thousand years. Not for him then! These words are for his descendants⸺not his physical descendants, but the children of the promise⸺and that includes us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, these words are spoken to you by the God who created you, who formed you, who continues to form you⸺and he is not done with the forming by any means!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:6&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/philippians&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Philippians 1:9-11&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that you may be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness. Fear not, O my soul. You have been redeemed by the Creator God of the universe. Called by him. Known by him. Belonging to him. Rejoice in that ineffable truth and embrace the forming of purity and blamelessness in your own life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this: you are called by name. Your name is who you are. It is your character. You are fully known by the one who calls. There is nothing that the Lord could subsequently learn about you which would change how he regards you. You are called and you are known and you are his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember God&amp;rsquo;s question to Jacob after the wrestling?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And he said to him, “What is your name?” And he said, “Jacob.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:27&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is God asking here? He is the omniscient and all powerful Creator God of the universe and he asks, “What is your name?” He is not seeking information! The question to Jacob is, what kind of man are you? And Jacob confesses his name⸺the cheat, the deceiver, vile and despicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then he said, “Your name shall no longer be called Jacob, but Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/genesis&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 32:28&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behold! God is the one who makes all things new! Praise him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And marvel at the extent to which the Lord will go to do this. Isaiah continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For I am the LORD your God, the Holy One of Israel, your Saviour. I give Egypt as your ransom, Cush and Seba in exchange for you. Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:3-4&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is my saviour. He is your saviour. The ransom is costly and there is no limit to where he will go for the rescue, because I am precious in his eyes, and honoured. Because you are precious, and he loves you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O my soul, he gave one man in particular in return for you: Jesus Christ, the only Son of God, in exchange for your life. In exchange for mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/john&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 3:16&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ransom is costly. But fear not, O my soul, he has redeemed you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are you here? Why do you exist? What were you created for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But now thus says the LORD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you are precious in my eyes, and honoured, and I love you, I give men in return for you, peoples in exchange for your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; bring my sons from afar and my daughters from the end of the earth, everyone who is called by my name, whom I created for my glory, whom I formed and made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://omysoul.faith/ref/isaiah&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 43:1, 4, 6-7&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You were created for the glory of God. He set his love upon you, called you by name, poured out that great love at Calvary, and redeemed you. There is no higher calling than for the glory of God. It is why I am here. It is why you are here. And as we receive that great Calvary love may all see it for what it is and give God the glory due his name. Be filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wrestling is done, O my soul. It&amp;rsquo;s time for that to end. You have been bought at a price⸺an unfathomable price. But that price has been paid, and in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now may your love abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, O my soul, to know the magnitude of the reason why you are here. It is for the glory of God! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
